{\move(10,10,190,230,100,400)\fad(0,1000)\fscx25\fscy25\t(0,6000,\fscx125\fscy125)\c&H000000&\3c&H00FFFF&}anoXmous
{\move(400,10,190,270,100,400)\fad(0,1000)\fscx25\fscy25\t(0,6000,\fscx125\fscy125)\c&H000000f&\3c&0000a6&}https://thepiratebay.se/user/anoXmous
Third refill
costs a nickel.
Tip.
Let's go! On the pass.
Gotcha. Fifteen.
Let's go. Come on!
And raise 10,000.
Twenty-five! Five! Ten!
Come on. Come on.
Fifteen.
Hey, you guys
have limits.
High five.
And raise 10,000.
Anybody up?
Twenty-five. Gotcha!
One-seven-five,
one-seven-five left.
Nobody wants to bet
against my hitter here, huh?
Nobody wants to bet?
Might as well sell tickets
to the place here.
Three on my side!
I got three. Right.
Ten. I got ten.
Oh, biggies.
- Anybody?
- Fifteen!
I got 30.
Oh, ho.
Real spenders we got here.
Real high rollers.
Ah, you had
your chance.
Come on. Let's go.
We're ready over here.
Just remember, anything goes but
no hittin' when somebody's down.
- Yeah.
- Okay. Let 'em go.
You want it? You want it?
Yeah? Go get it.
I want it.
Get in there!
Hey! Okay, Chuck!
Son of a bitch.
All right.
Come on, Chuck boy. Get him.
Get in there!
Get in there. Get him.
Ohhh!
Go get him!
Come on! Go get him!
You can get him, Chuck!
Come on! Take him now!
Move in on him.
Move in!
Yes! Yes!
Come on. Get up.
Come on. Come on. Get up.
Come on. Come on
Get up!
Come on. Get up!
Get up, you chump!
Hey, listen.
I think I can do
about six more of those.
Yeah. And a couple
of lemons there.
You can start
anytime, pal.
Chaney.
So what?
We could
make some money.
Right. Well,
I'm all ears, friend.
That piece of business
tonight. You set it up?
Happens all the time.
Help yourself.
Thanks.
- Suppose you been down
the long, hard road.
- Who hasn't?
Jail?
You a policeman?
Just like to know
where men come from,
that's all.
You look a little past it.
Besides, I already got a hitter.
Yeah. Yeah. I saw him.
Aw, son of a bitch
laid down on me tonight.
Look, friend.
Every town's got a bar,
and the bar's got
somebody who thinks
he's tough as a nickel steak.
But they all come
to Speed for the do-re-mi.
He's a bum,
I'm the one that loses.
I don't want your dough.
I got six bucks...
and nothin' else.
You bet it.
Well, well, well,
my old friend Speed's back...
with another
potential winner.
Anybody want
to bet this man?
Not after last night.
Anybody?
I'll give two to one.
Three to one!
Come on! Odds like that
do not come around every day.
Guess you boys aren't
as slow as he is.
Gives us 150 in the pot.
Gonna hold it?
And I got another 1-5-0
for anybody expects a repeat.
What do I hear?
Fifty.
Twenty.
Forty.
Got it.
I'll take it all.
Anybody else?
You're crazy!
You got 15 more.
You a bettin' man?
Oh, wait a minute.
We got another six.
That's all we got.
I'll take all of it.
I did my part, pal.
He's all yours.
Hey, Pops, you're a little old
for this, ain't ya?
Let's go. Let's go.
Get the fight going. Come on.
Like everything else
in this world, it takes
money to make money.
Here's your 12.
Another ten just
to have some fun on.
Work out our official
deal later, huh?
Plenty more
where that came from.
You don't have
to worry about that.
Now. New Orleans...
Speed's comin' home.
A little taste?
No?
Hello, sugarplum.
How'd it go, Speedy?
Well, a rough start
but a fast finish.
Uh-huh. How much?
Even.
Oh, wonderful.
Always be pleasant
around strangers, honey.
This is Chaney.
Gayleen Schoonover,
my permanent fiancée.
I'm pleased to meet you,
Mr. Chaney.
There she is. Let's go.
I'll just say
good-bye right here.
Wait a minute, pal.
We got some plans to make.
I wanna feel my way around the city.
- What about our partnership?
- I don't like to rush things.
Jesus Christ!
What are you talking about?
Always be pleasant
around strangers, Speed.
Are we gonna see
you again, Mr. Chaney?
I might turn up.
Don't forget now.
Number 11 Dauphine Street.
Who was that guy?
I'll tell you who he was.
Money on the hoof.
It looks a little rougher
than it really is,
but you get a lot of sun
through that window.
Fix the place up,
could be real nice.
Got some furniture
down in the storage room
you could use.
- Nah, I like it the way it is.
- Buck and a half a week.
In advance.
Mind if I sit down?
Would you like to talk or just sit?
What's your name?
Who you waitin' for?
I'm waitin' for
somebody to buy me
another cup of coffee.
Have mine.
You live around here?
Didn't take ya long
to get around to that one.
Thought maybe
I could walk you home.
Not likely.
Girl had two choices
in my hometown.
Stay and be bored
or move out
and take chances.
How's your luck
been runnin'?
How can you ask that?
Look how good I'm livin'.
Well, I've seen worse.
That depends on what
you're looking for.
How 'bout you?
I don't look past
the next bend in the road.
Want me
to come in?
No.
- You sure?
- It's not that easy.
I got a husband in jail.
No job and no prospects.
- I wasn't plannin' on botherin' ya.
- Oh? What was your plan?
Maybe I'll see ya around.
Jesus Christ!
Come on. Get up.
Babe!
H-Hey, good to see you, pal.
I'm mighty glad
you found time to stop by.
Come on!
Get things started right.
Don't mind Sleepin' Beauty here.
She's not one to rush
into the day's work,
are ya? Goddamn it.
We got an important guest here.
How 'bout gettin' up and
fixin' breakfast for us?
- Mornin'.
- Christ on a crutch.
Hey, so I suppose you want
to talk deal, huh?
Well, we go 50-50 on all
scratch bets and expenses.
All side bets,
I keep 75 percent.
That's how it works.
Sixty-forty in my favor
on scratch, side bets
down the middle.
I'm tellin' ya the goin' rate.
What's normal. Ask anybody.
- We'll do things different.
- Why should we?
Because right now, my friend,
you got a percentage of nothin'.
That makes me even with you.
I'm puttin' up all the money.
I take all the risks.
All right. All right. All right.
We'll do it your way.
Gayleen! What's a man have to do
to get some breakfast around here?
I got a good feelin' 'bout this.
I think we'll make some real money.
I've got a couple things in mind.
Set something up for you next week.
Go in slow, quiet. Four
or five hundred dollars.
Something like that.
There's something I want you
to know. I only come down here
to make some money.
Well?
And to fill in
some in-betweens.
In-betweens? Hell,
that's no kind of livin'.
Well, it suits me.
When I get enough change
in my pocket, I'm gone.
We just mark
this one down to research.
Part of your education.
I wanna have a long
talk with anybody
bettin' against me.
Listen. A hundred dollars
against Curly.
- On a marker.
- Uh-uh. No markers.
- Chick, boy, wha...
- Take it.
Who else?
Who's the smoothy
over there?
That's Chick Gandil.
One of the big money belts in town.
Son of a bitch has
broken me out three times.
He's the one we're gonna shake.
Anybody?
Last call!
Stay away from him.
Move fast. Jab him.
Ohhh!
Somebody help
this kid up.
That's why
he's the best.
Nobody ever beats him.
Not many want to try.
What the hell
you doin' back there?
I've always been a student
of comparative religion.
The Pentecostals present
a number of points of interest.
How much dopin'
are you doin'?
This month my financial
condition has prevented...
certain journeys
of the imagination.
Good. We're back
in business.
I really got somebody
for us this time.
Chaney, I want you
to meet my old friend, Poe.
Fix up your cuts,
bruises... all sorts
of good things.
I have two years
of medical school
to recommend me.
Two years doesn't
make a doctor.
Well, in my third year of studies,
a small, black cloud
appeared on campus.
I left under it.
What he's tryin'
to say is that...
he's a dyed-in-the-wool
hophead.
I have a weakness
for opium.
That's a habit
that's hard to quit.
Some are born to fail.
Others have it thrust upon them.
Could I see your hands?
Oh. No protruding
knuckles.
No calcium deposits.
Mm-hmm.
Make a fist. Ooh.
More area to absorb
the concussion of a blow
without breaking.
Simple matter
of engineering stress.
Reasonably thick skin.
Oh, he's got good skin.
I'd say there's
a good chance you're not...
what Speed, with an
unfortunate turn of phrase,
refers to as "a bleeder."
Like I told you, he's good.
How much?
Ten percent of what we
win, expenses. Standard.
Uh, hi.
Mr. Le Beau here?
I need a, uh, short-termer
for a thousand.
Huh. That's
a heavy taste.
How short?
Oh, a day, maybe two.
I've done business
with you before.
Yeah.
'Bout a year ago.
Mm-hmm.
- Got your money back.
- Yeah. You paid back
my $300 all right.
But you had to borrow it
from Abboar to do it.
That one you didn't
cover so well.
- Three weeks over. Big deal.
- It was closer to three months.
Well, he got paid.
What's the difference?
Well, there's a big difference
between me and Abboar.
Well, I'll, uh,
take your word for that.
Okay, Speed.
- That's 950.
- I said a thousand.
That's 50 for the loan.
And 50 for every day
until it comes back.
Whew. Boy, you really
puttin' the Jesse James to me.
Now, you wait
here, huh?
Well, how long
you gonna be?
'Cause I don't feel like
sittin' out here all day.
Listen. Don't start
complaining now.
Don't you get caught up
in any kind of game
in there, Speed.
Business.
It's business.
Give me one.
Well, hello, Speed.
Good seein' you, Chick.
How's my personal pigeon?
Just stopped by
to pay off my marker.
Well, that's all right now.
We all make mistakes.
- Guess you heard about my new hitter?
-  I'll see that.
Uh, yeah.
Word gets around.
Oh, he's good.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. Might even work him up
to ape man over there.
Well, now, there's...
there's no mystery about it.
It's my standard deal.
But, uh, you see,
you do have to have
a thousand dollars up front.
You makin' an offer?
Well, my man's just startin' out.
He's good,
but I have to get long odds
if I'm gonna face skinhead.
Assuming that you did have
the money, what kind of odds
you talkin' about?
- Five to one.
- Three to one.
Deal!
Somebody die
and leave it to ya?
Three to one, Chickie.
Money's on the table.
What do ya say?
You know,
I don't like being hustled
by a hope-and-a-prayer artist.
You're not gettin'
in that cheap.
The pot bet just now
went up to three thousand.
Now, you come on back,
when you get that rich.
- You mean to tell me
we don't have a deal?
- Not for a thousand.
I'll see you soon, Dempsey.
I'm feelin' quite fine,
Mr. Pettibon. Quite fine.
Well, listen, we got a boy
down here I think could make
an interesting contest for you.
Well, now, that's, uh,
quite a bit of money.
I don't know whether
our boy's up to it or not.
He's just startin' out.
He's, uh, real game.
He's awful green though.
Nobody takes advantage
of you bayou people.
We'll be there, Mr. Pettibon.
Good talkin' with ya.
Told you it'd be a fat one.
Barber...
How high?
Two thousand George Washingtons.
Is that "high" enough for ya?
Gonna pay some bills.
The dun at the door,
the wolf at the gate
shall be held in abeyance.
Mm-hmm.
You're that sure
of Mr. Chaney.
Su...
Does a goose
go barefoot?
I'm goin' to get
some cigars.
Oh, Mr. Pettibon.
Good to see you
again, Mr. Weed.
Ah, look what we did
for your little visit.
Well, this is mighty fine,
mighty fine.
I knew you'd like it.
Ah, this is my fiancée,
Miss Gayleen Schoonover.
Well, how do, ma'am?
Pleasure, Mr. Pettibon.
And, you remember
Mr. Poe here.
O-Oh, sure, Mr. Poe.
Nice to see you again, sir.
And that's Chaney.
- He don't say much.
- They's got a plan.
He ain't gonna say
much at all later.
That's your plan,
Mr. Pettibon, not ours.
Oh, now, now,
you said he was green.
What?
Third time out.
Well, he don't
look unpicked to me.
I guess I'll let my man
be the judge of that.
That's him right over there.
He looks like he's
up to the mark.
He'd better be.
Goddamn!
Aw, hell!
Very pretty. Very nice.
You better get
the money.
Oh, listen.
Nobody ever has
to tell me to do that.
Well, that's how
it's done, Mr. Pettibon.
I guess it just wasn't
your day, was it?
Damn small question
about that.
What the hell you doin'?
Well, now, this has been
a big setback for us.
I didn't think anybody could
go through my man that way.
It's obviously
an error in judgment on
your part then, wasn't it?
It was too damned easy.
There ain't no rules
about that, except who wins.
Now, that money's ours.
Somethin' wrong,
Speed?
Yeah. We got us a problem.
You're a ringer, Mr. Chaney.
You give us our goddamn money!
You want that money?
Take it.
Somebody always
shows up with a gun.
Goddamn sack
of country shit.
Steady on, Speed.
These boys are not refined.
I think you folks
better get in your car
and just drive right on home.
I think that's
pretty good advice.
There's a man makes some sense.
- He ain't gonna pay.
- Just okay?
Listen, goddamn it!
Next time I come back
to this coon-ass place,
I'm gonna bring a gun.
Well, you do that.
Make sure it's
a great big one.
Now, get on out!
That's how it's done.
Sorry spectacle.
Very poor example
of Southern sportsmanship.
All this drivin' for nothin'.
My God, it breaks your heart.
Breaks my butt,
that's what it breaks.
Why don't we take it
easy and drive around
the backcountry roads...
and see the sights
for a while?
What the hell
are you talkin' about?
Business.
Well, anyway, he went
through L.J. Just like that.
Nothin' to it.
Anybody see that?
- My goodness!
- Jesus Christ.
- Now I got the gun.
- I guess you do.
Anybody else?
What about you?
I don't think
you want to use it.
That's one way.
You want to see another?
Gayleen!
This your place,
Pettibon?
He's tearing the place up.
Whee.
Ooh.
Come on back here!
Where y'all goin'?
Come here! Come here!
Is this
where you live?
I'll see ya
in a couple of days.
- You know who we're
goin' after next?
- Yeah.
If this isn't your place,
who's the lucky lady?
Hey.
Y'all have a real
big time now, you hear?
Who is it?
Chaney.
What do you want?
Thought maybe you'd
like to come out.
You'd treat me
to a champagne
breakfast or somethin'?
Whatever you feel like.
You know, it's 5:00 a.m.
Christ, I barely know you.
Yeah, but would you like to?
I guess I can make
you some coffee.
You haven't gotten around
to tellin' me what you do.
Well, it's somethin'
people generally ask.
You worried I can't
pay the check?
No.
I'm worried because you never
answer any questions.
Now, tell me.
How do you make money?
I knock people down.
You mean
like a prizefighter?
No. They're pickup fights.
The money's made on bets.
And it's something
I'm doin' just for a while.
Funny way to make a livin'.
It's better than workin'
at the bus station changin' tires
for two bucks a day.
What does it feel like
to knock somebody down?
It makes me feel
a hell of a lot better
than it does him.
That's a reason?
Hey, there's no reasons
about it. Just money.
Hello, Chick!
Good to see you.
How's tricks?
This is a private gatherin'.
I don't believe
you gentlemen were invited.
No. You remember Mr. Poe here.
Mr. Poe.
Mr. Gandil.
This is gonna take one minute.
Now, you remember those
special numbers you quoted
me on, that three to one?
I'm gonna take you up
on that bet.
First you got to have
3,000 real whole dollars.
Otherwise, it's just
an academic question.
You wanna count it?
Okay. You're on.
Howdy, Doty.
Speed.
You know, we haven't been
seeing you around town.
Yeah.
Well, I been busy.
You don't have
anything in the eighth.
Man who can afford
a shoeshine sure ought
to be able to pay his debts.
Well, I got to keep up
appearances, huh?
Way we figure it,
you're overdue.
Overdue for what?
You pushin' me, Doty?
You'll get your money.
Sure we will.
I got $200 I'll lay
on you right now.
How's that?
Hmm?
Steal it.
Sell your sister.
Borrow it.
But get it all.
Yeah, well...
Now!
Well, I need some time.
Couple of days.
No. Two days.
Couple of days. I got-
I got everythin' workin'.
Come on. Two days.
Better be a promise.
You can bank on that.
Has been a few unfortunate
fighters busted their knuckles
on that hard head of his.
Bets in. Time!
All bets in!
Hey, old man.
I'm gonna end it for ya.
Just keep smilin', Big Jim,
while you still got some lips.
When I get done with him,
I'm comin' after you, big shot.
The only thing you gonna
be comin' after is a doctor.
Jesus, I just saw it over there.
$9,000 in a man's hand.
Whew... Enough
to take your breath away.
Start 'em. Get 'em goin'.
You okay?
We're ready over here!
Whoo-o-o.
Come on, Chaney.
Goddamn it.
Oh.
Yeah!
Go get him!
Hey, you're pretty good.
Yeah!
That's it!
Yes!
Whoo-o-o...
Goddamn!
My, my, my, my, my!
Look at that lying there
like a dead man.
Hardly know whether to call
for an ambulance or a hearse.
On second thought, let's
get a wheelbarrow in here...
and haul Mr. Gandil's
hitter out.
You've always had an unfortunate
way of puttin' things, Speed.
Nothin' personal, Chick.
Look at that.
All right. All right.
Stand... Come on.
Let him through.
Goddamn. Come on now.
Hey, Chaney!
Hey, listen.
I got a message from our
old friend, Chick Gandil.
He wants us to come up
and have a drink with him.
You handle it.
I'm not interested.
Oh, now, he said "us."
Never hurt anybody
to be polite.
Yeah!
Oh, I saw you out there.
Smooth, real smooth.
Thank you. Thank you.
It's all in the partner
that you have.
A-Ah, yes.
Thank you.
I would like
to propose a toast.
I propose a toast
to the... best man I know.
To the Napoleon
of Southern sports.
Me.
Speed.
Come on, Gayleen. Let's get
with those galloping dominoes.
We'll see you all later. Have
a good time now. Okay, Poe?
Come on, honey.
I assume you realize that the blood
of the fabled Edgar Allan
courses through my veins.
No. But it sure sounds like
I'm gonna hear about it.
Yes.
"Hear the sledges
with the bells.
"Silver bells.
"How they tinkle, tinkle, tinkle
in the icy air of night.
"While the stars,
that over-sprinkle...
"All the heavens,
seem to twinkle...
with a crystalline delight."
Hey, come on here.
All right.
Get the whole 400 for the line.
Get 'em over here.
Don't give me a short count now, okay?
- Come on, dice!
- Snake eyes!
Son of a bitch!
All right, pass the dice.
He's through.
Not yet, pal.
Shoot it all. Okay.
Bet it all.
Come on, nine!
Point six.
Everything in there? Come on!
All right!
Six is the point.
Come on. Make that six.
All right. I'm lookin'
for a big pair of threes. Come on!
Lose. Next lucky roller.
Get your goddamn
hat and coat.
You lost all of it.
Shut up.
What? Excuse me,
Mr. High Roller.
I should have known.
Sure has been a lot of fun, pal.
How long an arm has he got?
Gandil's a businessman.
Worried about his reputation.
He's not gonna try any muscle play.
There is one thing we are gonna have
to live with though.
Since you beat old Jim Henry like that,
fights are gonna be harder to find,
and we are gonna have to give odds,
which can be very expensive.
Would you tell Gandil that Mr. Chaney and
Mr. Weed are here to see him, please?
Just go right on in.
Thank you, ma'am.
How's your jaw, glass man, hmm?
Well, I'm glad you could drop by, Speed.
Always a pleasure. You
remember Mr. Chaney here.
Well, sit down.
Get comfortable.
Thank you.
You, uh, care
for a drink?
No, no, no.
Too early for me. Thank you.
All business, huh?
That's right.
Well, let's have it.
You got a direct way of speakin'.
Don't let it upset ya, Chick.
I like a man that's direct.
Makes everything easy to understand,
like the old days.
Chick, we didn't come down here
for no history lesson.
Let's get down to cases.
Maybe we should at that.
There's $5,000 in that envelope.
It's yours.
I don't believe I'm followin' the drift.
I'm buyin' half of Chaney.
You talk to me, not him.
I used to have the best street fighter
in this city. Now I don't.
I don't like that at all.
We can get along without you.
I'm sorry to hear that, Mr. Chaney.
I hope you come around to my way of thinkin'.
Well, hell! Look who's here.
Speed, you come to your Mama Lois's
to have a really good time.
Oh, I sure did, Mama.
I got myself
some lovely new girls.
Let's go have a look.
Girls, girls!
Now, Speed, each one has been especially
trained to suit your fancy.
I don't need no sales pitch.
I just come to get my hat blocked.
Well, how about
havin' a drink, mister?
Sure. Bourbon.
What'd you say
your name was?
Carol.
What'd you think about that, Carol?
Hey, it was terrific. You were really great.
You know something?
That's just exactly what I thought you'd say.
What the hell are you doin'?
Hey, Doty!
Come on! Hey! Ow!
No! Don't. Don't, please...
Is that okay, Doty?
Talk to him.
Mr. Le Beau says he's got
some business with you.
He don't want no trouble,
just you pay your debts.
Uh-huh.
Okay, mister.
Well, good seein'
you gentlemen.
Likewise, Speed.
We got a few things to talk about,
a couple of problems.
Well, I gotta get somethin'
goin' in a hurry now.
Been thinkin' about Gandil.
Maybe we should reconsider
that offer he made us.
Why the change of mind?
I'm flat-ass broke. I need some money fast.
I don't like Gandil.
That's no reason.
That's enough reason for me.
Well, that's fine for you,
but it doesn't do much for my case, does it?
I mean, if we don't go with Gandil,
it means I have to borrow.
My credit's not worth a damn all over town.
Can you loan me $2,000? That's what I need.
Speed, you made as much as me,
dollar for dollar.
Well, the way I look at it, you owe me.
We used my bankroll to begin with,
my money, my contacts!
You were a bum when I met you,
and you're nothin' without me.
Yeah, I figure you owe me.
Dumb.
You sayin' no to me?
Aw, Speed!
Chaney!
Aw, hell, Speed, now we're both finished.
Welcome to New Orleans, Street.
I don't do that.
You ever get scared when you do your work?
I don't think about it.
The only thing you care about is the money.
Isn't that right? Just so the money's good.
You got any more questions?
Try this one. Are you gonna stay the night?
Not this time.
All right. Let's get it out.
What's botherin' ya?
Hell, yes,
something's wrong, a lot of things.
The rent, price of groceries,
clothes I can't buy, a few items like that.
How much do you want?
I want my own.
I don't wanna depend on you.
You're not reliable.
You come when you want.
You go when you want.
And you never mention
what comes in the middle.
Suit yourself.
Can I buy ya one?
How you been?
You, uh... You wanna talk
about the sportin' life?
I'm out of it.
That's too bad.
I had to give up on you.
Went out and bought myself another hitter.
The best.
Must make you very happy
now that you got what you wanted.
I'll tell you what I want.
You must have quite
a stash saved away by now. How about 5,000?
Him against you.
Don't need any more money.
There's no point in avoiding
this thing, you know.
It's gonna happen.
He's right.
You want it
that much?
I'm getting paid.
I can always reach over
and start things right now.
Yeah, but you won't.
You don't think so?
You're not gonna do it for free.
Who the hell are you?
Hey! Hey!
Ouch! Son of a bitch! Help!
Hey.
This is your lucky night.
That depends on how you look at it.
Well, I'll tell you how to look at it.
Right about now, I'd be deciding
whether to bust your legs or your back.
But, um, somebody just paid
the interest on your debt.
Just for one week.
Your man fights Mr. Street here,
and I'll handle your home mortgage.
My man? He won't even speak to me, Chick.
We're gonna put you on ice for a while...
and, uh, see if maybe he'll speak to me.
I don't wanna interrupt anything.
Gandil come to see me.
We have got a problem.
You and me ain't
got no trouble, Poe.
I'm afraid we do.
It's about our old friend Speed.
He send you?
Don't even
know I'm here.
Me and Speed ain't related anymore.
Things don't work that easy.
He's in a lot of trouble.
I ain't interested.
Speed owes a ton
to one of our local riffraff.
They're puttin' the arm on him.
Gandil's gonna pay the loan off
if you take on his man.
No crowd, just business.
You want me to bet my $5,000.
That's all the money I got.
I don't owe that goddamn Speed nothin'.
That's not the point. It's real simple.
He's in the ringer.
You're the only one that can get him out.
Money's hard to come by, Poe.
Somebody got a cigarette?
I don't use any.
Of course, I'd be happy
to go down and get some.
You're not goin' anywhere.
Listen, things don't
work out tomorrow night,
which one of you gets to do the job?
We both do.
Mm-mmm, not this time. I'll take him.
That's right. You haven't won one
in a while, have you, Jim?
Three cards.
He really cleaned your plow, didn't he?
Why don't you shut up and play cards?
- Think he's gonna show up?
- Sure hope not.
I've got a visitor.
Some other time.
Uh, no, wait.
I'll walk you down.
Well, how you been?
How do I look?
I got no complaints.
There's somethin' I gotta tell you.
I don't think you should drop by anymore.
Things have changed.
I think I'm movin'.
I'm gonna get a better place.
I got a better offer.
Someone that spends the night.
He's even got a steady job.
Looks like you got things all figured out.
Is that all you've got to say?
Gentlemen.
Evenin'. Your man gonna show up?
We just have to wait and find out.
Let's get started.
Why not?
Where are they?
Upstairs.
Uh, go up and get 'em...
I'll do it!
We're not gonna wait here all night!
Thanks, pal.
Just like old times, huh?
We did add
a couple of new wrinkles.
Ever see him fight?
No, I can't say
I've had the pleasure.
But they didn't bring him
down all the way from Chicago to lose.
Let's do it.
All right, you pissant big shots,
we're ready over here.
All right, anybody else got anything to say?
Glad you could make it.
Things have a way of comin' around.
You know, Mr. Chaney, I envy you.
Must be excitin' to bet more money
than you can afford to lose.
What?
Who's gonna hold it?
He is.
It doesn't matter what you do.
You're always gonna smell like fish.
That got him.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Come on.
Use 'em.
- Foul! Get those palmers out of here.
- Use 'em!
- Goddamn it! Use 'em!
- Forfeit! Forfeit!
By God!
You owe me money.
You know, you cost me a great deal.
You'll live with it.
Mr. Chaney, it's been
a pleasure watchin' you work.
Well, you know, Chick, like old mama said,
"Next best thing to playin' and winnin'...
Is playin' and losin'."
I'll see you around.
Adios.
Sure this is far as you wanna go?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Hey, Poe.
I got a cat back at my place.
I want you to take care of it for me.
That's a lot of money.
You take care of Poe.
For a man who came to town
to make some money,
you're sure givin' a lot of it away.
You're forgetting about the in-betweens.
Yeah, I guess you filled them out all right.
Uh, well, where are you off to?
North.
Well, Chaney?
We ought to say somethin'.
Maybe we ought to head on down to Miami.
Get into some of that action down there, huh?
It's a hell of a town, you know.
Right on that warm oceanfront.
Fine salt sea air.
Be good for our health.
Uh-huh.
Oh, he sure was somethin'.
Let's go get the cat.
Yeah.