Stinks!
You reek of burnt flesh and steel.
Keep flying and one day you
won't be able to change yourself back.
Isn't it great!
Sophie did this for me.
The fighting is fierce.
The country's ablaze, from the
southern coast to the northern border.
I hate the fire in gunpowder.
They have no manners.
- My own kind attacked me.
- The Witch of the Waste?
Hack wizards masquerading
as monsters.
They'll cry plenty later on,
when they can't regain human form.
No, they'll just forget
they ever knew how to cry.
Aren't you supposed to report
to the king yourself?
Yes, well...
Hot water for my bath.
Oh, no, not again.
Is that Howl?
Yeah, wasting my hot water again.
I'm sure Howl won't eat any breakfast.
No matter.
Morning.
It's lovely shopping in the morning.
I've never seen the ocean!
Such beautiful, sparkling water!
Same as it always is.
I myself hate potatoes.
Pay up.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Fish, all fresh off the boat.
- That one's tasty.
- I myself hate fish.
The fleet's come home!
- Is that the smoke?
- There's been another battle.
Really? Sorry, lady, later.
That ship's on fire!
Sophie, let's go get a closer look.
No, I've no stomach for such things.
Let's go home.
Our most advanced battleship,
reduced to this.
Markl, there are Blob Men nearby.
Don't move.
They work for the Witch of the Waste.
They're gone.
Don't people notice
those terrible monsters?
Look! Up there!
That's what dropped those bombs!
An enemy airship, Sophie!
Sophie, flyers!
Ignore the flyers!
They're enemy propaganda!
Are you OK, Sophie?
A glass of water, please
Sure.
Sophie, what did you do
to the bathroom shelves? Look!
My hair's turned this weird color!
What... what beautiful hair.
Take a good look!
You mixed up everything on
the shelves and ruined the spells!
I didn't mix up anything,
I simply cleaned up.
Cleaning, always cleaning.
I told you not to get
too carried away!
It's hopeless!
How humiliating.
It's not so very bad.
This new shade's quite lovely
in its way.
I'm done for.
What's the point in living,
if you aren't beautiful?
Stop, Howl! Cut it out!
He's calling on
the spirits of Darkness.
He did this last time
a girl ditched him.
Please, Howl, that's enough.
You can just dye your hair again.
I've had enough of you, Howl!
I've never once been beautiful!
I've had enough of this place!
Thank you, Turnip
You're a kind scarecrow
Please come back, Sophie.
Howl's in trouble!
Cut it out, Howl!
I'm going out!
Sophie!
Get over here!
My, he's dramatic.
Is he dead?
Don't worry.
A tantrum never killed anyone.
Help me, Markl.
Get that hot water running, Markl!
C'mon, you can still walk.
You look after him now, Markl.
Sure.
I'll have to clean all over again.
I'm coming in.
Here's some hot milk.
Drink up.
I'll leave it here.
Drink it while it's hot.
Don't leave me, Sophie.
Try a little milk?
The Witch of the Waste
is searching for my house.
You're right, I saw her cronies
down at the port.
The truth is, I'm a coward.
All this junk is just sorcery
to keep her away.
I'm scared to death.
Tell me, why is
the Witch of the Waste after you?
She seemed quite interesting,
so I approached her.
But she terrified me
and I ran away.
Now the king's ordered me
to report to him.
As Jenkins and as Pendragon...
How many names do you use, Howl?
Enough to guarantee my freedom.
Can't you refuse the king?
See that...
The oath I took at
the Sorcery Academy.
Say, Howl.
Why not visit the king?
What!
Just say it to his face.
"Stop this foolish war
I refuse to help you."
Sophie, you don't know
what they're like.
But he's the king, right?
A king thinks only
of what's best for his people.
I know!
You'll go in my place, Sophie!
Pretend you're Pendragon's mother.
Just tell him your son is
an idle good-for-nothing.
Maybe Madam Suliman
will even give up on me.
Madam Suliman?
You're wearing that hat?
After all the magic I spent
making your dress pretty...
Off I go.
Sure!
See you later!
This charm
assures your safe return.
Don't worry,
I'll follow you in disguise.
There.
Off you go!
I'm sure this will never work.
I don't suppose he's following me,
disguised as a crow.
I'm sure Howl would pick
a more dramatic disguise
Not that...
The Palace is so far away.
Howl?
Don't tell me you're Howl.
Disguising yourself as an old dog,
of all things.
Do you know how exhausting
it is to be old?
How nice to see you.
The little hatter, right?
The Witch of the Waste!
Thank you so much for
delivering my note to Howl.
How's Howl doing?
Quite terrified.
Thanks to him,
I've become a cleaning lady.
My, how delightful.
By the way, what brings you
to see the king?
Job hunting.
I'm sick of working for Howl.
And yourself?
The king invited me.
It seems that idiot, Suliman,
finally needs my power.
Why don't you break the spell
you put on me?
That's impossible.
My gifts lie in casting spells,
not breaking them.
See you later, then.
Hey, wait a minute!
Just wait!
If you weren't here,
I'd have hit her with my cane.
What's wrong with you?
Madam, vehicles are prohibited
beyond this point.
Please continue on foot.
That Suliman!
Using magic to force me
to climb these stairs.
We'll catch up.
Pay her no mind.
Heavy, why are you so heavy?
You... Hey... Wait.
What is it?
Suddenly remembered...
how to break my spell?
I told you...
I don't know how.
Then, start studying up.
I don't get it.
Where does she get all that energy?
I have to put you down.
Why don't you call it a day?
You can't make it.
It's been 50 years now,
since they drove me out of here...
I've been longing
for this day, ever since...
Good luck to you, then.
Still, I'm not nice enough
to help you out.
Come, Howl.
You heartless wench!
Next time I'll turn you feeble, too!
Hurry up!
Madam, follow me.
First, you should help her.
We are forbidden to assist anyone.
But the king himself invited her.
Hang in there!
Just a little farther!
And you call yourself a witch?
Who asked you?
You suddenly look older.
Madam Pendragon and
the Witch of the Waste!
Pull yourself together.
Isn't this
what you've been waiting for?
Madam Pendragon and
the Witch of the Waste!
Pendragon...
That name sounds familiar.
Of course it does.
That was the name of my hat shop.
It was?
Please wait here.
A chair!
It's mine!
Howl, get back here!
Madam, this way please.
I understand you're Howl's mother.
Yes.
My name is Pendragon.
I'm sure you're weary.
Please have a seat.
Yes.
I am Madam Suliman,
His Majesty's witch.
Um, that dog is...
Ah, you mean Heen?
He does my errands.
I asked him to escort you.
Howl won't join us, then?
You see, he sends his mother
to make excuses.
I'm sure he'd be utterly useless
to His Majesty.
What a shame.
He was my last apprentice...
A student of such marvelous gifts.
I rejoiced in finally finding
a worthy heir.
But then, a demon stole his heart,
and he abandoned me.
He turned his magic
to purely selfish uses.
Mrs. Pendragon.
That boy is dangerous.
His power is too great
for one with no heart.
If he follows that path he'll wind up
like the Witch of the Waste.
Bring her!
What happened?
I just restored her to her real age.
All her powers are gone.
Once upon a time,
she was a magnificent witch.
She made a bargain with a demon.
Who consumed her, body and soul,
long, long ago.
Our kingdom can no longer afford
to turn a blind eye
to disreputable wizards and witches.
If Howl comes here
to serve the kingdom,
I will teach him how to break
with the demon.
If not, I'll strip him of his powers
as I have taken hers.
Now just a minute.
Now I understand why Howl
refused to come here.
Something's not right.
Forcing your aged guests
to climb stairs, dragging them
into strange rooms...
It's like a trap.
You call Howl heartless!
Yes, he's selfish and cowardly
and unpredictable.
But he's straight as an arrow.
He only wants to be free.
Howl won't turn into an evil monster.
He'll battle the demon on his own.
I believe in him.
Mrs. Pendragon...
You're in love with Howl.
Howl...
Howl's coming?
I want Howl's heart, I want it!
That's enough from you.
Howl's not coming.
Howl will most certainly come.
Now, I've found his weakness.
Your Majesty.
As you are.
How are you feeling?
Thank you for asking.
Meetings bore me.
I flew out for a breather.
How lovely.
These are...?
This is Wizard Howl's mother.
I see.
I appreciate it, but I don't intend
to win any war with magic.
It's true that Suliman's powers
shield our palace from bombs.
But they just fall on
neighboring towns.
That's how magic works.
Right, Suliman?
Such eloquence today, Your Majesty.
Suliman!
This is the final battle.
This time, we'll beat them to a pulp.
Suliman, you've outdone yourself
with that double. Await good news.
Thank you kindly.
Have my generals assembled?
It's been awhile, Howl.
Delighted to see you doing so well.
I saw right through you.
Not a very clever disguise.
I've kept my oath.
I've no wish to fight you.
I'll take my mother.
I won't let you go.
Don't look down,
you'll be dragged down.
It's time I showed your mother
what you really are.
Howl, don't! It's a trap!
Hold tight!
Sophie, sit up front.
Oh, no, Sophie,
you brought the whole gang along.
Nice doggie.
You're just Suliman's spy.
Oh, well, too late to toss you now.
Sophie, you steer.
What! I can't possibly!
They're after us.
I'll tackle them. Fly straight
to the castle in the Wastes.
What! That's impossible!
Don't worry,
the ring will guide you.
Summon Calcifer with your heart.
Summon Calcifer?
It's glowing!
Follow the light.
You'll be there by nightfall.
Why send me to Suliman
if you were coming yourself?
Your presence gave me
the courage for it.
She's too terrible to
face on my own.
You've saved me.
I was in grave danger back there.
Don't let go!
- You're good
- Stop joking!
We've got a lead now.
I can give you 5 minutes of
invisibility, now's your chance.
Howl!
No, thank you.
Thank you. That's the most fun
I've had in ages.
I supposed Howl thinks
he's escaped...
His mother's awfully young.
We're not far.
That's my hometown.
Don't look so friendly.
I don't trust you.
The castle.
They've come to meet us!
Sophie!
Markl, help!
I don't know how to stop this thing!
Sophie!
Doggie.
Markl!
I'm home.
Sophie, are you hurt?
You're home!
Thank you for coming to meet us.
Oh, no, you've gone too far.
I wonder if Howl's back.
Howl?
Howl? Is it you?
Are you hurt? In pain?
Stay away.
I want to help you.
I want to break
the spell you're under.
You can't even break
your own spell!
But I love you!
Too late.
Howl!
Howl must be back.
Sophie, you'd better figure out
how to break my spell quick.
We're both running out of time.
Meaning Howl will turn into
a monster? Is it true?
I can't tell you that.
I'm a demon.
Calcifer, Suliman told me,
Howl has given you
something very precious.
What is it?
Where is it?
That's confidential information.
And if I threaten
to dump water over you?
How dare you!
Howl will die with me!
Good morning, Turnip.
We've got to be brave.
Ready, Sophie!
OK! Open wider, Calcifer!
Here goes! Push!
Heave!
I... said... move!
Come on!
They call it a castle, but once
you get inside, it's a junk heap.
It's time to eat!
Here, old girl.
But, Sophie
she's the Witch of the Waste.
No need to worry.
Why's she staring at me?
Such a pretty fire.
Howl!
Hello, everyone.
- Welcome home.
- Master Howl, can we keep this puppy?
An old Witch and
Madam Suliman's dog.
Why'd you let them in, Calcifer?
Don't look at me!
They blew in with Sophie.
Sophie, always dramatic...
So you're Turnip.
You're under quite a spell, too.
Seems everyone in our little family
is complicated...
He's so handsome.
This is a busy day.
We're moving.
Moving?
Oh, good. There aren't any shops,
here in the middle of nowhere.
Madam Suliman can track us down
in no time, here.
But you'll have to stay behind.
The magic in your spell's too risky.
All right, that's done.
Take it away, Calcifer.
Excellent.
Stay right where you are.
Be gentle...
Here goes.
We've moved.
You can get up now.
Amazing, Master!
It's so grand!
What a pretty fire.
This is...
I added a bathroom.
For our growing family.
Sophie, come here!
Sophie!
I added a bedroom, too.
Go in.
This is... why?
I thought it would suit you.
Do you like it?
Yes, it's perfect
for a housekeeper.
I got you new clothes, too.
Open them later. Next.
Sophie! Come here!
Quick!
A courtyard!
There's a shop, too.
Let's go, Heen!
See that new color on the dial?
There's a new exit.