Tokuma Shoten - Nippon Television Network
Dentsu - Studio Ghibli
In ancient times, Japan was
covered in deep forests, within
which lived the gods of old.
PRINCESS MONONOKE
Yakkuru!
Ashitaka!
Good Timing. Hii-sama says
we should get back to the village.
Jii-ji said the same thing.
Jii-ji?
He says the moutain isn't right!
- And the birds have gone!
- And the animals, too!
I see.  I'll go see Jii-ji myself.
You three hurry back to the village.
Something's coming...
Jii-ji, what's up?
I don't know. But it's not human.
Hii-sama's called everyone in.
Here it comes...
It's a tatari-gami!
Tatari-gami?
Yakkuru, run!
It's headed to the village!
Ashitaka!
A tatari-gami is a cursed spirit!
Don't let it touch you!
Yakkuru!
Calm! You must calm yourself!
O noble god of the forest!
What spurned this rampage?
- A demon!
- Run!
Stop!
Why do you attack our village!
Stop! Calm yourself!
- It's down!
- Ashitaka!
- Bring Hii-sama!
- Keep the fires going!
Ashitaka!
Kaya, don't touch it!
It's no ordinary wound!
Ashitaka is hurt! Where's Hii-sama?!
Everybody, don't get any closer!
Hii-sama!
Pour this water, slowly,
over the wound.
Right.
O raging god from parts unknown...
...l must respectfully speak to you now.
Where you have fallen we will
raise a mound and perform rites.
Bear us no hate, and be at peace.
Foul humans...
...you shall feel my suffering,
and my hatred.
The situation is grim.
The boar came from a land
far to the west.
He was wounded by something
that ate away at his flesh.
He ran, growing with pain and hatred,
until he became a tatari-gami.
My dear Ashitaka...
Yes?
Show everyone your right arm.
Hii-sama!
My dear Ashitaka, are you prepared
to accept your fate?
Yes.
I accepted it the moment
I let loose my arrow.
...that mark is a curse that
will seep into your bones and kill you.
Hii-sama, what can we do?
Ashitaka protected the girls
and saved the village!
To sit and wait for death...
You cannot change your fate.
You can, though, rise to meet it.
Look...
This was inside the boar's body.
He was in agony. It shattered
his bones, tore at his entrails...
...without it, he would not
have become a tatari-gami.
So what is happening in the weastern lands,
that a boar-god could be so injured?
Perhaps by going west,
to see with eyes unclouded...
...you may at least find answers.
For more than 500 years now,
our tribe has hidden in this place...
...after our defeat in the war
against the Yamato regime.
These days, we hear the influence
of the Yamato has withered...
...and even the Shogun's
samurai are losing control.
...and yet with each generation,
our tribe also grows weaker.
And now, bitter fate, the young man who
should have grown to be our chieftain...
...must journey far to the west.
The law forbids that we watch
as you go. Farewell.
Ashitaka!
Kaya, you should not be here.
I will accept punishment.
Please, take this to remember me by.
But isn't this your beloved crystal dagger?
I breathed a charm on it
to protect you.
I will never forget you.
And maybe, some day...some day...
I'll always remember you, Kaya.
Fighting?
Move up!
Here's another one!
His head is mine!
Stop!
What is going on with my arm?
Don't let him get away!
I'm coming through! Let me pass!
Demon!
The mark is spreading...
This soup is really terrible...
There he is!
Will this do?
What the hell?
This isn't money!
Give me back my rice!
Just a moment, may I see that?
Hm?!
Woman, this is pure gold!
Is it coins you want? I can pay you!
Hey everyone, is there
a money house nearby?
No?
I'm just a simple monk, but I'd say
this is worth a whole bag of rice!
...no, three whole bags of rice!
Wait, young sir!
Hey, that's mine! Give it back!
Hey! Don't be in such a rush!
Now, now...there's no
need to thank me.
It is I who should
be thanking you!
You saved me back there
when those samurai attacked.
You fight like one possessed!
So you've spotted them... That's what
you get for flashing gold around.
Indeed, people's hearts harden
and become rough like hemp.
It would be rather annoying to
be robbed in our sleep.  Shall we run?
Oh...so the boar became a tatari-gami.
I followed the boar's trail back here,
but I lost it just outside the village.
That's to be expected.
Look over there.
The last time I was here,
that was a village.
There was a flood, maybe,
or a landslide. I'm sure many died.
War, poverty, sickness, starvation...
The land teems with those who
died swallowing their resentment.
You want to speak of curses?
This whole world is, in itself, a curse.
Ah, this is good!
I shouldn't have gotten involved
in the fighting. I killed two men.
But you saved me.
Give me your bowl.
You shall eat first.
Everyone dies.
Some now, some later.
Hmm, what an elegant bowl...
You remind me of legends
of an acient people...
...people who used stone arrowheads
and rode strange red elk.
They were the brave Emishi tribe,
said to live far off to the East.
First, though,
avoid the jaws of death.
Or so my old teacher used to say.
Eat up, it's your rice!
Would you know what this is?
This?
It was in the body of the boar.
It's what gave him his wounds.
As you travel west from here,
farther into the mountains...
...there is a deep forest that
is not safe for humans to enter.
This is the Shishi-Gami's forest.
The Shishi-Gami's forest?
They say the creatures there are giants,
just as they were in ancient times.
I knew it, he's going west.
It's not far now!
Stay on your guard!
Here they come!
It's the wolves!
Calm the oxen! Don't rush!
Form your ranks!
Keep your powder dry!
Let them come in range!
Number 1...Fire!
Number 2...Fire!
They weren't much, as demons go.
Those were just the pups.
Where's the mother?
It's Moro!
Moro! Over here!
Got her!
She's a god.
She won't die from that.
We took quite the beating.
We leave immediately.
What about the ones who fell?
Form up and move out!
He's breathing!
Hang on!
I am Ashitaka! I have come
from far to the east!
Are you the ancient gods said
to live in the Shishi-Gami's forest?
Leave!
A kodama...?  So kodama
live in these forests as well.
Keep still, or you'll make
your wounds worse.
If you leave them be, the are harmless.
They're a sign of a healthy forest.
But they might call the Shishi-Gami.
Shishi-Gami?  You mean like a large wolf?
No, something much worse!
A demon lord!
It's gone!
Yakkuru's not afraid.
There's no danger here.
We beg passage
through your woods.
Let's go back! Please!
There's a trail across the river.
We'll never get through these woods!
The current's too strong.
And this man's wounds are serious.
We have to move quickly.
So are you guiding us?
Or leading us astray?
Sir! These things
are not helping us get home...
...and more and more
of them keep appearing!
This is your mother? A fine tree!
The tracks of that girl and those wolves...
Is this their domain?
Sir, this really is dangerous.
This is the gate to another world!
I think you're right.
I'll only be a moment.
Tracks...
Three toes...and still fresh.
S-sir! What's wrong?
Are you all right, sir?
Your face has gone white...
...do you feel it, too?
Did you see that just now?
- What?
- No, never mind...
We're almost there.  Just hold on.
Thank you.
It's gone...
Strange...this man
feels less heavy now...
Hey! It doesn't hurt!
It's healed! ...ow!
No, no, it's still broken.
Sir! You were right!
We've arrived at Tatara Ba!
It's a fort!
That's Lady Eboshi's ironworks.
We melt iron and make steel!
Hey!
- Something's coming from the woods!
- Is it the Mononoke?
It's me! Koroku the ox-driver!
- Kouroku? Is it a ghost?
- Someone find his wife!
It's true! He's crossing
the lake right now!
You're sure it's him?
What's all this noise?!
Be quiet when I'm writing!
Koruku's come back from the dead!
What?!
You're not a ghost.
- Where are the others?
- Four of you fell...
Only the two of us were saved.
The ones that die
are always the ox-drivers...
Move!
Who's the man in the hood, sir?
I've no idea...
Gunner troops, listen to me...this man
carried your comrade on his back!
Thank him.
Ow! Don't grab me there!
Hey, you! Wait!
First, my thanks
for bringing back our men.
But the situation is suspicious...
You show up less than an hour
after our own party.
And you emerged from the
Shishi-Gami's forest, carrying...huh?
Koroku! You're alive!
Toki!
What is this!?
Good for nothing!
An ox-driver with a broken leg?
How are we supposed to eat?
But...but...
You're always making me worry.
Maybe the wolves should've eaten you!
Then I could find a better husband!
Toki! Please forgive me!
Toki, save your domestic squabbling
for some other time.
And you! Leaving them there to die!
Some escort you are!
You don't do any real work here.
Put yourself in harm's way
once in a while!
It couldn't be helped...
Thank you. My husband's an idiot,
but I'm glad he's safe.
Oh, good. I was afraid maybe
I shouldn't have brought him back.
Hey, I bet you are handsome.
Let's see your face!
Gonza...
He may stay and rest.  Later on,
I'd like to thank him personally.
Koroku...
It's good you're back. I'm so sorry.
Don't say that, Lady Eboshi!
He's already so spoiled.
Forgive me, Toki. I was there,
and I failed to save him.
Oh no, without you
watching over all our men...
...they'd all be resting comfortably
in the pit of the wolves' stomachs!
-So true!
-No mistake!
Go and rest, traveler.
Hey! I was right!
We had to fight off Moro herself
to bring back this rice!
Hurry up!
Where is he?
Is that Him?
Toki was right!
- He is handsome!
- He's a bit young...
Oh, that never stopped you before!
Quiet out there!
We lost two men today!
But if you want good looking men,
look no further!
You kidding? You lot?
Hey Traveler, come over to our place!
Forget this pig sty!
Hey! We risk our lives for the rice
you eat.  Show some respect!
And who made the steel
that bought that rice?
We work those bellows
all night long!
I would like to see where you work,
if you don't mind...
Really?
We'll have to dress up!
And wear makeup!
Don't forget! We'll be waiting!
Don't mind them, sir.
Lady Eboshi spoils them.
I've heard healthy women
make a healthy village.
But...women of that sort,
living in Tatara Ba?
We shouldn't have them around.
Their presence defiles the steel.
Lady Eboshi brings back all
the working girls she can find.
She's kind, that's all.
Keep your rice in your mouth, old man.
But she's also hard as nails! She's
picked more than one fight with demons!
That's right, the wolves are nothing.
You should've seen her bring down Nago!
Nago?
A massive boar!
He was a terrifying presence!
...and he wouldn't let us near the mountains.
Moutains full of trees and ore!
Just sitting there!
Yeah, we'd used up the ironsand
from the lower reaches...
We all wanted at those mountains!
But there was no way!
Even so, we needed trees, so
we kept pushing further out...
...and then Nago struck.
Oh, there he goes again!
That's when Lady Eboshi
and the gun troops stepped in!
Sir? What's wrong?
Does your arm hurt?
No, I was just thinking about Nago...
He must have died full of hate.
Ashitaka, or whoever you are,
I'm sorry for keeping you waiting.
...this is fine.
There is so much to do before
the morning shipment goes out.
Let's take a break.
Please let everyone know.
Sure.
Some suspect you are a spy.
Perhaps for the samurai, or Mononoke.
Tatara Ba's success
brings a lot of attention.
May I ask why you're here?
I believe this iron is yours.
It shattered the bones and tore
the flesh of a giant boar.
...turning him into a tatari-gami.
And when I finally killed him,
he gave me this mark.
It will slowly kill me.
Where are you from?
You ride a strange beast...
Between north and east.
Beyond that I cannot say.
You will answer her question,
or I'll cut you down!
And if I tell you about that ball of iron,
what would you do?
I will see with eyes unclouded.
And decide.
'Eyes unclouded'?
I see.
I will show you my secret.
Follow me.
Lady Eboshi...?
Gonza, please continue without me.
My garden, where none dare come.
My secret is just ahead,
if you still want to know it.
Good evening.
Here's one we just finished!
It's still heavy.
And yet you hold it so lightly...
Too light, and it will fall apart!
It's not just for me... I intend for
the other women to carry them as well.
Won't that be a sight!
These people here designed
and built this new gun for me.
The Chinese ones are heavy
and hard to use.
With these, we can take on anyone,
be they demons or samurai.
Scary, scary!  Our Lady Eboshi
is ready to conquer the world!
I'm sorry to rush you.
I'll have some sake sent up.
That'll be splendid!
So ravaging the forests and turning
boar-gods into tatari-gami isn't enough?
You would birth a whole new
era of hatred and suffering?
I regret that you suffer.
I fired that shot.
That foolish boar... if someone was
to be cursed, it should have been me.
Your right arm seems
to be trying to kill me...
If I thought it would lift my curse,
I would let it.
But I don't believe it would
stop with just you.
Must it kill us all to be at peace?
Lady Eboshi, our elder wishes to speak.
Lady Eboshi, do not scorn
the young man's strength.
Young man, I also carry a curse.
So I can sympathize
with your grief and your rage.
...yet I beg you
not to kill this woman.
She is the only one
who looked upon us as human.
Without fear of our disease...
...she washed our rotting flesh,
tended to our bandages...
Elder?
Life is suffering. Life is hard.
Curse this world, curse humanity,
and yet we all still wish to live...
Please consider my
humble words...
They're back.
At night they come to plant trees
and take back the mountain.
Ashitaka, would you consider
staying here to help us?
Do you intend to invade
the Shishi-Gami's forest?
Without ancient gods, even
the Mononoke will become simple beasts.
If we cut light into the forest, and tame
the wolves, this shall be a bountiful land.
Princess Mononoke may even
become human again.
Who?
A lost girl whose heart
was stolen by the wolves.
She lives to kill me.
I have heard that the blood of
the Shishi-Gami can cure any illness.
It could cure these lepers...
and perhaps your curse as well...
Lady Eboshi, what do you think?
Well done. Just right
to conquer the world!
...but it is still too heavy.
Ha, ha! Scary, scary!
You made it!
Toki, may I give it a try?
Huh? Hey, wait!
May I try?
He's come all this way...let him try!
What strength!
Hey, he's here!
See? Handsome, right?
Quick, fix your robe before it falls off!
You'll never keep that pace.
It's hard work.
Yep. And shifts run
for five days and nights.
Is life hard here?
Yeah, but it's better than
the lives we used to have!
We get to eat our fill,
and the men know their place!
I see...
You're leaving tomorrow?
You should stay longer!
You could work here!
Thank you, but there is someone
I must meet.
She's coming!
It's Princess Mononoke!
It's her!
Stop!
I don't want to fight you!
She's heading to the Hall!
None of the wolves got in!
Build up the fires! Gunners to
the stockade! Keep her inside!
Stay at your posts!
Stay Alert!
She's up on the roof!.
Don't get excited! Keep working!
The fire mustn't go out!
- Is she alone?
- Yes. We have her cornered.
I assume she's come
for you, Lady Eboshi.
It can't be helped...follow me!
Princess Mononoke.
Can you hear me?  I'm right here.
If you would take revenge upon us...
...here are some who seek
vengeance for husbands...
...killed by wolves.
Come on out!
We have a score to settle!
There she is!
Out of the way!
You're in the line of fire!
It's a trap! Stop!
Princess of the Wolves!
Return to the woods!
Don't die for nothing!
To survive is also courage!
Go home to your forest!
I knew it!
Let him do as he likes.
Got her! She's falling!
Stay back!
Even cut off, a wolf's head can still bite.
Aim where she falls.
Fire!
Stay back!
Get up!
Wait!
She's trapped now!
Don't let her escape!
Kill her!
Are you all right, sir?
Don't worry about me, go!
You...you're Mononoke, too!
Halt!
Please step aside.
What are you doing, Ashitaka?!
I'm taking this girl.
I'm sure she'll make a lovely wife.
There is a demon inside you.
It's inside her, as well.
Look on this!
It is the manifestation of the hatred
that haunts my cursed body!
It rots my flesh, and ushers me
towards death!
Do not foster such
hatred anymore!
Don't push your misfortunes on us.
I'll take care of that arm for you...
Lady Eboshi!
Someone come and take her.
Don't worry. She'll wake up shortly.
The girl leaves with me.
Wait! I won't let you leave!
Why did you hurt Lady Eboshi like that!
Don't move!
Kiyo, stop it!
How does he still walk?
- What about Lady Eboshi?
- Sh-she's fine!
Bring me my gun!
Gunners, assemble here!
They won't get away!
Toki, quick!
Ashitaka?
Please, we can't let you pass.
We will not raise this gate.
Turn back, please...
We are greatful for your help.
We don't want you as an enemy.
We beg you...
I entered this morning on my own two feet.
Now I shall leave the same way.
What are you doing?  It takes
ten men to open that gate!
Sir, no! You're killing yourself!
It moved!
Move aside!
Wolves!
Fire, I need fire!
Stop! Your princess is safe!
I'm coming out now!
Yakkuru, let's go!
I thank you.
He's gone...
Wait!
That one's mine.
They attacked you?
Are you going to die?
Why did you interfere?!
Speak while you still live!
I couldn't let you die...
I'm not afraid to die!  If it would
stop the humans, I would happily die!
I could see that in your eyes
when I first saw you.
And now your meddling
will cost you your life!
Cutting your throat should
stop you from saying stupid things.
You must survive...
Shut up!  I don't take orders from humans!
You are beautiful...
What's wrong, San?
Shall I snap his neck?
Apes?!
Apes! Do you mean disrespect
to the tribe of Moro?
This is our forest.
Give us human.
Give us human and go.
Leave, before my fangs find you.
Go, go...
We eat man.
We eat the human.
Let us eat the man.
Noble Apes...are you not
the guardians of the forest?
Why would you wish to eat a human?
We eat human. We receive his power.
We need power to drive humans
away. So we eat.
It won't work! Such power
will not come from eating humans!
Eating humans will taint your blood!
You will destroy yourselves!
We planted trees.
We plant and we plant.
Humans rip it up.
Forest not return.
We kill humans.
The Shishi-Gami is with us.
Keep planting the trees!
The Moro tribe will fight
alongside you until the end!
Shishi-Gami will not fight.
We all die.
Wolf girl not care.
Wolf girl is human.
You insolent monkey!
I shall break your neck!
Stop it!
I'm fine, don't worry about me...
You go ahead. I'll deal
with the human.
What about that one?
Can we eat him?
No, you can't. Now, get going.
Come here. Let's make peace.
Please.  I'll need your help
to carry your master.
You're smart. You know
not to set foot on this island.
I stink of human...
Go where you like,
and live as you please.
There he is!
The Daidarabotchi! At last!
Quick! Come and look!
This is whole reason we've been
wearing these stinking pelts!
If you look at the Shishi-Gami,
you will go blind!
And yet you consider yourselves
among the best hunters in the west?
Have you not seen our orders,
signed by the Emporer himself?
We have permission to exterminate
the Shishi-Gami! So move!
The Daidarabotchi is
the Shishi-Gami's nighttime form.
Very soon it should turn back...
This is the Shishi-Gami's den.
Oh, it's vanishing...look!
Jiko!
I know.
Over there...
There's hundreds of them.
They're not from these woods.
But each is a renowned lord
from other mountains.
It's Okkoto of Chinzei island!
Chinzei? Are you saying he crossed the sea?
There's no mistaking those tusks.
And the bastard brought his
whole tribe with him!
We're discovered! Fall back, quickly!
Come on! Jump! Jump!
My wound is gone!
Yakkuru...
If you're awake, thank Yakkuru.
He watched you the whole time.
How do you know his name?
He's told me all about you,
your village, your forest...
The Shishi-Gami brought you
back to life, so I will help you.
I had a strange dream...a golden deer...
Eat.
Chew.
We're here to kill the humans
and save the forest.
Why are there humans here?
The girl is San, my daughter.
The humans are everywhere. Go back
to your mountain and kill them there.
We kill for the forest
of the Shishi-Gami.
Why are there humans here?
The Shishi-Gami healed this man.
Therefore we will not kill him.
The Shishi-Gami saved him?
The Shishi-Gami healed his wounds?!
Why did he not save Nago?
Is the Shishi-Gami not
the guardian of the forest?!
The Shishi-Gami not only gives life,
he also takes it away.
Have you boars forgotten even that?
No, the wolves monopolize the Shishi-Gami!
You pull his attention from the rest of us!
And by not saving Nago,
you've betrayed us!
Nago feared his own death...
...and I now understand...
...as I carry inside me
a similar poison stone.
Nago fled, but I remain,
and contemplate my death.
Moro! You must ask the Shishi-Gami...
San, I have already lived long enough.
The Shishi-Gami will probably
take my life, rather than heal me.
No! Mother, you're here
to protect the Shishi-Gami!
We are not fooled! Nago was beautiful
and strong. Our brother would not run!
You wolves must have eaten him!
Silence! My mother shall not be slandered
by the likes of you!
Wild gods of the mountains, please hear me.
It was I who killed Nago.
A tatari-gami attacked my village,
and to save my people, I felled it.
It was a large boar-god.
And here is my proof...
I came to this land to ask
the Shishi-Gami to lift my curse.
He healed my injuries,
but did not remove the mark.
He told me to live on in pain,
until the curse destroys me.
Okkoto! At last, someone with some sense!
Okkoto, wait!
You mustn't eat him!
You are Moro's daughter.
I have heard of you.
Your eyes...
Stand back. I will not eat him.
Wolf Princess...
Do not fear. I must pass along
the final moments of Nago's life.
My thanks to you, young one.
It is a sad thing for a tatari-gami
to have come from one of our tribe.
Lord Okkoto...do you know
how I may lift my curse?
Leave this forest. When next we meet,
I will have to kill you.
You cannot win against
the guns of the humans.
Moro, look on my tribe.
We grow small, and we grow stupid.
To go on in this manner...
...is to end as nothing more
than meat for the humans to hunt.
To risk all on a final battle
is to play into human hands.
I do not ask for the help of wolves.
Even if we all perish in the fight,
we boars will have our vengence.
The Shishi-Gami!
Keep the oxen together!
Hold your fire...let them come!
Fire!
Reload! Quick!
That damned Eboshi's fighting
the wrong enemy!
You men go on ahead, and keep hidden.
I see them!
They're coming back!
Chief...
Oh, good, you are here.
Let them know, we'll be moving soon.
Hello, Jiko.
The Emporer wishes us to act. Now is not
the time to spar with the local samurai.
Lord Asano sets them against me.
Asano, eh? A powerful man.
He demanded half our iron.
Greedy, isn't he.
But now is no time to fight men.
The boars gather in the forest.
They'll be coming here soon.
I suggest you give Asano what he wants.
And after the Emporer's wishes are met,
you can fight whomever you like.
Laby Eboshi! Hurry!
More samurai are coming!
Speak of the devil! Asano's messengers...
Messengers!
Remember your manners, ladies!
Welcome back!
Hey, don't you want to hear them out?
Eboshi of Tatara Ba, your battle
with the local samurai was magnificent!
We bring a message from the Chief Warlord.
Respectfully open your gates!
We can hear you just fine where you are!
Lady Eboshi slaved to free this land
from the Mononoke.
And now that it's worth something,
you show up!
Leave here immediately!
Insolent women!
Show some respect!
Insolent women!?
We haven't had any respect
since the day we were born!
You want iron?  Here you go!
They're really something!
Samurai or forest god,
they don't care.
Eboshi's women don't lack courage.
What good is this paper?
Well, it's been impressive enough
to get me the resources I need...
...after all, we are going to kill a god!
Yes, Lady Eboshi?
Does this paper mean anything to you?
It is from the Imperial Court.
- The Imperial Court?
- What's that?
- And signed by the Emporer.
- The Emporer...?
OK, you got me there.
You may go.
Each day that we cut trees and make
our steel, the forest grows weaker.
My way, there are fewer casualties.
We gave you plenty of money and steel.
And we didn't lend you guns and troops
just so you could make more of both.
Of course, I'm sure you know that.
Could it be someone has
led the Emporer to think...
...that the Shishi-Gami's head
will bestow immortality?
I'm sure I don't know what
the Emporer thinks.
I'm just a simple monk, afterall.
I will keep my promises.
The boars will be easier
than Moro and her tribe.
And bring out those suspicious troops
you've got 'hidden' down in the ravine.
So I'm found out, am l?
Oh, and one more thing...
Did a young man pass through your land?
Riding a strange red elk?
He's already left.
They make my skin crawl!
They're not ordinary hunters.
They're Jibashiri.
Let us go with you!
We can't trust them!
We can't help you from here
if anything happens!
And you've taught us to shoot!
And that's why I need you here.
I fear humans more than Mononoke.
After the Shishi-Gami is dead,
you just watch.
It isn't just the Shishi-Gami's head
that those umbrella-toting monks want.
And even the gunner troops they've
sent us may become our enemies.
We can't trust men.
Stay on your toes.
Don't worry about Lady Eboshi.
I'll protect her with my life.
- If only that were true!
- What?!
Maybe if you were a woman...
Do you suffer?
You could end it all
by jumping, you know.
Even as your strength returns,
the mark will continue to spread.
I feel like I've slept for days.
I dreamt that San was watching over me.
I hoped you would cry out in your sleep,
so I could bite off your head.
What a beautiful forest...
Are the boars moving yet?
Go back into the cave, boy.
You can't hear it...
The cry of the woods
trampled under by boars...
I sit here listening to it,
and to the crumbling of my body...
...and wait for that woman...
How I yearn to crush
her head in my jaws!
Moro, is there no way for the forest
and the humans to live in peace?
Must this end in fighting?!
The humans spread farther
and farther.
In time, they'll spread even to here.
And what about San?
When you die, is she left alone?
Typical human.  Irrational, selfish...
She is a daughter of the forest.
She shall live and die with the forest.
Set her free! She's human!
Silence, boy!
You know nothing of what she is!
Humans who violated our forest
threw her in my path to slow me down!
She cannot be human,
nor can she become wolf.
She is my dear, ugly,
furless child...
How can you hope to save her?!
I don't know.
But together we could survive.
And how will you do that?
Side by side, fighting the humans?
No. That would only spurn more
hatred and pain!
There is nothing you can do, boy.
Soon that mark will kill you.
Leave here when the sun rises.
Were you able to walk?
Only thanks to you and the Shishi-Gami.
Yakkuru! Sorry for worrying you!
My legs are so weak!
It's too quiet...where are the kodama?
We're close enough to
smell Tatara Ba's forge...
Thank you for your help.
I have one favor to ask of you.
Please give this to San.
Let's go.
What a terrible smell!
It makes me sick!
That's not normal smoke.
It's to confuse our sense of smell.
That woman has arrived.
...and she knows we're here!
- Such an obvious trap.
- A trap?
She's trying to lure the boars
into leaving the forest.
She's has something big planned...
Then we must warn them!
They'll all be killed!
Okkoto is no fool.
He will realize it is a trap,
but the boars will charge anyways.
They are a proud race.
The last one alive
will still be charging forward.
They've begun cutting trees.
More bait.
Mother, I must go.
I must help Okkoto.
I can be his eyes.
As you will.
Although there is another path...
a life with that human boy...
I hate humans!
From Ashitaka? For me?
It's beautiful...
You two go with San.
I will stay with the Shishi-Gami.
Let's go.
The tribe of Moro fights with you!
Where is Okkoto?
Thank you.
It's coming from Tatara Ba!
Let's go!
Who goes there?!
Samurai!
Halt!
Let me pass!
Who was that?!
- He's stopping them!
- What!?
Don't waste your arrows!
Come quick!
You're right! It is him!
Is it a ghost!?
Ashitaka!
Toki?
Is everyone all right?
More or less...
As soon as our men were out of sight,
the samurai moved in to attack!
They've taken the lower ward!
But we're holding them off!
Where's Lady Eboshi?
She took every man who could move
and went to kill the Shishi-Gami!
We've no way to call
her back for help!
Hunt the Shishi-Gami?!
So that sound before...
Sir! I've still got your bow!
What about his saddle and cloak?!
- But...
- Useless!
Koroku, thanks!
I'll bring help. Can you hold out?
If worse comes to worse, we can
always pour hot iron on them!
Hurry, Ashitaka!
Bring Lady Eboshi back quickly!
Missed!
They're bringing boats. Hurry!
We entrust Lady Eboshi's safety to you!
And in the meantime, we will fight, too!
I'll be back! Good luck!
Be careful!
There he is!  Signal ahead!
They're after us, Yakkuru!
Burning flesh...
Yakkuru!
Stay back!
Yakkuru, show me your wound...
I'm sorry, I need you to wait here.
I will return.
I said wait!
Just a little further...
Who goes there?!
This is a place for the dead.
You must leave immediately!
I have an urgent message from
the people of Tatara Ba.
I must see Lady Eboshi.
She's not here. You will
tell me, instead.
I will speak only to her! Where is she?!
Young sir...you're alive!?
What a mess this has all become.
There's still men buried.
It was horrible...
Tatara Ba is under siege by samurai.
The women are holding the inner stockade.
There is still hope if you go now!
The bastards!
Asano waited untill we left!
Is Lady Eboshi here?
No, she's gone to kill the Shishi-Gami!
We must call her back!
There's no time!
If you are done spouting
nonsense, then leave.
Everyone back to work!
Are you serious?
Now wait a minute!
Do you intend to leave
those at Tatara Ba to die?
If we wait we'll be too late!
Send a messenger to find Eboshi!
The woods are huge.
How could we find Eboshi in time?
Aren't you supposed to be
good trackers?  Help us!
Lady Eboshi's being used.
Tell me, when the boars came,
did you see any wolves among them?
Or San, the Mononoke princess?
I don't know...it was pitch black
when they came at us.
She was there.
I was in the front...
What happened?
I...I can't remember.
Everything just happened so fast!
Jiko's monks put us out there
to lure the boars in.
They must have laid explosives
under the ground...
...everything just exploded around us!
Where's San?!
Be still! I want to help you.
A wolf! There's a wolf
still alive over here!
Sir! What are you doing?!
Sir!
Move!  Boy, what are you doing!?
I need this wolf to guide me.
If you will not look for Eboshi, I will.
So you're with them, are you?
Move.
What's more important, the head of
the Shishi-Gami, or Tatara Ba?
Poison darts!
Stop!
Everyone together!
He's free!
Go through the swamp
and hide near the lake.
The gunners are with them.
Be careful.
Take this. My last arrow's broken.
You go with them.
Take care of Yakkuru for me!
Find San! That's where Eboshi will be!
Don't fall behind the Jibashiri.
Today we finish this!
Jiko...
Well? How does it look?
Okkoto's hurt. He and the girl
are moving deeper into the forest.
They go to the Shishi-Gami
for help. Follow them!
But the Shishi-Gami will not appear
if they suspect you are human!
Not a problem.
Is that boar's blood on his face?
That's the Jibashiri, for you.
Disgusting, isn't it?
Keep going! We're almost to
the Shishi-Gami's waters.
Something's coming!
Okkoto, something's wrong!
We're so close.  Hang in there!
Something unnatural is approaching.
There's too much blood.
I can't smell what it is.
The apes!
You did this.
It is your fault. Forest will die.
Is this how you thank those
who fought for your forest?
You've brought something unspeakable!
Things neither animal nor human!
Neither animal nor human?
- They're here!
- It's the end!
Warriors!
They've returned...
They've returned!  My warriors have
returned from the land of the dead!
Forward, my warriors!
To the Shishi-Gami's waters!
Okkoto, no! The dead
cannot come back to life!
They wear boar skins
to hide their scent!
They're men!
Stop! You must not bring them
to the Shishi-Gami!
Shishi-Gami! Show yourself!
If you are lord of this forest, revive
my warriors and we shall slay the humans!
Okkoto! You must calm yourself!
We're surrounded!
Okkoto's done for! Leave him!
No! He'll end up a tatari-gami!
Go and warn Mother of
what the humans have done!
We need her strength!
Hurry, the Moro tribe must not die!
Go!
I will kill the first
one that moves.
And your true form will be
exposed for all the forest to see!
Ashitaka?
Stay Back!
I burn! A flame bursts from within me!
No!
Okkoto! You mustn't become a tatari-gami!
Okkoto!
An answer!
What is it?
- San's in danger!
- Let's go!
It burns!
No!
I don't want to become a tatari-gami!
Please, Okkoto!
Too slow! Get on!
A wolf!
Eboshi!
Dammit! You go on ahead!
Eboshi, listen!
Stop!
Ashitaka?
The samurai are attacking Tatara Ba!
Stop this futile hunt and return at once!
The women are fighting!
The men are heading back now!
Your people need you!
What proof do you have?
None! I would have stayed
and fought if I could!
So it's 'don't kill the Shishi-Gami,
kill the samurai,' is it?
Why can't the forest and the
people of Tatara Ba live together?
Which side is he on?
Let's go back!
I've done all I can for the women.
They can defend themselves.
We've reached water.
The Shishi-Gami won't be far.
The moment of truth!
Don't let down your guard!
Why don't we get rid of her now?
Killing gods is scary business.
Let her do it.
Moro! Are you alive?
San!
San, where are you?
Ashitaka!
Okkoto...
Leave, boy.
If we fight, the Shishi-Gami
will not appear.
Okkoto! Be still!
Okkoto! Return San to me.
Where is she?
San, can you hear me?
It's me, Ashitaka!
San!
Shut him up!
Kill him! Kill him!
San!
Ashitaka!
And here I thought I was saving my
last bit of strength for Eboshi...
Close ranks!
Do not let him touch you.
It's curse is not for you to carry.
Have you lost your power of speech?
Well done. Fall back
and tend to the wounded.
My, my, what a horrible sight!
There he is!
Give me back my daughter!
Ashitaka...
Will you save San?
The Shishi-Gami...
Eboshi! Don't shoot!
Eboshi! The Shishi-Gami
is not your enemy!
Your gun was ineffective.
That was only my first try.
San!
Don't die!
What?! Why did
the Shishi-Gami kill them?
He's transitioning to the Daidarabotchi!
Everyone! Watch closely.
I will show you how you kill a god.
The Shishi-Gami may be
a god of life and death...
...but that is no excuse to cower in fear!
Stop!
Eboshi!
Goddammit, you demon!
Got him! Go grab the head!
Jiko! Bring the box!
The porters are all dead!
Quickly, quickly!
Do not touch the Shishi-Gami's body.
It will steal your life away!
As promised, one head!
Lady Eboshi!
Moro, you bitch!  Just a head,
and still a wolf can bite!
Come on, come on!
Hurry, hurry!
Jiko!
Run!
To the island!
But I can't swim!
Then walk along the bottom!
Give her to me! I'll rip her apart!
Moro's already taken her revenge.
Eboshi is punished.
Lady Eboshi!
Give me a hand!
I don't need your help.
I promised Toki and the others
that I would bring you back.
He's looking for his head.
We can't stay here.
San!
I need your help.
No! You're on the side of the humans!
Take that woman and leave!
You humans did this,
and I hate you all!
I am human.
...and so are you.
Silence! I am wolf!
- San...
- Stay away from me!
I'm sorry. I tried to stop this.
It's over. Everything.
The forest is dead.
Nothing is over.  We're still alive.
Please, San, help me.
Wait! Help us!
A little crisis and they're useless!
No, no, no!
The head's moving!
It's calling him here!
It's fixed.
Thanks.
It's very quiet...
They're waiting for dawn.
I wonder if that young man
found Lady Eboshi...
Of course he did! They'll be
marching over that hill any minute now.
Oh, look at that scruffy face.
Hey! Koroku!
Oh, let him sleep while he can.
I don't like the sound of that...
The Daidarabotchi!
Don't leave your posts!
What do we do?!
It's coming this way!
It's no good! We run!
We guard Tatara Ba!
That's what we promised Lady Eboshi!
Down there! It's Ashitaka!
Everyone run!
The Shishi-Gami is searching
for its stolen head!
Touch that black muck, and you will die!
Head into the lake!
The water will slow it down!
Eboshi and the men are on
the other side, heading this way!
We'll try to return the Shishi-Gami's head!
- Ashitaka...
- Please hurry!
It's coming this way!
What should we do, Toki?
Don't Panic!
Everyone into the water.
Stay calm! And help the injured!
No, not that way!
Oh no...the roof...
It's no use. Tatara Ba is lost.
This is the end!
As long as we're alive, we have hope!
To deeper water!  Quickly!
There they are!
Go!
Stop!
Oh, you're alive! Thank goodness!
We must return the head.
Put it down and back away.
Fool! We're so close!
The sun is about to rise!
It's bloated and slow...look...
...and when the sun's rays touch it,
it will vanish like a bad dream!
Jiko, it's coming! Hurry!
Look, everyone wants everything, that's
human nature...but I'm about to get it!
I don't want to kill you...
Of course...
Don't look so stern...
Run!
Ashitaka!
Uh-oh...
We're surrounded!
Morning sun, rise!
Open it!
Don't you get it?  It's too late!
Ashitaka, don't bother talking to humans...
I wish to return it with human hands.
Dammit, I don't think this is a good idea.
Noble Shishi-Gami!
We return your head!
Take it in peace!
Here he comes!
It's stopped...
The men!
Lady Eboshi!
Mind her wounds!
It's falling!
Hang on! Don't let go!
Amazing.  The Shishi-Gami brings
life, even in the face of death.
San, look!
Even if it all grows back, this is
no longer the Shishi-Gami's forest.
The Shishi-Gami is dead.
The Shishi-Gami can't die.
He is life itself.
Life and death, he lives on in both.
And he's told me to live.
Ashitaka, you mean a lot to me.
But I haven't forgiven humans.
That's all right. You return to the forest.
And I will help rebuild Tatara Ba.
I'll always be near.
Yakkuru and I will visit you.
As often as we can.
Can you believe it?
Saved by wolves!
Someone bring Ashitaka.
I want to thank him.
We'll start over again.
We'll build a good village.
Well, I give up!
You can't win against fools...
The End