Name?
Horowitz, Salomon.
Schneider, Sarah.
Birnbaum, Olga.
- Over there.
- Come here.
Over there.
Isak Hudes
Zucker, Helena
Hirsch, Salomon
Hauptman, Chaim
Weisman. Weisman, Marcus
Feber, Ludwig
Elsa Bauman
- Josef Klein
- Klein
Davidowich, Ignacy
Paula Biffer
Nadel, Rachela
- Steiner, Gertruda
- Steiner, Hilda
- Jerzy, do you know who that man is?
- I don't know.
Let's get together, please.
Smile. Good.
Yes, sir
Bring them over a round of drinks.
Very good, sir.
And who shall I say they are from?
You can say they are from me.
From the gentleman.
Where?
Do you know him?
Find out who he is.
Yes, sir
Agnieszka,
I would
give anything to hear you sing tonight
but I know you won't.
You embarrass me.
What's he doing?
Stay here.
How are you doing?
You'd leave a woman
alone at the table in a place like this?
Sweetheart, you're the picture of loneliness.
Oh
Mmm what a
lovely fragrance. You are breaking my heart.
An extra chair, please. Vodka for my friend.
And for the lady?
Pernod.
Come to the table, girls. Drink with us.
Come to us. Marry us.
Thank you.
I'll tell you what I mean by cooperative.
Two days after the law is passed
that all jews have to wear the star
the jewish tailors
are turning them out by the gross
in a variety of fabrics at three zloty each.
Tell me about your cellar wines.
- I have an excellent German Riesling: 1937.
- Mmm French
- A Bordeaux: Chateau Latour, '28, '29?
- No, I'm sorry.
It's as if
they have no idea what kind of law it is.
As if it's the emblem of a riding club.
- A Margaux, '29?
- No no, we don't have that.
- Burgundy then? A Romanee-Conti, '37?
- Yes
It's
human nature: "We'll do this to avoid that."
That's what
they have done since thousands of years.
It's what they do. They weather the storm
but this storm is different.
This is not the Romans. This storm is the SS.
Martin
Yes, sir
Who is that man?
That's Oskar Schindler.
To all jews:
From now on all jews are forbidden
to prepare meat in the kosher manner.
Message to all jews. From now on
- Rabbi
- Private property cannot be confiscated.
How long are the schools going to be closed?
I do not know.
Article 47: Pillage is formally prohibited.
You don't know anything.
I am familiar
with the Hague Convention. Religious...
They come into our house
and tell us we don't live there anymore.
It now belongs to a certain SS officer.
Please. I only know what they tell me
and
what they tell me changes from day to day.
Aren't you supposed to be able to help?
I mean, what if I just took this thing off.
What are they going to do about it?
They will shoot you.
- Why don't you stop this silly talk?
- Itzhak Stern
I'm looking for Itzhak Stern.
Are you Itzhak Stern or not?
- I am.
- Where can we talk?
There's a company
you did the books for on Lipowa Street.
It made... what? pots and pans?
By law I have to tell you, sir: I'm a jew.
Well, I'm a German. So there we are.
A good company, you think?
Modestly successful.
I know nothing about enamelware. Do you?
I was just the accountant.
Simple engineering though,
wouldn't you think?
Change
the machines around, whatever you do...
you could make other things, couldn't you?
...field kits, mess kits: army contracts.
Once the war ends
forget it, but for now it's great.
You could make a fortune, don't you think?
I think
most people right now have other priorities.
Like what?
I'm sure you'll
do just fine once you get the contracts.
In fact
the worse things get, the better you'll do.
Oh I can get
the signatures I need. That's the easy part.
Finding
the money to buy the company: that's hard.
You don't have any money?
Not that kind of money. Do you know anybody?
Jews, yeah. Investors
You must have contacts in the
jewish business community, working here.
What community?
Jews can no longer own businesses.
That's why this one's in receivership.
But they wouldn't own it.
I'd own it.
I'd pay them back in product, pots and pans.
Pots and pans:
something they can use
something they can feel in their hands.
They can trade it on the black market
do whatever they want. Everybody's happy.
If you want,
you could run the company for me.
Let me understand.
They'd
put up all the money. I'd do all the work.
What,
if you don't mind my asking, would you do?
I'd make sure
it's known, the company's in business.
I'd see that it had a certain panache.
That's what
I'm good at, not the work, not the work:
the presentation.
I'm sure I don't know
anybody who'll be interested in this.
Well, they should be, Itzhak Stern.
Tell them they should be.
Attention. Attention.
To all jews. From now on it is forbidden...
I've got a client
who'll sell marks for zloty at 2.45 to 1.
Wool, mink collar. It's a nice coat.
She'll trade it for ration coupons.
Wicks for lamps.
You have a truckload of wicks?
What
am I going to do with a truckload of wicks?
Nine by 12, nine by 14.
- I don't know.
- Big, beautiful, Persian
Past
What?
You don't recognize this? It's shoe polish.
In metal containers?
You asked for shoe polish.
...in metal containers. This is glass.
It's not what I asked for.
- What's the difference?
What's the difference?
My client sold it to his client
who sold it to the German army
only, by the time it got there, because
of the
freezing cold, it broke. All 10,000 units.
Mmm ooh ooh ooh. This is not my problem.
- This is not his problem.
- This is not your problem?
This is not my problem.
All right.
The German army
wants to find out where it came from.
I am going to make sure they find out.
Now it's your problem.
You, be quiet.
Metal containers.
Hello
Pardon me
for interfering, but that's a nice shirt.
...a nice shirt.
Do you know
where I can find a nice shirt like that?
Like this?
It's illegal
to buy or sell anything on the street.
We don't do that. We're here to pray.
Do you have
any idea how much a shirt like this costs?
Nice things cost money.
How many?
I'm going to need
some other things too, as things come up
This won't be a problem.
...from time to time.
Attention. Attention.
Name? Address?
Fill out the form.
Move on. move on.
Don't push.
Come here.
Stand by.
Attention. Attention.
All jews are accommodated
in the separate jewish district.
Failure
to comply with the obligation to report
to the resident's authority
will be dealt by the military court.
This is
obviously the right place. How are you doing?
Goodbye, jews. Goodbye, jews.
Goodbye, jews.
- This is the vecheka, Moyshe.
- Ojciec.
No. This can't be true.
Oh my God
Oy God. Oh my God
It could not be better.
It could be worse.
How? Tell me.
How on earth could it possibly be worse?
Good morning
- Hey, Goldberg
- Poldek
What's this?
The Judenrat has its own police now, Poldek.
You don't say.
"Ordnungsdienst"
- I'm a policeman now. Could you believe it?
- It's hard to believe.
No, it's not hard to believe.
It's
a good racket, Poldek, the only racket here.
Look. Maybe I could
put in a good word for you with my superiors.
Your superiors?
Come on.
They are not as bad as everyone says.
Well, they're worse than everyone says
but it's a lot of money, a lot of money.
Give me my housing assignment.
Come on.
You look funny in that hat, Goldberg.
You look like a clown, you know.
He's a very important man.
Just give him two minutes of your time.
- Since when did time cost money?
- Just sit down and listen.
Please. Sir?
For
each 1,000 you invest, I will repay you with
two hundred kilos of enamelware a month
to begin
in July and to continue for one year
after which time, we're even.
That's it. It's very simple.
Not good enough.
It's not good enough.
Not good enough?
Look where you're living. Look
where you've been put. "Not good enough."
A couple
of months ago you'd be right. Not anymore.
Money's still money.
No, it is not.
That's why we're here.
Trade goods: that's the only currency
that'll be worth anything in the ghetto.
Things have changed, my friend.
Did I call this meeting?
You told Mr. Stern you wanted to speak to me.
I'm here. I've made you a fair offer.
Fair would be a percentage in the company.
Forget the whole thing. Get out.
How do we know that you will do what you say?
Because I said I would.
You want
a contract? To be upheld by what court?
I said what I'll do. That's our contract.
We were right.
...five, six, seven
eight, nine...
The standard SS rate for
jewish skilled labourers is seven marks a day
five for unskilled and women.
This
is what you pay the Reich Economic Office.
The jews themselves receive nothing.
Poles: you pay wages.
Generally they get a little more.
Are you listening?
What was that about the SS?
The rate? The what?
The jewish worker's salary.
You pay it
directly to the SS, not to the worker.
- He gets nothing.
- But it's less.
It's less than what I would pay a Pole.
It's less.
That's the point I'm trying to make.
Poles cost more.
Why should I hire Poles?
An enamelware factory over at Lipowa Street.
It's owned by a German
but it's outside the ghetto,
so you can barter for extra goods
for eggs, I don't know what you need
with
the Polish workers. You can't get it here.
Also,
he's asking for 10 healthy women for the...
I am healthy.
Bring your sister, OK?
Come.
You need to convince them you have a trade
something valuable to the war effort.
- Like what?
- What if you don't?
I'm a musician.
Your name goes on a list.
I hear your name
goes on a list and they put you on trucks...
- No no. That's not true.
- You're a musician?
- Lisa
- Yeah
I'd find a good hiding place if I were you.
I'm not going to hide like some animal.
There are places to hide.
I'm a graduate of the University of Lviv.
I used to work
at the hydroelectric station in Roznow.
Blue card
I'm going to get the necessary papers
because this card is no good anymore.
You can stay in this line
all day. You'll still get one of these.
They are
no good. You'll have to leave the line now.
Then you'll get a blue card, a blauschein
to say that you are an essential worker.
I'll get these papers for you at Pankiewicz.
Pharmacist. Just there, look.
Guess who is here?
Poldek. Enjoying the weather, Poldek?
Enjoying the lines?
Need some shoe polish?
In a metal container maybe?
Not essential?
I think
you misunderstand the meaning of the word.
No blue card, sir.
Stand over there. Move. Next.
What do you mean, "not essential"?
I teach history and literature.
Since when it's not essential?
He's a metal polisher.
It was not right?
It's very good. He's 53 years old.
It's too new.
Mmm thank you.
You're crazy. You left it in your drawer.
How many times have I told you?
"Your work certificate
you keep in your pocket at all times"
and you leave yours
in your drawer! How many times I've told you?
I'm a metal polisher.
Take the round sheet of tin
dip it in soap emulsion
then place it centrally in the press.
We obtain the soup pot.
...the soup pot.
...soup pot.
Grosz, Mrs. Grosz, stay together.
Sir, I have 10 work permits here
for the Deutsche Emailwarenfabrik.
If it's carbonized, clean it with a file
but don't touch
both the electrodes at the same time.
You'll get electrocuted. Here. Have a try.
Roll the metal under the press
but
be very careful unless you want your fingers
to become part of the teapot.
Occupation?
I'm a writer. I play the flute.
But Moses is a skilled metalworker.
He can make tin pots. He can make tanks.
He can make whatever Mr. Schindler asks.
He's highly skilled. Give him
your card. Moses, give him your card.
Now, dip the basin
with the tongs into the enamel solution
and after swivelling it around,
carefully place it aside to drip dry.
And whatever he asks you, allow me
just to represent you and speak for you.
Don't say a word.
Filing, billing,
keeping track of my appointments, shorthand
typing, obviously... How is your typing?
Uh all right.
Please
You need a secretary. Pick one.
I don't know how. They're all so... qualified.
You have to choose.
Please give a nice smile.
Big smile. Big smile.
Attention.
If you would, look after my guest.
Boxed teas are good. Coffee, pate
kielbasa sausage, cheeses, Beluga caviar.
- Yes
- And of course
who could live without German cigarettes?
Get me as many as you can find
and some more fresh fruit
the real
rarities: oranges, lemons, pineapples.
I need
several boxes of Cuban cigars, the best
yes and dark, unsweetened chocolate.
not in the shape
of lady fingers, the chunk chocolate
big as my hand, you sample at wine tastings.
Yes
We're going to
need lots of cognac, the best: Hennessy
Dom Perignon champagne.
Get L'Espadon sardines
and oh, try to find nylon stockings.
It is my distinct pleasure to announce
the fully operational
status of Deutsche Emailwarenfabrik
See some rags.
Manufacturers
of superior enamelware crockery
expressly
designed and crafted for military use
utilizing only the most modern equipment.
D.E.F.'s staff of highly skilled and
experienced artisans and journeymen
deliver a product of unparalleled quality
enabling me
to proffer, with absolute confidence and pride
a full line of field and kitchenware
unsurpassable
in all respects by my competitors.
See attached list and available colours.
Anticipating
the enclosed bids will meet with your approval
and looking forward
to a long and mutually prosperous association
I extend
to you in advance my sincerest gratitude
and very best regards.
Oskar Schindler.
Yeah. I need
700 gross from here for next Thursday.
Nine hundred...
No. Make it 10 for Wednesday.
All this stuff here goes to Madritsch's
factory on Tuesday of next week.
My father was fond
of saying, "You need three things in life:
"a good doctor
"a forgiving priest
"and a clever accountant."
The first two
I've never had much use for
but the third...
Just pretend, for Christ's sake.
Is that all?
I'm trying to thank you.
I'm saying,
I couldn't have done this without you.
The usual thing
would be to acknowledge my gratitude.
It would also,
by the way, be the courteous thing.
You're welcome.
Get out of here.
Klonowska, who is it?
She's so embarrassed. Look at her.
You know something? You would like her.
- Oskar, please
- What?
I don't
have to like her just because you do.
You would, though.
It doesn't work that way.
You've done well here.
You look wonderful.
Be careful of the step, miss.
Mrs. Schindler, Marek
It's not a charade, all this?
A charade? How could it be a charade?
The clothes, the car, the apartment...
Wait a minute.
Take a guess.
How many people are on my payroll?
Oskar
My father, at the height
of his success, had 50. I've got 350
350 workers
on the factory floor, with one purpose:
...to make pots and pans?
...to make money
for me.
Does anyone ask about me?
Back home?
Everybody
all the time.
Hmm
They won't soon forget the name,
Schindler here. I can tell you that.
"Oskar Schindler," they'll say.
"Everybody remembers him.
"He did something extraordinary.
"He did something no one else did.
"He came here with nothing
"a suitcase
"and built
a bankrupt company into a major manufactory.
"and left with a steamer trunk
"two steamer trunks full of money
"all the riches of the world."
Hmm
It's
comforting to see that nothing's changed.
You're wrong, Emilie.
There's
no way I could have known this before
but there was always something missing.
Something was missing.
Even if I'd known what it was
there's nothing
I could have done about it because
you can't create this thing
and it makes all the difference
in the world between success and failure.
Luck?
War!
Should I stay?
It's a beautiful city.
I asked you if I should stay.
It's up to you.
Promise me, Oskar
no doorman or maitre d' will ever presume
I'm anyone other than Mrs. Schindler
and I'll stay.
Goodbye, darling
I could try to read this
or I could eat my lunch while it's still hot.
We're doing well?
- Yes
- Better this month than last?
Yes
Any reason to think next month will be worse?
The war could end.
What?
There is a machinist outside
who'd like
to thank you personally for giving him a job.
Every day he comes.
He's very grateful. It'll just take a minute.
Mr. Lowenstein?
I want to thank you, sir
for giving me the opportunity to work.
You're welcome.
I'm sure you're doing a great job.
The SS beat me up. They would have killed me
but I am
essential to the war effort, thanks to you.
That's great.
I work hard for you.
I'm sure you do.
I'll continue to work hard for you.
That's great. Thanks.
God bless you, sir.
All right.
You are a good man.
He saved my life.
Yes, he did.
God bless him.
Yeah. Come on.
God bless you.
I'm sorry,
Herr Direktor, but you're running very late.
This is for the Obersturmbannfuhrer, sir
and this is
for his niece, Greta. It's her birthday.
By the way
Greta as in Garbo.
don't ever do that to me again.
Go go. drive. Don't bow.
Did you happen to notice that
that man had one arm?
Did he?
What's his use?
Very useful.
How?
Brooms and shovels have been unloaded.
Everyone take one and clean the streets.
We'll be late for work.
You shouldn't think of them as yours, Oskar.
You need to understand
that some of the officers here
don't give a damn about production.
To them it's a matter of
national priority
that jews be made to shovel snow.
It's got nothing to do with reality, Oskar.
You know it and I know it.
Jews shovelling snow:
It's got a ritual significance.
Come with me.
I am an essential worker.
An essential worker?
Yes
I work for Oskar Schindler.
An essential worker for Oskar Schindler.
A one-armed jew? Twice as useless!
- Yes yes
- Twice as useless!
I lost a day of production, Rolf.
I work for Oskar Schindler.
Danka, look at the snow.
Look at the snow. Look at the snow.
I lost a worker.
I expect to be compensated.
File a grievance with the Economic Office.
It's your right.
Would it do any good?
Of course not.
A big shot from the SS
Budget and Construction Office came to lunch
and he told us that to believe
the jewish skilled worker had a place in
Reich economics was a treasonable idea.
A one-armed machinist, Oskar?
He was a metal press operator
quite skilled.
Herr Direktor?
Shit. I don't believe it.
Stern, is that you?
No. It's Poldek.
It's about Stern.
Leave your luggage on the platform.
Clearly label it.
Given name first, then your surname.
Do not bring your baggage with you.
It will follow you later.
Leave your luggage on the platform.
Clearly label it.
Stern?
He's on the list.
He is?
Well, let's find him.
I'm sorry. You can't have him.
He's on the list.
If he were an essential worker,
he would not be on the list.
I'm talking to a clerk. What is your name?
Sir, the list is correct.
I didn't ask you about the list.
I asked you your name.
Klaus Tauber
Tauber
Hauptscharfuhrer
This gentleman thinks a mistake's been made.
My plant manager is somewhere on this train.
If it leaves
with him on it, it'll disrupt production
and
the Armaments Board will want to know why.
Attention. This train is leaving now.
Is he on the list?
Yes, sir
Itzhak Stern
Well
the list is correct, sir.
There is nothing I can do.
What is your name?
Close and secure all doors.
My name?
- My name is Kunder.
- This train is now leaving.
Kunder, Hauptscharfuhrer Kunder
K-U-N-D-E-R. And what's yours?
Schindler: S-C-H-I-N-D-L-E-R
Gentlemen, thank you very much.
I think I can guarantee you
you'll both be in southern Russia
before the end of the month. Good day.
Close the door properly.
Stern
Stern Stern
Itzhak Stern
Stern, Itzhak Stern
Stern Stern
Itzhak Stern
Stern
Sir?
- Stern
- Herr Direktor
My apologies.
Stop the train.
I apologize.
He's here.
Stop the train.
Stop the train. Stop it.
Sign here. Initial there.
It makes no difference to us, you understand.
This one, that one...
It's the inconvenience to the list.
It's the paperwork.
I somehow left my work card at home.
I tried to
explain to them, it was a mistake but
I'm sorry. It was stupid.
What if I'd got here five minutes later?
Then where would I be?
I woke up from a dream this morning.
I was broke and
sharing a room with 12 people I didn't know
only to discover I was broke and sharing
a room with 12 people I didn't know.
You laugh about it?
I have to laugh.
You are living behind walls.
The walls I can deal with.
It's
the restrictions to my life, I'm tired of.
Those walls
keep them out. That's all I care about.
I like it here.
There's a kind of... I don't know
...ancestral squalor to it all.
- You are a slave to these people.
- No one envies us anymore.
I'm smart.
Oh yes, you're smart.
You're a real genius.
You had your chance.
Today, today
I actually found time to organize a thought.
I can't remember the last time I did that.
When's the last time we did this?
When's
the last time we stood around and talked?
No one ordered me onto a truck today.
No one took my business away from me.
You don't really have a business to take.
There's nowhere down from here.
This is it. This is the bottom.
The ghetto is liberty.
This street
divides the ghetto just about in half.
Right side: Ghetto A
civil employees
industrial workers, and so on.
Left side: Ghetto B
surplus labour
the elderly and infirm mostly
which is where you will want to start.
Do you have any questions, sir?
Yeah.
Why is the top down? I'm fucking freezing.
We expect a labour force of 25,000 to 30,000
segregated, of course:
the men in the barracks near the quarry
the women on the other side of the wire.
My place is where?
There, sir.
- There?
- Yes, the villa
You call that a villa?
Their synagogue, can you see it?
That's not a villa.
We're planning
to turn it into the camp stables.
It's a house.
What's that over there?
- A kindergarten.
- Fifty-one
And we have a dentist,
a shoemaker, practical physicians4
There they are, sir.
Hmm
One of you is a very lucky girl.
There is
an opening for a job
away from all this
backbreaking work
at my new villa.
Uh
Which of you has domestic experience?
Yeah. On second thought,
I don't really want someone else's maid:
All those annoying habits I'd have to undo!
I don't want to give you my cold.
What's your name?
- Helen Hirsch
- What?
Helen Hirsch
What? I can't hear.
Yeah
Take it all down.
To work.
Take it down. It is not safe.
She says, the foundation
was poured wrong. She's got to take it down.
I told her it's
the barracks, not the fucking Hotel Europa.
Fucking
jew bitch engineer! You fucking bitch!
Herr Kommandant
the entire foundation
has to be torn down and re-poured.
If not, there will be at least a subsidence
at the southern end of the barracks:
subsidence
and then collapse.
- And you are an engineer?
- Yes
My name is Diana Reiter.
I'm a graduate of civil engineering
from the University of Milan.
An educated jew, like Karl Marx himself!
- Unterscharfuhrer
- Yes?
Shoot her.
What?
Herr Kommandant
I'm only trying to do my job.
Yeah and I'm doing mine.
But sir, she's foreman of construction.
We are not
going to have arguments with these people.
OK
No. Shoot her here, on my authority.
It will take more than that.
I'm sure you're right.
Take it down, re-pour it
rebuild it
like she said.
We have more to see
but we have only one more hour of light.
Today is history.
Today will be remembered.
Years from now
the young
will ask with wonder about this day.
Today is history and you are part of it.
Six hundred years ago
when elsewhere they were
footing the blame for the Black Death
Kazimierz the Great
so-called
told the jews, they could come to Krakow.
They came.
Not that fat. No, less.
They trundled their belongings into the city.
Yes, a bit less
They settled.
They took hold.
They prospered
in business, science, education, the arts...
They came here with nothing.
Nothing!
...and they flourished.
For six centuries
there has been a jewish Krakow.
Think about that.
By this evening
those six centuries are a rumour.
They never happened.
Today is history.
Spread out and enter in two rows.
Comrades, quickly.
I think we will start with Ghetto B.
Hopp hopp hopp hopp
All right?
Start from both sides?
- No no. I would like you to start there.
- The right side?
- The right side, yeah.
- And then move around.
All right.
Open.
Get up.
- Quite a bit
- Oh
Hopp hopp hopp hopp
Come down.
Get down, jews.
To the square.
Gold, Chaim
Chodi Square
Yes, Chaim Gold
Shoot him.
Do not kill. Do not kill.
Put warm clothes on
and go to the square.
No suitcases, no suitcases
Walk through.
Hey, little boy. How old are you, eh?
What's your name?
What's your name, eh?
No suitcases, I said.
Do not pack suitcases. No suitcases
Go to Chodi Square.
Leave your suitcases here.
Blue card: Chodi Square
What is this suitcase for?
They all go to Chodi Square.
We're getting out through the sewers.
I have to check if they're clear.
Mila,
pack some things: nothing bigger than this.
I can't go in the sewers.
I told you, I won't go in the sewers.
You can go.
Yes, you can.
I won't go in the sewers.
Move. Over there. Over there. Move.
Your card, jew
No papers, jew
That line
Your card
I am not going up
because of your damn card
your shit card.
What is this shit?
Have you gone crazy?
With this gun
you could have killed me.
You were so close to me.
What is the excuse here?
You must be crazy.
Stay back. Stay back.
Do not speak. Do not speak.
Just go to the trucks.
Continue running.
Continue running. Do not speak.
Come here, you jewish pig.
Stay still, I said. Stay still.
Walk here fast.
She's as good as dead. Leave her.
Give me
a moment. Just let me bring her inside.
You can join her
or join the line.
Women to the left.
- Wilhelm
- Rose
Men to right. Women to the left.
Women to the left.
Let me go. I won't leave my husband.
Women to the left
Promise me. Be safe.
and men to the right.
Your government is in the wrong country.
Mama Mama
Mila
You have a blue card.
A blue card doesn't matter anymore.
They are cleaning out the ghetto.
There is not enough room for you.
What are you talking about?
We tried it before.
There's more than enough room.
I changed my mind.
Mama
Oh look at the space in there.
Now look at me. You are just scared.
I can fit the girl but not you.
Mama, I'm coming out.
Stay where you are.
I'd rather you be here than who-knows-where.
Mama
Herr Kommandant
Very good saluting.
I respectfully report,
I've been given orders
to clear the bundles from the road
so there will be
no obstructions to the thoroughfare.
Finish and join the lines, little Polish
clicking soldier.
Mrs. Dresner?
Yes
Oh you are a friend of my son's.
Don't worry.
I'll go quietly. I'll be no trouble.
No. Get under the stairs.
They'll be done
searching soon. You'll be safe there.
Please hide. Please
warmed by the sun.
Hide under the stairs.
I've
searched the building. There's no one here.
So then, let's go to the next block.
Agreed.
- Danka
- Mama
Hello, Adam
Hello, Danka
Come with me.
I will put you in the good line.
Do you know
the saying, "An hour of life is still life?"
You are not
a boy anymore. I'm saying a blessing for you.
Oh please, let's go. Let's go, please.
Come on.
Mark here.
No. Please, sir
we won't find it.
What's that? Is it Bach?
No no. Mozart
- Mozart?
- Yes
Are we going to do that too today?
No. We're never doing that.
I wish this fucking night were over.
Roll call. Rows of five.
Line up.
Stop. Everbody, stop.
Go on. Go on. Rows of five.
Hats off.
Read the names.
Whoever is called will raise his hand
with a clear "yes".
Yes
- Keller, Fanni
- Yes
- Adalbert, Hermann
- Faber, Dorothea
- Yes
- Goldstein, Pola
- Warmberger, Markus
- Yes
Edelstein, Max
Roll call over.
To work.
The worst is over. We are workers now.
Do not pretend to be tired.
Oh God, Amon
Return to the barracks immediately.
Come here a minute. Come on here.
Come now. Come now.
Amon, you're such a damned fucking child.
Wakey wakey
Make coffee.
Make it yourself.
The SS will manage certain industries itself
inside Plaszow:
a metalworks, brush factory
another for reprocessing jewish clothing
from the ghettos
for use by bombed-out families back home.
But it's private industry
like yours that stands to benefit most
by moving inside the wire
of Commandant Amon Goeth's camp.
No no no. Sit sit. Julian, how are you?
Good to see you, my friend.
- Oskar Schindler
- Leo, John
Franz, good to see you.
Hello, Oskar. Glad you could join us.
My pleasure. My pleasure.
- Julius. How are you? Good good.
- You've lost weight.
Only in the shoulders.
Please, everybody, sit down. Sit down.
How are you doing? Oskar Schindler.
We started without you.
Fine. Did I Miss anything good?
I was
explaining to Herr Bosch and Herr Madritsch
some of the benefits
of moving their factories into Plaszow.
I meant the food.
Since your labour is housed on-site
it's available to you at all times.
You can work them all night if you want.
Your factory policies
whatever they've been
in the past, they'll continue to be.
They'll be respected.
I have to know:
Where do you get a suit like that?
What is that? Is that silk?
Of course
Yes
It has a nice sheen about it.
Thank you.
Very nice.
I'd say I'd get you one,
but the man who made it is probably dead.
I don't know.
I go to work the other day.
Nobody's there.
Nobody tells me about this.
I have to find out. I have to go in.
Everybody's gone.
No
They're not gone.
They're here.
They're mine.
Every day that goes by, I'm losing money.
Every worker that is shot costs me money.
I have to find
somebody else. I have to train them.
We are going to be making so much money
that none of this is going to matter.
It's bad business.
Thank you.
Leave the bottle.
Take that.
Lena
thank you.
Scherner told me something else about you.
Yeah? What's that?
That you know the meaning of the word
"gratitude".
...that it's not some vague thing with you
like it is with others.
You want to stay where you are.
You've got things going on the side.
Things are good.
You
don't want anybody telling you what to do.
I can understand all that, you know.
I know you.
What you want
is your own sub-camp.
Do you have any idea what is involved?
The paperwork alone! ...and
then you've got to build the fucking thing.
Getting the fucking
permits is enough to drive you crazy.
Then the engineers show up.
They stand around.
They argue about drainage, foundations
codes, exact specifications
parallel fences four kilometres long
1,200 kilograms of barbed wire
6,000 kilograms
of electrified fences, ceramic insulators
three cubic meters
of air space per prisoner...
I'm telling you, you want to shoot somebody.
I've been through it, you know? I know.
Well, you know. You've been through it.
You could make things easier for me.
I'd be grateful.
Out of the way there.
Keep moving. Keep moving.
Where's Stern?
Goldberg and Chilowicz
make sure I see my cut
from the factory owners in this camp.
I'm
leaving you to take care of my main account:
the Schindler account.
He wants his independence.
I gave it to him.
But independence costs money.
This, you understand?
Look at me.
Don't forget who you are working for now.
Yes, sir
Make sure he stays. He's a slippery bastard.
We need more wine.
More wine.
Stand on my friend. Don't let him leave.
What happens in my life
Cheers cheers
Thank you, Herr Direktor.
Cheers, Herr Direktor
What are you doing?
What? Scratching my head.
It makes them think we have lice.
It helps make them keep their distance.
- Do you have lice?
- Do you have your notebook?
The calendar on my desk has the birthdays
of our SS friends' wives and children.
Don't forget to send something.
Record pay-offs to the Main Administration
and Economics Office, the Arm...
Slowly, Stern. Slowly.
The Armaments Board,
Governor General's Division of the Interior
and Chief of Police as "fees"
and make them on the first of each month
as opposed to
individual pay-offs to our SS contacts.
The list is in
the lower drawer of my desk, which you
"...first of month."
...SS contacts list,
lower drawer of my desk, which you handle
as cash contributions
to legitimate charities
sent, of course, to each official's office.
Dealings with our black market contacts
listed as
"suppliers" in the legitimate ledger
- are more complicated.
- Forget it.
What do you mean,
forget it? You can't forget it.
It
gives me a headache. It gives me a headache.
- I couldn't get you out of here.
- I'll be all right.
Anyway I'm here almost every week:
Wednesdays usually.
I'll look in on you
and see how you're doing.
Here.
Put these in your pocket.
Come on.
Herr Direktor, don't let things fall apart.
I've worked too hard.
Thanks for...
Good luck
Attention. Hats off.
- Work.
- Get to work.
What are you making?
Hinges, sir.
I've got some workers coming in tomorrow.
Where the hell are they from again?
Yugoslavia, Herr Kommandant.
I've got to make room.
Make me a hinge.
Yes, sir
Keep going. You're doing well.
Oh that's very good
but I'm
a bit confused, and perhaps you can help me.
What I don't understand is
that you've been working
since I think... what? about
6:00 this morning?
Yet
such a small pile of hinges.
- Oh Christ
- May I try that, sir?
Check the angle lever. Maybe it's bent.
No no. You wouldn't
hear a click if the angle lever hits the pin.
Maybe
it's the pin. Maybe the pin shaft is greasy.
Yeah, come on.
What did I just say? Here.
Herr Kommandant
I beg to report that my heap of hinges
was so unsatisfactory
because the machines
were being recalibrated this morning.
I was put on to shovelling coal.
Strange, huh?
Yeah
Thank you, Muek.
Ah Lisiek
don't touch
the leather. It's just been oiled.
- Rottenfuhrer
- Oh for me?
Oh thank you very much, Herr Direktor.
Herr Direktor
He was making hinges slowly.
So the man can turn out a hinge in
less than a minute. Why the long story?
Hmm?
Thank you, sir
You're welcome.
Nobody knows who stole the chicken, hmm?
Tell him about the chicken.
A man walks around
with a chicken and nobody notices this.
Save yourselves.
Tell him about the chicken.
Still nobody knows.
It was you.
You committed this crime.
No, sir
But you know who, though.
- Yes
- Who?
Him.
He's very gifted.
Yeah, sure. Bring him over.
Sir
thank you.
Thank you again, Herr Direktor.
You're welcome again.
It's
an honour to work for such a great company.
It's great to have you.
I promise to learn everything
there is to know about enamelware production.
That's great.
Hello?
- Miss Elsa Krause is here.
- I only need five minutes.
She wants to speak to the Herr Direktor.
Yes
He won't see you.
Please, sit down.
Pernod? Cognac?
No. No, thank you.
So what can I do for you?
They say that no one dies here.
They say your factory is a haven.
They say you are good.
Who says that?
Everyone.
My name is Regina Perlman, not Elsa Krause.
I've been living in Krakow
on false papers since the ghetto massacre.
My parents are in Plaszow.
Their names are Chana and Jakob Perlman.
They are older people.
They are killing older people now in Plaszow.
They bury them up in the forest. Look.
I don't have any money.
I borrowed these clothes.
I'm begging you.
Please
Please bring them here.
I don't do that.
You've been misled.
I ask one thing:
whether or not the worker has certain skills.
That's
what I ask and that's what I care about.
My father is an importer, not a metalworker.
Such activities
are illegal. You will not entrap me.
Cry and I will have you arrested
I swear to God.
People die. It's a fact of life.
He wants to kill everybody? Great.
What am I supposed to do about it?
Bring everybody over? Is that what you think?
"Send them
over to Schindler. Send them all."
"His place is a haven,
didn't you know? It's not a factory."
"It's not an enterprise of any kind."
"It's a haven for rabbis and orphans
"and people with no skills whatsoever."
Do you think I don't know what you're doing?
You're so quiet all the time.
I know. I know.
- Are you losing money?
- No. I'm not losing money.
That's not the point.
So the point is...
It's dangerous. It's dangerous to me.
You have to understand.
Goeth is under enormous pressure.
You have to think of it in his situation.
He's got this whole place to run.
He's responsible
for everything here, all these people.
He's got a lot of things to worry about
and he's got the war
which brings out the worst in people
never the good,
always the bad, always the bad
but in normal circumstances
he wouldn't be like this. He'd be all right.
There'd
just be the good aspects of him, which...
He's a wonderful crook
a man who loves good food,
good wine, the ladies, making money
...killing.
He can't enjoy it.
Bejski
told me, the other day somebody escaped
from a work detail outside the wire.
Goeth lined up
everybody from the missing man's barracks.
He shot the man to the left of Bejski
and the man to the right of him.
He walked down the line
shooting every other man with a pistol:
25.
What do you want me to do about it?
Nothing nothing.
We're just talking.
Perlman
husband and wife
Jakob and Chana Perlman
Have Goldberg bring them over.
Hats off.
At ease.
I'm sure
this will be better than those rags, Lisiek.
Herr Direktor,
I was just helping Lisiek to find something
to clean the stains
from the Herr Kommandant's bathtub.
Go and clean it.
Pardon me, Herr Direktor.
You don't have to report to me, Helen.
You know who I am?
Hmm?
I'm Schindler.
Of course. I have heard and
you have been here before.
Here. Why don't you keep this some place?
Go on. Take it.
I get extra food here.
Well, if you don't want to eat it, trade it
or give it to Lisiek.
Why not build yourself up?
My first day here
he beat me
because I threw out the bones from dinner.
He came down
to the basement at midnight and
he asked me where they were:
for his dogs
you understand.
I said to him... I
I don't know how I say this.
I never could say it now. I said to him
"Why are you beating me?"
He said, "The reason I beat you now
"is because you ask why I beat you."
I know your sufferings, Helen.
It doesn't matter.
I have accepted them.
Accepted them?
One day he will shoot me.
No no no. He won't shoot you.
I know.
I see things.
We were on the roof on Monday
young Lisiek and I, and we saw
the Herr Kommandant
come out of the front door and
down the steps
by the patio, right there below us
and there
on the steps he drew his gun and he
shot a woman who was passing by
a woman carrying a bundle
through the throat...
just a woman on her way somewhere, you know?
She was no
fatter or thinner or
slower or faster than anyone else
and I couldn't guess what had she done.
The more you see
of the Herr Kommandant,
the more you see there is no
set rules that you can live by.
You can't say to yourself,
"If I follow these rules, I will be safe."
He won't
shoot you because he enjoys you too much.
He enjoys you
so much, he won't even let you wear the star.
He doesn't want anyone else to know
it's a jew he's enjoying.
He shot the woman from the steps
because she meant nothing to him.
She was one of a series
neither offending or pleasing him
but you, Helen...
It's all right.
It's not that kind of a kiss.
Thank you.
Shh
Here.
Right. The wine.
- A wonderful party, Amon.
- Thank you.
Why do you drink that motor oil?
Hmm? I send you good stuff all the time.
Your liver's
going to explode like a hand grenade.
You know, I look at you.
I watch you.
You're never drunk.
Oh that's
that's real control.
Control is power.
That's power.
Is that why they fear us?
We have the fucking
power to kill, that's why they fear us.
They fear us because
we have the power to kill arbitrarily.
A man
commits a crime. He should know better.
We have him killed
and we feel pretty good about it
or we
kill him ourselves and we feel even better.
That's not power though.
That's justice.
It's different than power.
Power
is when we have every justification to kill
and we don't.
Do you think that's power?
That's what the emperors had.
A man stole something.
He's brought in before the emperor.
He throws himself
down on the ground. He begs for mercy.
He knows he's going to die.
And the emperor
pardons him.
This worthless man
he lets him go.
I think you are drunk.
That's power, Amon.
That is power.
Amon, the Good
I pardon you.
What do they want?
I don't know but
they're in my office now reviewing our books.
As my accountant
tell me:
Should I be alarmed that the auditors
- are reviewing my books?
- Well
...or have you done your job properly?
You needn't be alarmed.
I needn't be alarmed.
I'm sorry, sir.
Do you know how much this saddle is worth?
Do you know how much it costs?
All right.
Stern, what the hell
are you doing following me around?
Barracks 1, 11
15 and 32 to the parade ground.
She was smoking on the job.
Tell her not to do it again.
I have to report, sir:
I've been unable
to remove the stains from your bathtub.
What are you using, Lisiek?
Soap, Commandant.
Soap? Not lye?
Go ahead. Go on. Leave leave. I pardon you.
I pardon you.
Although
I am not a rabbi, in these circumstances
I pray
to the Almighty that he will forgive me
if I intone the blessings.
So
this is where you come to hide from me.
I came to tell you
that you really are a wonderful cook
and a well-trained servant.
I mean it.
If you need a reference after the war
I'd be happy to give you one.
It must get lonely down here
when you're listening
to everyone upstairs having such a good time.
Does it?
You can answer.
"But what's the right answer?"
That's what you're thinking.
What does he want to hear?
The truth
Helen, is always the right answer.
Yes, you're right.
Sometimes we're both lonely.
Yes. I...
I mean
I would like so much to
reach out
and touch you in your loneliness.
What would that be like, I wonder? I mean
What would be wrong with that?
I realize that you're not
a person
in the strictest sense of the word but
No. Maybe
you're right about that too, you know. Maybe
what's wrong isn't
It's not us.
It's... No, it's this.
I mean, when they compare you to
vermin and to rodents and to lice
I just...
No. You make a good point.
You make a very good point.
Is this the face of a rat?
Are these the eyes of a rat?
Hath not a jew eyes?
You will forgive everything
because my love is so sweet.
I feel
for you, Helen.
It's me.
No, I don't think so.
You're a jewish bitch.
You nearly talked me into it, didn't you?
Didn't you?
Bravo
High high high
- Bravo
On behalf of the workers, sir
I wish for you a happy birthday.
Happy birthday
Well, the staff, please
Thank you very much for the lovely cake.
Thank you
very much. Tell them, thank you from me.
The trains arrived
and the people were driven out with clubs.
They were
lined up in front of two big warehouses.
One was marked,
"Cloak Room" and the other "Valuables"
and there they were made to undress.
A jewish boy handed them
pieces of string to tie their shoes together.
They shaved their hair.
They told them it was needed to
make something special for U-boat crews
and then they were
herded down a big corridor
to bunkers with stars of David on the doors
and
signs that said "Bath and Inhalation Room".
The SS gave them soap.
They told them to breathe all the time
because it's good for disinfecting
and then they gassed them.
Mila, why soaps?
So that they would agree to go in, I think.
Come on, Mila. Stop it.
Your bedtime stories are scaring everyone.
Yeah
You know it's ridiculous.
I cannot believe it.
I didn't say
I believed it. I said I heard it.
From who?
From somebody
who heard it from someone who was there.
You know
if they were there
they would have been gassed.
Yes
It doesn't make any sense.
We're their workforce.
What sense
does it make to kill your own workforce?
To go to all this
trouble of assembling a workforce, only to
No. It can't be true.
We are very, very important for them.
Yeah, we do know. Good night
Good night
Good night. Sweet dreams
Attention attention
Everyone who is alive
is to come to the Appellplatz.
Attention, attention
We have to go to the Appellplatz.
Everyone who is alive
The list makers are here.
is to come to the Appellplatz.
There is going to be a selection.
Attention attention.
Everyone who is alive
is to come to the Appellplatz.
Gentlemen
- One
- Two
hundreds of thousands
of Hungarians are coming.
Everyone, line up in a single row.
You could afford to lose some weight, Amon
and you've got to cut down on the cognac.
Morning
What's going on?
It's another semi-annual physical.
There.
Oh I've
got another shipment coming in of
What are they this time?
- Hungarians.
- Yes ...hungarians.
We've got to separate
the sick from the healthy to make room.
Now now
Good night, mother
Good night
This is not allowed
until the evening.
Let me help you.
Quick quick quick
We've got to go out there.
Don't go.
Look alive, Rebeka.
Good night, mother
Run around. Faster faster
Run around. Run around.
Good night
That's my mechanic.
Whose bright idea was it to get rid of him?
Move. Run around.
Hurry hurry. Keep your clothes.
Good night
Open your mouth. Let me see your throat.
Take a deep breath. Yes yes
Lift your arms.
Turn around.
Squat down.
Form a column.
No no no. Wait. Go away. She can work.
Come here. Look.
Separate the sick from the healthy:
those who can work
and those who can't. She can work.
You can work. You can come.
Move. Hurry up.
Those not selected for transport
put your clothes back on.
Go back to the barracks.
Return to the barracks.
Oh my God
Olek? Olek?
Danka?
Olek Olek
Olek?
Danka?
- Danka?
- Olek?
Get into the barracks.
Into the barracks with you.
I didn't see him.
They're hiding.
I'm telling you, they're hiding.
I know Danka. She knows
a good place. She took all of them together.
Back to the barracks.
Find your own hiding place.
There's no room for you here. Go away, quick.
Get out. This is our place. Get out.
Oskar
Amon, gentlemen
why didn't you call me?
I tried to call you. Here, Hujar. Move.
Quite a picnic, huh? Madritsch, Oskar
they're running a little late, you know?
It's taking longer than I thought.
A drink?
Something cold. Bowle.
The Bowle.
Oh another beautiful day!
Silence. Quiet.
Loading of the transport wagons is finished.
We are ready for departure.
Water
Water water
Well done
Oh thank you
What
do you say, we get your fire hoses out here
and hose down the cars? Thank you.
Indulge me.
- Hujar
- Yes, sir
Go and bring the fire hoses.
Where's the fire?
In the windows. That's it, that's it.
On the roof.
That's it.
Good good. In the window, in the window.
Come on. Come on.
That's it. More more.
That's it. That's it. More more.
This is really
cruel, Oskar. You are giving them hope.
You shouldn't do that.
That's cruel.
Come on. Try and reach the far end. Look out.
Water, more water
I've got some 200-meter hoses back in Emalia.
I have 20 meters at home in my garden.
We can reach the cars at the end.
What?
Hujar
Yeah, sure
Don't forget the roof.
On the roof on the other side.
Scharfuhrer
every time the train stops
you open the doors
and you give them water, yeah?
Yes, sir
This car, this car
I'm not saying
you'll regret it but you might.
You should be aware of that.
We will have to risk regret.
All right. Sure. It's a nice day.
I'll go for a drive with you.
What about you?
I violated the Race and Resettlement Act
though I doubt anyone
can point out the actual provision to me.
I kissed a jewish girl.
Did your prick fall off?
He likes women.
He likes good-looking women.
He sees a beautiful woman, he doesn't think.
I mean
he has so many women
and they love him.
Yes, they love him.
I mean, he is married, yes but he's
All right. No.
She was jewish. He shouldn't have done it
but you didn't see this girl.
I saw this girl. This girl was, woof!
She was very good-looking.
They cast a spell on you, you know, the jews.
When you work
closely with them, like I do, you see this.
They have this power. It's like a virus.
Some of my men are infected with this virus.
They should be pitied,
not punished. They should receive treatment.
This is
as real as typhus. I see this all the time.
It's a matter of money?
Hmm?
You're offering me a bribe?
A bribe? No
No, please
It's a gratuity.
Heil Hitler
Hello, Amon
Sit down.
We give you
jewish girls at five marks a day, Oskar.
You should kiss us, not them.
God forbid,
you ever get a real taste for jewish skirt!
There's no future in it.
They don't have a future.
That's not just
good, old-fashioned, jew-hating talk.
It's policy now.
Yes, already caught. Good.
One more, yes, nice
Let's go then. Move.
Faster here. Quick quick quick
Move your ass.
Faster.
Move youselves.
Don't go to sleep.
Only the whole scraps, not the vegetables
Come on. You can do that with your hands.
Take the lead.
Leave the small pieces.
That's how it is: Valhalla.
Valhalla's calling here.
Can you believe this?
As if I don't
have enough to do, they come up with this!
I have to find
every rag buried up here and burn it.
The party's over, Oskar. They're closing
us down, sending everybody to Auschwitz.
When?
I don't know.
As soon as I can arrange the shipments:
maybe 30, 40 days. That ought to be fun.
I've been talking to Goeth.
I know the destination.
These are the evacuation orders.
I'm to help organize the shipments
and put myself on the last train.
That's not what I was going to say.
I made Goeth
promise me, he'll put in a good word for you.
Nothing bad is going to happen to you there.
You'll receive special treatment.
The directives coming in from Berlin
mention
"special treatment" more and more often.
I'd like to think that's not what you mean.
..."preferential treatment", all right?
Do we have to invent a whole new language?
I think so.
You're staying, I take it.
In Krakow? What on Earth for?
What for? You have a business to run.
Of course, you'll
have to hire new workers... Poles, I guess.
They cost a little more, but...
What are you going to do?
You ran my business.
No. I'm going home.
I've done what I came here for.
I've got more money
than any man can spend in a lifetime.
Some day
this is all going to end, you know.
I was going to say, we'll have a drink then.
I think I'd better have it now.
Bible says. And it still is news.
Mama may have. Papa may have.
But God bless the child
That's got his own
That's got his own.
Yes, the strong gets more
While the weak ones fade.
Empty pockets don't ever make the grade.
Mama may have. Papa may have.
But God bless the child
That's got his own
That's got his own.
Money, you've got lots of friends.
They're pounding on your
I don't understand.
You want these people?
"These" people? My people! I want my people.
Who are you? Moses?
Come on. What is this?
Where's the money in this? Where's the scam?
It's good business.
It's good business in your opinion.
Look. You've got to move them
the equipment
everything to Czechoslovakia
pay for all that and build another camp.
- It doesn't make any sense.
- Look, Amon.
- You're not telling me something.
- It's good for me.
I know them. I'm familiar with them.
I don't have to train them.
You're not telling me something.
It's good for you. I'll compensate you.
That's right. It's good for the army.
Yeah, of course.
- Do you know what I'm going to make?
- What?
- Artillery shells.
- Everyone's making artillery shells.
- Tank shells. They need that.
- Tanks shells, yeah.
- Everybody's happy.
- Everyone's happy except me.
You're probably scamming me somehow.
If I'm making 100,
you've got to be making 300
and
if you admit to 300, then it's 400, actually.
But how?
I just told you.
You did but you didn't.
Yeah, all right. Don't tell me.
I'll go along with it.
It's just irritating. I can't work it out.
Look.
All you have to do
is tell me what it's worth to you.
- What's a person worth to you?
- No no no no
What's one worth to you?
Poldek Pfefferberg, Mila Pfefferberg
and
uh Stagel, Stagel...
Paul: Paul Stagel
Doctor
The investors
- I want all of them.
- Yes, sir
Fischer, Ismail Fischer
Fischer, Ismail
Josef Scharf
One moment, sir. I'm sorry, sir.
Come on, Stern. Scharf Scharf
the children, all the children
- Herbert Stier
- Thank you.
How many?
400, 450
More more
- Feigenbaum, Jakob
- Wolf: Wolf Wein
Feigenbaum, Lutek; Jakob... Nacha
- Yes?
- Necha
Necha, that's right.
...and Wolf
How many?
More
You can do the same thing I'm doing.
You might even make money at it.
I don't know.
Come on, Julius. I know about
the extra food and clothes you give them
paid for out of your own pocket.
If we make a combined approach
we could
get more than 4,000 out, mine and yours.
Oskar
We could relocate them
in something like safety, in Moravia.
I don't know.
How many cigarettes have you smoked tonight?
Too many.
For every one
you smoke, I smoke half.
- I've done all I can.
- I will not accept that.
No Oskar. I can't do any more.
I will not accept that.
No
How many? How many?
- 850, give or take
- Give or take what, Stern?
Give or take what? Count them. How many?
That's it.
You can finish that page.
What did Goeth say about this?
You just
told him how many people you needed and...
You're not buying them!
You're buying them?
You're paying him for each of these names?
If you were still working for me
I'd expect you to talk me out of it.
It's costing me a fortune.
Finish the page
and leave one space at the bottom.
You...
The list is an absolute good.
The list is life.
All around its margins lies the gulf.
Oskar, there's a clerical error here
at the bottom of the last page.
No.
There's one more name I want to put there.
I'll never find
a maid as well trained as her at Brinnlitz.
They are all country girls.
No
One hand of 21
- If you win, I pay you 7,400 reichsmarks.
- No
- Hit a natural and I'll make it 14,800.
If I win, the girl goes on my list.
I can't wager Helen in a card game.
Why not?
It wouldn't be right.
She's just going to Auschwitz No. 2 anyway.
- What difference does it make?
- She's not going to Auschwitz.
I'd never do that to her.
No.
I want her to come back to Vienna with me.
I want her to come
to work
for me there. I want to grow old with her.
Are you mad?
Amon
you can't take her to Vienna with you.
No. Of course I can't.
That's what I'd like to do.
What I can do, if I'm any sort of a man
is the next most merciful thing.
I shall take her into the woods and
shoot her painlessly in the back of the head.
What was it you said for a
natural 21?
Was it 14,800?
Schindler jews
to these tables. Say your names clearly.
We are the family Dresner:
Juda, Jonas, Donata, and Chaja.
We are Rosners: Henry, Manci and Leo
- and our son.
- I am Olek.
Maria Mischel
Chaim Nowak
Wulkan, Markus
Michael Lemper
Itzhak Stern
Rebeka and Joseph Bau
- Rosalia Nussbaum
- Wilhelm Nussbaum
Jakob Levartov
- Farber, Rosa
- Farber, Andrzej
Sara
Friehof, Fischel
Mietek Pemper
Poldek and Mila Pfefferberg
Horowitz, Dolek
Adam Levy
Marcel Goldberg
Klipstein, Isak David
Altmann, Eduard
Grunberg, Miriam
Luftig, Eliasz
Hilmann, Eduard
Erna Rothberg
Zuckermann, Jetti
Helen Hirsch
The worst is over.
Men to
this transport and women to this transport.
Be careful.
Men to
this transport and women to this transport.
Watch your step. Men to
Wonderful, Olek
wonderful!
Do you know how we make ice into water?
Olek, get another one.
Everyone, stand in a single row.
You'll be pleased with the level
of efficiency I get from these workers.
Budzyn, under my command
was the envy of every other
commandant in the labour camp system.
- The prisoners, however
- Excuse me.
They would have rather been somewhere else...
The train
with the women has already left Plaszow
and will be arriving here very shortly.
I know you've had a long journey
but it's
only a short walk further to the factory
where hot soup and bread is waiting for you.
Welcome to Brinnlitz.
Beans in cholent?
Beans are the best part.
I don't like beans.
Beans and meat and potatoes and bread
That's not the way you make cholent.
Eggs in cholent?
Yes
I don't like cholent.
No, you don't.
What do you like?
I like caviar.
One day on the fire...
All cars are in position.
Everyone, stay together in the group.
Stay away from the car.
Stay away from the car, I said.
Faster quick quick quick
What's going on here?
Quick
Get out. Quick quick quick. Out.
30, 35, 40, 45...
Get out.
Where are the list makers?
Where are the tables?
Get out.
Hopp hopp
...luggage in wagons
Quick. Get out. Faster.
Leave the luggage in the wagons.
Faster.
Go faster.
Mama, where are we?
They're in Auschwitz.
The train was
never routed here: a paperwork mistake.
Hurry. Fast.
Remove your shoes.
Faster faster
Fold your clothing.
To the shower.
Remove your clothes. Move.
Move.
Stand up and go out.
Undress faster.
Faster.
Undress quickly.
Get soap and towel
and go to the shower for disinfection.
Undress quickly.
Faster.
Take that soap quickly.
Move out faster. Move.
Quickly quickly
Get in immediately. Faster.
Into the shower. Quick.
Faster.
Into the bath. Faster.
Faster faster
Quickly quickly
Come in.
Look down.
Hands on shoulders.
How old are you, mother?
Sixty-eight.
Cough for me, mother.
They say,
to fall against the fence is a kindness.
Don't kill yourself against the fence, Clara.
If you do,
we'll never know what happened to you.
How old are you, mother?
66, sir.
Sir?
Good morning
A mistake has
been made. We are not supposed to be here.
We work for Oskar Schindler.
We are Schindler jews.
Who is Oskar Schindler?
He had a factory in Krakow:
enamelware.
A pot maker.
How old are you, mother?
You are not
the only industrialist who needs labour
Herr Schindler.
I remember,
earlier this year, IG Farben ordered
a trainload of Hungarians
for its chemical factory.
The train came in through the archway
and the officer in charge
of the selection went immediately to work
and sent 2,000 of them
straight away to special treatment.
It is not my task to interfere with
the processes that take place down here.
Why do you think I can help you
if I can't help IG Farben?
Allow me to express the reason.
I'm not making any judgement about you.
It's
just that I know that in the coming months
we're all going to need portable wealth.
I could have you arrested.
I'm protected by powerful friends.
You should know that.
I do not say I am accepting them.
All I say is,
I'm not comfortable with them on the table.
I have a shipment coming in tomorrow.
I'll cut you 300 units from it:
new ones.
These are fresh.
The train comes, we turn it around.
Mmm yes yes
- It's yours.
- I understand.
I want these.
You shouldn't get stuck on names.
That's right.
It creates a lot of paperwork.
Zoldinger, Ernestina
Waldergrun, Hilda
Waldergrun, Leonora
Laast, Anna
Pfefferberg, Mila
Dresner, Horsch
Dresner, Danka
Nussbaum, Sidonia
Rosner, Manci
Hirsch, Helen
Grosz, Chaja Sara
Seelenfreund, Estella
Run faster.
Run faster. Faster.
Faster. Faster. Come on. Forward.
Go on. Go on. Go on. Faster.
Faster. Move.
Scare them. Scare them.
No no no
Girl, let's go now. Now, quickly.
Danka Danka Danka
No no no
Hey hey hey. What are you doing?
These are mine. These
are my workers. They should be on my train.
They're skilled
munitions workers. They're essential
essential girls.
Their fingers
polish the insides of shell metal casings.
How else am I to polish the inside
of a 45 millimetre shell casing?
You tell me. You tell me.
Back on the train.
Under Department W provisions
it is unlawful
to kill a worker without just cause.
Under the Businesses Compensation Fund
I am entitled
to file damage claims for such deaths.
If you shoot without thinking
you go to prison
I get paid.
That's how it works.
So
there will be no summary executions here.
There will be
no interference of any kind with production.
In hopes of ensuring that,
guards will
no longer be allowed on the factory floor
without my authorization.
For your cooperation you have my gratitude.
Come on. Come.
Man! I haven't seen such a thing for years.
Come on, boys. Come.
Look at the men.
No doorman
or maitre d' will ever mistake you again.
I promise.
Itzhak
This is Itzhak Stern, my accountant. Itzhak
You must be Mrs. Schindler.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
Emilie has volunteered to work in the clinic.
- Very generous of you.
- I know.
We need to talk when you have a moment.
This is my wife, Stern.
I don't keep any secrets from my spouse.
Oskar, please, attend
to business. It's much more attractive.
- Madam
- Hello
- What is it?
- We've received an angry complaint
from the Armaments Board.
The artillery shells,
tank shells, rocket casings
apparently all of them
have failed quality control tests.
That's to be expected: start-up problems.
This isn't
pots and pans. This is a precise business.
- I'll write them a letter.
- They're withholding payment.
Sure. So would I. So would you.
I wouldn't worry about it.
We'll get it right one of these days.
There's a rumour, you've been
going around miscalibrating the machines.
They could
shut us down and send us back to Auschwitz.
I'll call around
and find out where we can buy shells
and pass them off as ours.
I don't see the difference
whether they're made here or somewhere else
You
don't see a difference? I see a difference.
You'll lose a lot of money.
Fewer shells will be made.
Stern, if this factory ever produces
a shell that can actually be fired
I'll be very unhappy.
- Hello, madam
- How do you do.
How are you doing, Rabbi?
Rabbi
Good, Herr Direktor
The sun's going down.
Yes, it is.
What day is this?
Friday?
It is Friday, isn't it?
Is it?
What's the matter with you?
You should be preparing for the sabbath
shouldn't you?
I've got some wine
in my office. Come.
What?
Do you have any money
hidden away
some place that I don't know about?
No
Why? Am I broke?
Uh
well...
Yesterday morning
at 2:41 a.m.
at General Eisenhower's headquarters
General Jodl
signed the Act of Unconditional Surrender
of all German
land, sea and air forces in Europe
to the Allied Expeditionary Force
and simultaneously to the Soviet High Command.
The German war is therefore at an end.
But let us not forget for a moment...
I think
it's time, the guards came into the factory.
Japan, with all her treachery...
The unconditional surrender of Germany
has just been announced.
At midnight tonight
the war is over.
Tomorrow
you'll begin the process
of looking for survivors of your families.
In most cases
you won't find them.
After six long years of murder
victims
are being mourned throughout the world.
We've survived.
Many of you
have come up to me and thanked me.
Thank yourselves.
Thank your fearless Stern
and others among you who worried about you
and faced death at every moment.
I'm a member of the Nazi Party.
I'm a munitions manufacturer.
I'm a profiteer of slave labour.
I am
a criminal.
At midnight
you'll be free and I'll be hunted.
I shall remain
with you until five minutes after midnight
after which time,
and I hope you'll forgive me
I have to flee.
I know
you have received orders from our commandant
which he has received from his superiors
to dispose of the population of this camp.
Now would be the time to do it.
Here they are. They're all here.
This is your opportunity.
Or you could leave
and return to your families as men
instead of murderers.
In memory
of the countless victims among your people
I ask us to observe three minutes of silence.
Thank you, Mr. Jereth.
Open wide.
As soon as peace occurs, I want
I want that cloth distributed to the workers:
2 meters each.
Also,
each person is to get a bottle of vodka.
They won't drink it. They know its value.
Likewise
those Egipshi cigarettes we organized.
It'll be done, everything you ask.
We've written a letter
trying to explain things
in case you are captured.
Every worker has signed it.
Thank you.
It is Hebrew, from the Talmud.
It says, "Whoever
saves one life, saves the world entire."
I could have got more out.
I could have got more.
I don't know.
If I'd just...
I could have got more.
Oskar, there are 1,100 people
who are alive because of you. Look at them.
If I'd made more money...
I threw away so much money.
You have no idea.
If I had just...
There will be
generations because of what you did.
I didn't do enough.
You did so much.
This car:
Goeth would have bought this car.
Why did I keep the car?
10 people right there
10 people
10 more people.
This pin:
2 people.
This is gold:
2 more people.
He
would have given me 2 for it. At least one.
He would have given me one, one more
one more person
a person, Stern
for this.
I could have gotten
one more person
and I didn't
and I didn't.
You have been liberated
by the Soviet Army.
Have you been in Poland?
I just came from Poland.
Are there any jews left?
Where should we go?
Don't go east. That's for sure.
They hate you there.
I wouldn't go west either, if I were you.
We could use some food.
Isn't that a town over there?
Heil Hitler