Left, right, left, left, left...
Over here.
Everybody out of the truck.
Over to the ammo dump.
Get the hell going in a hurry.
Casper, come on with me.
Hey, Fred, can you help me
get this stuff unloaded?
Get that damn thing up here.
I read they're looking for
professionals in Africa.
What – whores?
No, mercenaries, sarge.
Mexico and Latin America, too.
Mercs are getting 1300 a month
plus transportation.
They want combat soldiers,
Casper, not typists.
I was told to report to you, sergeant.
I'm Hardin.
Rifleman Charles Hardin, Corporal.
Where're you from, Charlie?
El Paso.
Is that right? Tell me how
you like being
in the Louisiana National Guard
all of a sudden.
I don't.
But then I didn't much like being
in the Texas Guard either.
Well, not liking the Texas Guard
makes sense.
Not liking the Louisiana Guard
can get you into trouble with me.
You got that?
Got it.
You get your butt on over to
2nd squad – you'll recon with them.
Casper, show him the way.
Introduce him to the boys.
Right.
Cease fire!
We sure get all the good details
around here.
It'll be good exercise for you, Simms.
Put a little muscle in your pants.
It's the last thing I need, coach.
Unless you want to take care of it?
Listen, Stuckey.
Maybe I'll just bend you in half
so you can take care of it yourself.
Easy, big fella!
Listen, Stuckey. I like a joke just like
anybody, but I don't like that one.
- Come on, now.
- Ah! I'm with you coach.
Speaking for myself, I like women.
Yeah, we won't be seeing
many of them.
- Life's full of surprises.
- What does that mean?
I've arranged for a little treat
for the weekend, boys.
Six whores de combat
awaiting our assault.
I'm sure they'll fuck us
in a more interesting way
than the Louisiana National Guard.
- You ain't kidding, right?
- I never joke about women.
Women? What women?
Got some hookers at the end
of the line, coach.
- You mean prostitutes?
- Exactly what I mean.
This is new low, Spencer,
even for you.
I got 'em scheduled to meet us
just outside of Catahoula.
Gotta be there about the time
we emerge from the...
great primordial swamp.
- Got one for me?
- Me?
You mean us, don't you, brother?
What's happening here?
The purpose of the National Guard
is to keep you darker brothers away
from decent Southern women.
- Man!
- However...
in the spirit of the New South,
I have made full arrangements.
What about you, Hardin?
I got a wife. You can count me out
of this one.
I suppose you're used to a more
serious soldiering over in El Paso?
We had things organized over there.
Watch a ball game on TV,
shoot dice and sleep.
Louisiana Guard is a little different.
They have us out doing really
important things like...
beating up on college kids and
tear gassing niggers.
Please, Mr. Guardsman,
no more canisters.
Don't set the shepherd dogs on me.
See what I mean?
We have a long, noble
military tradition.
- Hey, Casper!
- Huh?
Cut it out, Stuckey. Act like a soldier,
you damn dumb son of a bitch.
In the real world do you do
something useful
or are you like the rest of the men
in the 2nd squad?
I work for Petramco.
Chemical engineer.
College man.
They're kind of rare in Texas,
aren't they?
Oh, we manage to come up with
one every now and then.
You know, one might get
the impression
you don't enjoy an occasional chat
with your fellow guardsmen.
Guess what? You're right.
I can't say as I blame you
here and there.
Reece is under the impression most
of the time that he's in a dime novel
and Stuckey...
He isn't smart enough
to read a dime novel.
- The coach, well...
- Yeah, I think I know the type.
Look, these guys are OK.
They just wanna have a little fun
with you being the new boy an' all.
They're not OK. They're just
Louisiana versions
of the same dumb rednecks
I've been around my whole life.
Hup! Hup, two, three, four!
Come on boys!
When I was training in Fort Polk
once our instructor got bit...
right here, by a coral snake.
Just put his hand on a log and took
his machete out and just...
cut it right off, took it right off.
- Horseshit!
- Bullshit!
I swear it's the truth. Just fuck you!
I don't give a shit. Believe it or not.
For those of you who are interested,
we are going on an overnight
recon and patrol.
Hush up and listen up!
We've been designated Bravo, that
is Bravo Team, recon and security.
Rendezvous point Charlie, that is
Charlie, is just outside Catahoula.
We're gonna travel in file formation
with maximum use of cover
and concealment.
We are traveling to make time.
No tents, no sleeping bags.
Ponchos and liners only.
We're gonna have all kinds
of weather out there.
Sun, rain, cold in the morning.
Get used to this idea –
you're going in the water
and that water's going to be cold.
Cribbs!
You with us?
Oh, sure I am, sarge.
I'm really up for this.
Well, that's good 'cuz you're going to
be my pace man.
Reece, you'll be point.
Yo!
We're talking about 38km.
You make sure your canteens are
filled at the water buffalo.
Each and every member
does their job.
I don't want nobody
dogging it out there.
You're all buddies. You're counting
and depending on each other.
Everybody does their job.
Now please, for once in your life,
try to look like soldiers.
Civilian in peace, soldier in war.
I am the Guard.
That's right. Try to remember that.
Looks like somebody built
a whole new ocean here.
We are supposed to be
at this coordinate.
Either this map is wrong
or all of a sudden I can't find my way
around the block.
The channel must have shifted
with the winter rains.
What's supposed to be land
is underwater.
- D'you want me to raise company?
- No, there's no need for that.
It's real simple. Either we can get
across going down this point of land
and it don't look good,
we go all the way back
and start over.
Over here!
Damn!
Somebody shot Rudolph.
Who do you think these canoes
belong to?
Us.
They belong to indigenous
personnel.
Don't you be fucking
around with them.
Think they float?
Hell yes. They're pirogues. Cajuns
back there use them all the time.
Well, they ain't using them now.
What say we take 'em down
the bayou?
Yeah, I can deal with that,
the way my back feels.
We might make Catahoula tonight.
Put them women under martial law.
What women you talking about?
Spencer's running some ladies.
He's got some skirts waiting for us.
It's all set. Noleen and
her bayou queens.
Just a little something for morale.
Really?
Let me add, sergeant, that these
women are expecting some...
small unit military penetration.
I don't think we should take
the canoes. They're not ours.
That's right, they're not ours.
Let's get in 'em and take off.
Hold on, fungo.
Nobody gave you an order.
How else are we gonna get there?
Maybe you got a point there, Reece.
Hell yes, let's move.
Wait a minute, Reece.
How are the rightful owners
gonna get those boats back
when there's no other access
to the far shore?
Hell, we only need three of them.
They can use the other ones
to get 'em back.
A little R & R never hurts.
Catahoula, here we come.
What d'you say, sarge?
OK. Bowden, write 'em a note.
- Yes, sir.
All right, get those steel pots off,
hook 'em on your belts.
Shape up now.
Shape up, Stuckey.
Get in the goddamn boat
and look like soldiers.
Come on, Bowden.
Get that oar.
Hey! Look over there.
There they are.
These must be their canoes.
Hey there, you men! Read the note!
We left you a note.
Dumb coon asses.
They don't understand.
I hope they find my note.
Maybe they only speak French.
Well, does anybody speak French?
Yeah. Voulez-vous fuck me?
Reece, knock that shit off.
We're bringing them back.
Let 'em have it.
Take no prisoners.
Stuckey! Asshole!
Casper, get your boat over
to that point of land now.
Sarge!
Poole! Poole!
Get outta here.
Get outta here, Bowden.
What the fuck?
Hit it! Take cover.
They shot him! They shot him!
Spencer, over here. Over this way.
Jesus Christ, what's happenin'?
Are they still shooting?
Where are they?
I don't know. I can't see 'em.
Hey, get down, man.
Poole. We gotta get Poole.
You take care of it. I'm gonna go
over there and look out for 'em.
Come on.
Come on, let's go.
He fell over there.
Let's set him down.
Goddamn you, Stuckey.
Over here, come on.
Come on, watch out.
No sign of them.
Where the hell's that damn map?
He was holding it. I remember.
Damn! Compass is gone.
How'd that happen?
It was in the water.
What the hell d'you think?
And guess who put it there.
That's right, Bowden. What the hell
d'you tip us over for?
Didn't tip the canoes over.
You started it. It's your fault.
The hell you talkin' about?
You fucking panicked, you asshole!
I'll show you panic,
you little fucking redneck.
I didn't panic.
I didn't panic, you piss-ass!
What the hell is this shit?
Look, we're all soldiering together.
Damn it. You two guys shake hands.
All right.
OK.
OK, good.
Simms, where's your radio?
In the water. Where d'you think?
You're supposed to be
in charge of it.
What the hell's the matter
with you?
Look, we have a dead man here.
Now what are we gonna do?
Let's go get them cocksuckers
who shot Poole.
I'll decide where we're going
and when.
Let's haul ass.
What about Sergeant Poole?
I say we leave him
unless you wanna carry him.
He's an American soldier.
He's got a Bronze Star, a Purple
Heart, a Vietnam Service Medal.
We're not leaving him here.
The quicker we get outta here, the
quicker they can come back for him.
We're gonna follow through with our
mission. That's our responsibility.
Come on, Casper. Let's get going.
No, goddamnit!
We're not leaving him here.
- Who says?
- I say,
I've got the stripes, I'm in charge
and I don't wanna hear
any more shit about it.
Now, let's just go.
Stuckey, you were one dumb son of
a bitch firing that machine gun.
Yeah, Stuckey.
Nobody gave you an order to fire.
Look, it was only a goddamn joke.
They were only blanks.
Forget it.
Forget it'? Shit! This moron gets
somebody killed – you say forget it?
I got something for you boys
to remember.
Stuckey wasn't the one
that shot Poole.
The big thing is that after we get
Poole back to headquarters
we come back and
get these Cajuns.
Oh hell yes! All we got to do is
swim a couple a hundred yards
and then find 'em back in that forest.
After we done that we can capture
'em and shoot 'em with our blanks.
Well, what d'you think?
This bayou forks to the east.
Easiest to get where we want
moving that way.
We want to be heading north.
The interstate's north.
We're going to the interstate.
Not if you go east.
The interstate's north.
Fuck you, Spencer.
What the fuck you know?
I know there's a big fireball in the
sky that usually rises in the east
and we're walking right into it.
- You gotta go east to go north.
- Yeah, right.
Who wants to run that by me one
more time? We got to go where?
Can somebody figure out where
the hell we're goin' and do it quick?
Hardin, shut up.
It's my responsibility and
we're goin' east to get north.
Go ahead and do
what you want, zip.
Exactly what the hell
I'm gonna do, Spencer.
Now let's move your asses.
Come on.
Turkey.
Turkey meat, turkey skin,
cracker meal, turkey fat, salt.
Smokes made it through
the water, huh?
Yeah, I saved a pack. Lucky, huh?
Maybe it's about time
we divide up the bullets.
- What bullets?
- Reece has got some ammo.
He always brings some along just
in case he runs into any big game.
Back at bivouac he was showing off
a box full of 556s.
Hey, what the hell is this
anyway, man?
Some kind of military secret
or something?
No way.
I brought along one box of shells
for my own use.
Right now I'm locked and
loaded down
in case I meet up with them
sons of bitches that shot Poole.
Let me see your weapon, Reece.
You just stay on back.
You give me the ammo. We're going
to divide them up evenly.
- We'll share 'em.
- Bullshit.
It's mine and that's it.
It's not right, Reece. Give him
the bullets. It's a military situation.
I'm giving you a direct order, Reece.
You give them to me.
You come one step closer, Casper,
and I'll give you something else.
It's a court martial offense, man.
If you give me the ammo
we'll drop it right here.
Otherwise I'm going to
turn your ass in.
I don't give a shit what you s...
Quit fucking around and
give him your rifle.
Now.
I'll take Hardin's and
give them to him.
Here's your ammo.
Blade to the throat, huh?
That how they do
these things in El Paso?
Yeah. That's how they do things
where I grew up.
Thought you were some kind
of chemical engineer.
I am and I'm out of the habit of
spending time
with a bunch of gun-toting rednecks.
Well, you know how it is.
Down here in Louisiana when we
don't carry guns we carry ropes.
RC Colas, MoonPies. We're not too
smart but we have a real good time.
What're you doin', Cribbs?
Say, man, I'm on sentry.
You wanna get some of this stuff?
How can you smoke that crap?
I ain't on your team, coach.
Goddamn right, you're not.
You couldn't make the squad.
That stuff kills your will to win.
How your boys do this year?
This was a rebuilding year.
We had injuries to key personnel.
We finished three and seven.
What do you do for a living anyway?
I pick up a little cash
pimping here and there
but most of what I turn over is from
selling dope to high school kids.
You're goddamn lucky
I don't believe you.
No, it's true.
Some of my best customers
are at Fremont High
and they were ten and 0 this year.
Coach.
I don't have to listen to this bullshit.
- Hey, Lonnie.
- Huh.
When are we going to kick his boy's
ass all the way back to El Paso?
Soon as we get up
to the rendezvous
then we're going to come back for
these coon asses that got Poole.
Lonnie...
Do you think this whole thing
was my fault?
Don't worry about it.
It's done.
Hey!
How can you guys play cards
with Sergeant Poole lying dead
over there?
You got another idea about
what we should be doing?
Just don't seem right.
Poole doesn't care – he's dead.
I don't know what the hell any of us
can do about it
so why not play cards?
Just don't seem right.
- It's up this way.
- Where?
- Over there.
- OK, come on, keep moving.
Hey, Spencer, what about
Company Command?
They should be wondering about us,
don't you think?
No, not yet.
We've been out of contact
for 12 hours.
He's right. They should be looking
for us by now.
No way. It's National Guard,
remember?
We were supposed to meet
the trucks 20 minutes ago.
Another hour and a half
the trucks will actually show up.
Two o'clock they'll start asking
around if anyone's seen us.
At three they'll start checking
the bars.
By four they'll really get steamed.
By five it'll occur to someone
that maybe we got lost.
At six the captain will consider
calling Battalion.
At seven-thirty he will.
Battalion will tell him it's too late –
there's nothing anyone can do
till morning.
There's the cabin.
It's him, that son of a bitch.
Where's the others?
There's more of them.
As far as I can tell he's alone.
- We'll capture him.
- What for? I can get him from here.
Look, Reece,
this is Louisiana National Guard,
not the goddamn vigilantes.
Let's move our asses.
Come on, let's go.
All right, look.
Here's the program.
We found one of the Cajuns
that shot Poole.
We're gonna capture him.
He's up about 250 meters up ahead.
You sure he's one of them?
Of course we're sure.
What the hell do you think?
Why don't you try talking to him
before you start blowing
his head off?
Simms, Reece, Stuckey and I
are the advance unit.
The initial action's
gotta be decisive.
- Surprise is the key.
- Hey, Casper.
- Did you hear what I said?
- I heard you.
We'll talk to him after
we've captured him.
The rest of you guys are
rear element,
you stay 100 meters back
and keep down.
We'll marry up after the objective's
sealed off. Let's go.
Wait. I'll volunteer for
the advance party.
Forget it. Just do what the hell
you're told. Let's go.
Jesus! This is bullshit.
That's just what I was thinking.
Do you always get out
of everything?
I don't see you raising your hand
to volunteer.
That's right.
I'm not gonna ride shotgun
with these dumbbells.
Four of them with automatic rifles
against some swamp rat.
I make it even money.
What are you doing, coach?
Shut up.
Whoa!
What in the hell...? Let's go.
Son of a bitch!
You're under arrest.
Bowden, get the hell away
from that prisoner.
I told you to stay in our back.
- Mission accomplished, sergeant.
- Ah, bullshit!
You used your real bullets.
Just pissed them away.
- I didn't panic.
- Oh hell!
All right. Easy now.
We've got to interrogate him.
- Hey! (Speaks French)
- Surrender.
- Drop the knife.
- (Speaks French)
You son of a bitch.
I said drop the goddamn knife.
(Speaks French)
Son of a bitch! You could have
busted his jaw.
- That's right.
- We want him to talk.
You almost knocked his mouth
down to his ass.
Jesus Christ, Simms.
We gotta interrogate the man.
How the hell's he going to talk to us
if you break his fucking jaw?
- That's his fucking problem.
- What the hell did you do that for?
That son of a bitch shot
Sergeant Poole.
Oh fuck him. Come on, Lonnie.
Let's go see what's inside.
Can you talk?
Ma bouche.
Where's your buddies?
How many of them are there?
Mange-merde.
What the shit is that?
This Cajun got himself a couple
of mink this morning.
Goddamn!
This boy's a poacher.
We poached the poachers!
Hey, Lonnie!
Yeah, he shined his last gator.
What the hell's going on here,
Casper?
We got ourselves a prisoner.
Congratulations.
Think you guys have done
a wonderful job.
Hey, did you have to
cut his arm off too?
I'd say he uses dynamite to kill fish.
We got us a genuine outlaw.
Casper! All kinds of good shit
in here.
Simms, I don't want you
hitting him again.
You're the one that belted him?
Goddamn right.
What d'you want to go and
do that for?
I don't know.
Just got pissed.
What the hell, man? This army
bullshit is getting to you.
Beans, hominy, spinach.
Hell, this is better than C-rations.
Guns, knives, ammo, supplies.
We got it all right here.
I'd say we conducted ourselves
a pretty successful little raid.
We can pack this shit up later.
Let's get outside and
interrogate the prisoner.
Cribbs.
- Yeah.
- Tie up the prisoner.
How am I supposed to tie up a man
when he only has one arm
to do the tying?
Maybe we ought to try
talking to him first.
You speak English?
Does anybody here speak French?
Bowden?
Yeah.
Hey, what's wrong with you, coach?
Don't bother me.
Not now, not ever.
I'll give it a try. A couple of years of
parlez-vous in high school.
Ah...
Hier quelqu'un...
Shit! I can't remember
how to say "shoot".
How about "bang bang"?
Hier, quelqu'un...
Bang une ami.
Mon pas fait rien. Mon dis toil
I think he's saying
he didn't do anything.
Hell, I don't know. It doesn't sound
like any French I ever studied.
What the hell is this? I saw him.
I was there too and
I couldn't swear to nothing.
Can't even remember
if the man had one arm.
He was more than 100 yards away,
remember.
We're gonna take this prisoner
back with us
to Staff Command for interrogation.
Then he can stand trial.
Right now I want everybody over to
the rain barrel, fill your canteens.
I want to put some miles
between us and here.
Lonnie!
Bowden, you dummy.
There's dynamite in there.
- Christ!
- Hit it!
- Get down!
- Take cover!
That'll teach them to fuck with us.
Yeah, right. Can't argue with that.
What are you doing, Bowden?
Went and blew the shit
out of everything.
Well, I do what I do.
What d'you paint the cross
on your chest for?
It's part of the joke.
What joke?
It's a corporal joke, private.
Oh, what the hell, Bowden.
You dumb son of a bitch. You blown
up all the supplies we've captured.
All the guns, the ammo
and the food.
Casper, there comes a time
you have to abandon principles
and do what's right.
Maybe we'd better find
the interstate.
Let's get going, Casper.
I think your little raid's
about finished.
Yeah, right. All right, men.
Let's move out.
Get on!
That dumb shit Bowden.
Demolitioned that damn shack,
we lost everything we captured.
Yeah, could have worked as a signal
for this bastard's relatives
to gather round.
You don't think we've got to worry
about these coon asses, do you?
Hell yeah.
But I know who's got to worry
about a lot more than me and you.
You don't have to tell me.
They think you boys are bad luck.
They might be right.
I been hanging round niggers my
whole life, I haven't got a break yet.
Listen, fellas.
I'm sorry about that incident
back there.
Guess I was a little...
over emotional.
Yeah, you could say that.
You could also say you were
totally out of control.
I'm sorry, but I admired
Sergeant Poole a great deal.
I liked him a lot.
I hope that that'll excuse my...
excessive behavior.
Sure.
Say, coach?
At the risk of a punch in the mouth...
Don't worry about that, Hardin.
Why d'you paint the cross
on your chest?
You know the avenging angel
and all that?
I thought at least you might
get it, Spencer.
Sorry to disappoint you, coach.
If you'll excuse me, I think I should
apologize to the rest of the men.
I got news for you.
He's nuts.
I mean really fuckin' nuts.
This is not exactly news
to the rest of us.
Is that all you've got to say?
After that whole number he pulled
back there?
What am I supposed to say?
He's a dumb son of a bitch.
He's real emotional,
he got pissed off.
He got pissed off.
So he paints himself red,
laughs like a fucking maniac
and blows off like a volcano.
What if he is crazy?
What do you want me
to do about it?
Put him in a cage? Shoot him?
Either one sounds OK to me.
Any chance we're ever going to
get outta here?
You damn right we are.
Figure two hours tops
we hit the I-10.
Jesus!
What the hell's this supposed
to mean?
Don't mean nothin'.
Just some dude drying the skins.
It's a funny way of
stretching the skin.
You sure they weren't left for us?
There's eight of them.
So what?
There's eight of us.
What about this shit? Hmm?
You know what it means?
Lapin.
Come on, let's keep going.
Wouldn't do any good here
no matter why they were left.
Goddamn it, Casper,
where's the highway?
It's been hours.
It'll be right up ahead here.
It can't be too far.
Yeah, right. Used to run right
through here.
Those ecology boys must have
moved it.
Oh, fuck you, Spencer.
All right, hold up.
Everybody take five.
We'll go get a bearing.
With what? We don't have
a compass, remember?
You hear of taking a reading
off the sun, Spencer?
Sure. Rises in the east,
sets in the west.
Interstate's north. If you ask me,
that's not where we're headed
so why don't you go read
the sun, Casper?
That's exactly what I'm
gonna do, thanks.
Say, man, this cat know
what he doin'?
What do you think?
Then why the hell are we
following him?
He's got stripes. That's why.
Some of you boys outta remember
that this is a military operation.
Coming from you, Reece,
that's real classic.
Hey...
What the hell was that?
Dogs, man. What d'you think?
It's hunting dogs.
Hunting dogs mean hunters.
They can show us
the way outta here.
Getting close.
Yeah. Great!
Hey, Casper!
We got some huntin' boys nearby.
They can show us the way
outta here, Casper.
They can show us the way out.
Lonnie!
Agh!
Lonnie.
Goddamn!
Agh!
Son of a bitch!
Goddamn.
Goddamn, he got me.
- Agh! My arm!
- Goddamn bastards!
- Cribbs, you all right?
- He got my arm.
- Hardin! How bad is he? OK?
- I think so. Shit!
- Spencer?
- Yeah.
- Reece?
- Sons of bitches!
Goddamn sick setting
their goddamn dogs on us.
How can they do that? They set their
goddamn dogs on us.
- Reece, Lonnie, knock it off.
- Hey, they weren't his dogs.
Whose side are you on anyway?
I ain't on yours, Reece, that's for...
Knock it off! All of you, knock it off.
It's just what the enemy wants –
a fight among ourselves.
Now damn it, everybody just take
five and pull yourselves together.
And you go cool off.
- Come on, man.
- Come on.
Spencer?
Yeah.
I wanna know what the fuck's
going on here.
I don't get you.
Well, I'll make it real simple.
My company transfers me
to Baton Rouge,
been down here about six months.
I don't know a goddamn thing about
the swamps of Louisiana.
I get sent on some bullshit military
exercise, and all of a sudden,
guys start coming at us from
out of the fuckin' trees. Now...
I'll ask you again.
What the hell is going on here?
I'll tell you something.
I'm just a city boy.
What's going on here?
I haven't the slightest fucking idea.
Except we ran into some people
that are real weird
and I think maybe
they're trying to kill us.
Because some asshole fired blanks
out of his damn machine gun.
Yeah.
Because a bunch of assholes
stole some boats.
Yeah.
Hey, Casper!
He's getting heavy.
It can't be too much further.
Why don't we leave him
and come back?
No. I told you before.
It's cold as a witch's tit and
this son of a bitch weighs a ton.
I don't wanna hear you
calling Poole that.
- He can't hear me.
- Well, I can.
Shit, Casper, the cock-sucker's
dead. I'm just talking about the body.
Goddamnit, Reece. I told you I didn't
want to hear you calling him that.
Watch out.
What?
What you almost stepped in.
Jesus Christ!
Look at them bastards.
It's like a steel pussy.
Hell, man. What kind of women
you been hangin' out with?
All laid out. Seven of them.
Like the rabbits.
There were eight rabbits.
Then how come there's only
seven of these?
Did we lose anybody?
They were set for us?
Either us or the last seven bears
in the state of Louisiana.
Hey.
Quest-ce que c'est que ça?
What did you ask him?
I asked him what
they were doing there.
You son of a bitch.
Are there any more? Huh?
- I'm talking to you.
- All right.
Reece, cut it out.
Come on, knock it off.
Now, look. They didn't get us
and they're not gonna.
Let's settle that we've wasted
enough time.
The interstate ain't that far away.
Now, let's move out.
Cribbs, you take point.
Come on, Tyrone.
Damn, Casper.
I don't see why I'm point.
I don't know where the highway is
and I know it. You're always talking
about, you know.
Why don't you come up here
and be point?
No unnecessary noise
and no talking in formation.
Agh!
Cribbs!
Jesus Christ, Cribbs!
Our Father, who art in Heaven,
Hallowed be Thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done
On earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread.
Forgive us our trespasses...
...as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
Lead us not into temptation
But deliver us from evil.
For Thine is the kingdom,
the p...
For Thine is the kingdom...
And the power and the glory.
Forever, Amen.
We give this prayer as dead men
asking for our salvation.
I don't wanna hear any more
of that kind of talk.
Now, we're at war and
that's all there is to it.
I want you men to start looking like
soldiers and not like mailmen.
Weapons carried at the ready.
We've only got about a half-hour
of daylight left
so this is it – we'll bivouac here.
A clearing this big will make it tough
for those bastards to come
sneak up on us.
Right. Hey, Casper.
Wait a second.
Talk a few things over, huh?
Tomorrow morning the helicopters'll
be out looking for us.
Damn good chance they'll find us
if we stay on clear ground like this.
So all we have to worry about until
then is the Cajuns, right?
We don't know the enemies'
strength or his disposition.
And while he may have the
advantage of familiar terrain,
we have the advantage
of military training.
That's a terrific speech, Casper.
But I want to improve
our odds a little bit.
What are you going after, Spencer?
Maybe they want this trapper back.
Maybe he's all they want.
Let's take the chance and let him go.
That man killed Poole.
The only place he's going is with us.
We don't know that he killed Poole.
He's just the first Cajun we ran into
after it happened.
Hey, Spencer.
You know they're fixing to kill us all.
You got it.
Look, I'm tired of hearing
about all this.
Reece, you and Stuckey gag
the prisoner and tie him to a tree.
Simms, go on sentry.
Casper, you're a dumb asshole.
Now, you listen to me, Spencer,
and you listen real good.
Tomorrow morning we're heading
north with the prisoner.
The man who killed Crawford Poole,
the man whose buddies killed
Tyrone Cribbs.
In case you've forgotten, Spencer,
they were friends of ours.
Now, let's all get unpacked
and bedded down.
No fire tonight.
You all right?
Yeah, I'm OK.
You know, you might be right
about the trapper.
Why the hell didn't you
say anything?
Maybe I can't believe any of this shit,
that's why.
Oh. Well, let me know
when you start.
Look, the problem ain't what the hell
I believe in or don't believe in.
What is?
How long we're gonna follow
this dumb bastard, Casper.
Looks to me like he's leading us
round in circles.
And?
Maybe we need a new leader.
You volunteering for the job?
I'm the new boy, remember?
You know these guys.
It's your move.
Besides, I'm not
the volunteering type.
You're terrific, Hardin.
You don't want to volunteer
for yourself
but you don't mind at all volunteering
me for the court martial.
Fuck you.
I got something to tell you, Casper.
- Fragmentation.
- What?
Remember your training.
I'm making a grenade here.
Even blank rounds can save
your life if you improvise.
Damn it, Casper, don't give me
this crap. This is important.
It's Bowden.
There's something wrong with him.
He won't talk.
Spencer says he's just gone
totally crazy.
You'd better come on over.
I think he's right.
Come on.
Hey look, Bowden. I know it's been
kinda rough on all of us.
I can understand you're not
feeling too good.
Why don't you talk to us about it?
Come on, Bowden.
Bowden, I'm giving you an order.
Now, damn it, talk to us.
Hell, I don't know.
I do.
The motherfucker's crazy.
Well, what we gonna do with him?
Just leave him there.
Maybe he'll be better in the morning.
The hell we are.
This guy made his own bomb,
remember. You gonna tie him up.
Yeah, we don't want him walking
around when we're sleeping.
He's way too big and dangerous.
- Use your head, Casper.
- He's right.
He is, Casper. What the hell?
Won't hurt none to tie him up.
Ain't no good to us anyhow.
Never was, as far as that goes.
If he's tied up we lose
potential fire power.
Jesus Christ, Casper.
Get a goddamn rope and
quit jerking off about fire power.
Remember what happened the last
time you mouthed off to me?
Bullshit, Casper!
This ain't a goddamn game.
All right, there's 40 feet of rope
in my pack.
Go get it, Simms.
What the hell are you doin', Reece?
This man's gonna talk to me.
Let him up.
You stay out of this.
I said let him up.
Sure.
Now are you happy?
That's the second time
you asked for it with me.
This time you're going to get
an answer.
About time I paid you off, cowboy.
How about I blow
your fuckin' head off, Reece?
You ain't got the balls.
OK, you got it.
(Speaks French)
Tuez!
Kill him!
He's dead.
Reece is dead.
Looks like your prisoner got away,
Casper.
Lonnie!
- Come on!
- Let me go!
Goddamnit! Let me go!
I'm gonna get you,
you son of a bitch.
You hear me? I'm gonna get you.
How many more graves are
we gonna be leaving back here?
No more of ours, I can tell you that.
Yeah? You can tell me that.
Shut up.
You talking to me?
I'm talking to everybody
including you.
Keep your mouth shut
and dig the grave.
Why don't you dig it?
You're the one that killed him.
I'm not going to tell you again.
Keep your fucking mouth shut,
and dig the goddamn grave.
I don't want any more shit
out of you either.
Look, just do what
the hell he says – dig.
We've had three casualties.
We're not going to have any more.
Survival is a mental outlook.
If you're not prepared mentally
to overcome all obstacles
and hardships,
the chances of you
coming out alive...
...are greatly reduced.
We're getting tired of listening
to all this, Casper.
Goddamn you, Spencer,
I'm trying to do my best.
I know you are, Casper, but quoting
the manual to us isn't helping much.
You think you could do any better?
Yeah, I do.
But I'm the team leader.
You're not even a corporal
You're just a PFC.
Hey!
I'm getting tired of this damn crap.
I'm with you, Spencer.
Casper, you ain't never going to find
that fuckin' highway.
Casper, you promise me
that this Texas asshole's
going to be court-martialed?
He's got to be.
He killed a fellow soldier.
Then I'm with you.
Hardin?
What's this voting bullshit?
Let's get movin'.
Come on, Bowden. Let's go home.
Spencer, you just can't
walk off like this.
We're a squad, a unit.
We're Bravo Team.
You guys are deserting.
You bet your ass we are.
You coming?
Come on, Stuckey. Let's go.
How's your arm?
It'll be all right.
Look, for what it's worth...
I know Reece was a real
son of a bitch.
I don't wanna talk about him.
Yeah, well,
maybe it was self defense.
Look, let's just drop it.
It's over with.
Right.
Hey, Spencer.
What chance do we got?
You're always so smart
about everything.
Now you're the leader
so give me an answer.
Right now they got state troopers,
helicopters, hound dogs,
everybody in Louisiana
looking for us.
Spencer, I've had it with
them hound dogs.
Tell you something else.
Who's ever looking for us,
they better make it quick.
Hey!
Come on!
Simms! What the fuck is going on?
- I thought I saw something.
- Where?
Over there.
Are you sure? I didn't hear anything.
Me neither.
Didn't you hear it?
You musta heard it.
I didn't hear nothing.
You wasted your bullets
just like Bowden did.
Well, there's nothing now.
What the fuck?
Come on. Let's take off.
Motherfuckers!
Simms!
No more!
- Christ!
- They dug 'em up.
They dug 'em all up.
- Come on, this way.
- Let's get outta here.
Bowden! For Christ's sake!
They've outflanked us.
We're pinned down.
Would you cover me, Simms?
With what? All I got is blanks.
No radio contact, no ammo,
no air support, no mortars.
How the hell are we supposed
to fight with that?
Don't fucking ask me.
You're supposed to know that.
Well, fire goddamn blanks.
Use anything you got.
We got four bullets.
- I got mine.
- You shot yours, asshole.
Get ready.
Come on. We gotta retreat.
Retreat! Retreat! Pull back!
Pull back!
Listen.
What?
I don't hear anything.
I can hear it.
There!
Hey! Down here!
Over here!
- Over here!
- Down here!
Hey! Come back!
If he did see us
he's got to come back for us.
He couldn't land here -
there's too many trees.
Hey.
Where's Stuckey?
Please!
Help me!
Stuckey!
- Stuckey!
- Shit!
All right, we spread out.
We gotta find him.
Buddy teams. Me and Hardin.
I'll take Bowden.
Casper, you go with Simms.
First team to find him fire a blank
every five minutes.
The other team will work
its way there. OK?
What if we don't find him?
We'll wait an hour. Fire five blanks
then one blank every five minutes.
Both teams will work back
to each other.
Let's go.
Stuckey!
Stuckey! You little fuckin' redneck,
where are you?
Shit!
Dirty sons of bitches.
Go on, Simms.
Get back to the others.
- You're crazy.
- Go on.
You're crazy!
You heard me. Go on.
Get outta here.
I didn't do anything wrong.
I'm not supposed to be here.
Stuckey!
I think all we're doing is telling
the opposition where we are.
They haven't had too much trouble
finding us up to now.
Casper!
Simms!
Come on, let's go.
We gotta go for ourselves now.
The others make it,
then they make it.
Yeah, OK.
Boy, it's a great state
you got here, Spencer.
Sent out one fuckin' helicopter.
What do you want them to do?
Send out the National Guard?
Civilian in peace, soldier in war,
I am the Guard.
Bowden?
Hey, Bowden.
You wanna talk?
Hey, coach.
What's he coach anyway?
Football. What else?
Think he teaches history
or something too.
Looks like it's all history for him now,
poor bastard.
Could be history for a couple of
other poor bastards around here
if we don't get a break.
Yeah.
Tomorrow about this time
you'll be sitting in your den
with a beer in your hand
looking at the tube
and listening to
your old lady's bullshit.
I don't have a den.
I'll buy you one
if we ever get out of here.
Great.
How long you been married?
Five years.
Happy? Hmm?
As in happily married?
Yeah.
I like her.
She's got a good sense of humor.
What's it to you?
I just thought if I got outta here and
you didn't maybe I'd look her up.
I said she had a good sense
of humor. I don't.
Yeah.
Mine's stretched a bit thin
too at the moment.
Since they got the trapper back...
...they must be hunting us
just for the fun of it.
You got an idea of something
we can do about it
or are you just talking
for the record?
I'll tell you what I'm saying
for the record.
I wanna live.
I don't know how I'm going to do it...
...but I'm gonna fight my way
outta here.
Well... don't forget
to save me a seat, pal.
Don't worry. You got it.
Let's go.
Poor son of a bitch.
I'm not gonna kill y'all
if I don't got to.
You got a bayou over here.
Take it.
Stay to the west side.
You gonna find a road
about a mile up d'ere.
Do you mind telling us
what's going on?
It's real simple.
We live back in here. This is our
home and nobody don't fuck with us.
- What about him?
Did he do it to himself or
did your friends help him out?
If I was you all I'd quit ax'ing
question and haul ass.
And my buddies?
They're not nice like me.
Are we supposed to say thanks?
You not supposed to say nothin'.
Soldier.
Come on, Hardin.
Over there.
A truck.
Fucking truck.
Vous étes perdus, eh?
Huh?
Er... You lose you in there.
Uh, yeah.
You wanna ride, uh?
God, yes.
Jettes toi en arriére.
Throw you in the back.
Sure, you bet. Next town, right?
- That's right, yeah.
- Great.
This can't be Catahoula.
Some backwoods stop.
What happened to that town
they were taking us to?
I guess this is it.
Say, where is the telephone?
Pas de telephones ici.
We got electric light but we don't got
no telephone.
We wanna go to a town
with a telephone.
Eat first. You can go
in town more later.
No, we wanna go to town now.
No, have something to drink.
Spend some good time with us.
Laissez es bons temps rouler.
You make that telephone more later.
You come with me. I'm gonna show
you where you can wash yourselves.
(Speaks French)
Wash up?
What do you think?
I think I feel better.
Cleaner, anyway.
Yeah?
But what about safer?
Well, I wouldn't lie down
and go to sleep.
Maybe we oughta forget about
Mr. and Mrs. Cajun
and try to find the next town
by ourselves.
What for? If they're still hunting us
they'd find us in the swamp.
We're safer here.
OK.
But we grab a ride with the
first thing outta here.
Biére.
Merci.
Relax, Hardin.
These are the good Cajuns.
The other guys are a long
ways back.
You relax.
(I Dewey Balfa: Parlez Nous a Boires)
Oh parlez-nous a boire,
non pas du marriage
Toujours en regrettant,
nos jolies temps passé
Si que tu te manes lavec une jolie fillel
T'es clans les grands dangers
ga va te la voler
Si que tu te manes avec une vilaine flue,
T'es clans les grands dangers
faudra tu fais ta vie avec J'
Look at those two guys.
What two guys?
Getting out the boat.
Yeah.
D'you think they're the ones
that've been after us?
Hell, I don't know.
I never seen them.
I think it's them.
Don't go getting paranoid on me.
I got reason to be paranoid
and so do you.
They gotta kill us.
We're the only witnesses.
Don't sweat it. They can't pull
anything here in front of everybody.
- Allons dancer.
- Huh?
Allons dancer.
- Dancer?
- Dancer.
I'm telling you, Hardin, relax.
Right.
Excusez-moi.
Agh!