(FOX FANFARE)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(LOUD BOOM)
(DROID WHIRRING)
(BRAYING)
(BRAYING CONTINUES)
(RUMBLING)
(LOUD BOOM)
(BEEPING)
Echo Three, Echo Seven.
Han, old buddy.
Do you read me?
HAN: Loud and clear, kid.
What's up? (STATIC)
Well, I finished my circle.
I don't pick up any
life readings.
HAN: There isn't
enough life on this
ice cube to fill
a space cruiser.
Sensors are placed.
I'm going back.
Right. I'll see you shortly.
There's a meteorite that
hit the ground near here.
I want to check it out.
It won't take long.
(BRAYING)
LUKE: Steady! Hey!
Steady, girl!
Hey, what's the matter?
You smell something?
(GROWLING)
- (GROANS) - (GROWLS)
(SCREECHES)
(BRAYING)
(CLAMORING)
(DROID BEEPING)
(BEEPS)
HAN: Chewie! Chewie!
Chewie!
(CHEWIE GRUNTS)
All right! Don't
lose your temper.
I'll come right back
and give you a hand.
(CHEWIE GRUMBLES)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Solo?
No sign of life out
there, General.
The sensors are in place.
You'll know if
anything comes around.
RIEEKAN: Commander
Skywalker reported in yet?
No. He's checking out a
meteorite that hit near him.
With all the meteor
activity in this system...
it's going to be difficult
to spot approaching ships.
General, I gotta leave.
I can't stay anymore.
RIEEKAN: I'm sorry
to hear that.
Well, there's a
price on my head.
If I don't pay off Jabba
the Hutt, I'm a dead man.
A death mark's not an
easy thing to live with.
You're a good fighter, Solo.
I hate to lose you.
Thank you, General.
Well, Your Highness.
Guess this is it.
That's right.
Well, don't get
all mushy on me.
So long, Princess.
LEIA: Han!
HAN: Yes, Your Highnessness?
I thought you had
decided to stay.
Well, the bounty
hunter we ran into
in Ord Mantell
changed my mind.
Han, we need you!
- We need? - Yes.
- Well, what about you need?
- I need.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
You probably don't.
And what precisely am
I supposed to know?
HAN: Come on!
You want me to
stay because...
of the way you feel about me.
Yes! You're a
great help to us.
You're a natural leader.
No! That's not it!
Come on.
Ah-ha! Come on!
You're imagining things.
Am I? Then why are
you following me?
Afraid I was gonna leave without
giving you a good-bye kiss?
I'd just as soon
kiss a Wookiee!
I can arrange that!
HAN: You could
use a good kiss!
C-3PO: Don't try to pay me.
I didn't ask you to turn
on the thermal heater.
I merely commented
that it was
freezing in the
princess's chamber.
(R2-D2 BEEPING NERVOUSLY)
But it's suppose
to be freezing.
How will we dry
out her clothes?
I really don't know.
Oh, switch off!
Why did you take
this apart now?
I'm trying to get us out of
here, and you pull both...
Excuse me, sir.
Put them back
together right now!
- Might I have a word with you, please?
- What do you want?
Well, it's Princess Leia, sir.
She's been trying to get
you on the commun...
I turned it off. I don't
want to talk to her.
Oh. Well, Princess
Leia is wondering
about Master Luke.
He hasn't come back yet. She
doesn't know where he is.
I don't know where he is.
Nobody knows where he is.
What do you mean,
nobody knows?
- Well, uh, you see...
- Deck Officer!
- HAN: Deck Officer!
- Excuse me, sir.
- Might I...
- MAN: Yes, sir?
Do you know where
Commander Skywalker is?
I haven't seen him.
It's possible he came
through the south entrance.
It's possible?
Why don't you go find out?
It's getting dark out there.
Yes, sir.
C-3PO: Excuse me, sir.
Might I inquire
what's going on?
Why not?
Impossible man.
Come along, R2, let's
find Princess Leia.
Between ourselves, I
think Master Luke...
is in considerable danger.
(BRAYING)
Sir, Commander
Skywalker hasn't
come in the south entrance.
- He might have forgotten to check in.
- Not likely.
- Are the speeders ready?
- Uh, not yet.
We're having trouble
adapting them to the cold.
We'll have to go
out on tauntauns.
Sir, the temperature's
dropping too rapidly.
That's right, and my
friend's out in it.
(BRAYING)
Your tauntaun will
freeze before
you reach the first marker.
Then I'll see you in hell!
Hyah!
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(ROARING)
(GRUMBLING)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(GRUMBLING CONTINUES)
(ROARING)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUMBLES)
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
(LUKE GRUNTS)
- (GROWLS)
- (GRUNTS)
(SHRIEKING)
(LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATES)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(GRUNTS, GROANS)
(WHISTLING CONTINUES)
(BRAYING)
(BEEPING)
(WHISTLES, CHIRPING)
C-3PO: You must
come along now, R2.
There's really nothing
more we can do.
And my joints are
freezing up.
(BEEPS, CHIRPING)
Don't say things like that!
Of course we'll see
Master Luke again.
And he'll be quite all right.
You'll see.
Stupid little short circuit.
He'll be quite all right.
(BEEPING)
(PANTING)
(GROANS)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(LUKE GROANS)
(BRAYING)
(BRAYING CONTINUES)
(BEEPS)
Sir...
all the patrols are in.
Still no.
MAN: Still no contact
from Skywalker and Solo.
C-3PO: Mistress Leia.
R2 says he's been
quite unable...
to pick up any signals.
Although he does admit
that his own range
is far too weak to
abandon all hope.
Your Highness, there's nothing
more we can do tonight.
The shield doors
must be closed.
- Close the doors.
- Yes, sir.
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
R2 says the chances of...
survival are 725...
to 1.
(DOOR WHIRRING)
- (WHIMPERS)
- (BEEPS SADLY)
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- (CHEWIE EXCLAIMS)
Actually, R2 has been known
to make mistakes...
from time to time.
Oh, dear. Oh, dear.
(CHIRPS)
(BEEPING SOFTLY)
Don't worry about
Master Luke.
I'm sure he'll be all right.
He's quite clever, you know,
for a human being.
(CHEWIE WHIMPERS)
(WIND WHISTLING)
OBI-WAN: Luke.
Luke.
Ben?
You will go to the
Dagobah system.
Dagobah system?
There you will
learn from Yoda...
the Jedi master...
who instructed me.
Ben!
- Ben?
- (BRAYING)
HAN: Luke!
Luke!
(WIND WHISTLING)
Don't do this, Luke.
Come on, give me a sign here.
(BRAYING CONTINUES)
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
HAN: Not much time.
LUKE: (GROANING) Ben! Ben!
- (LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
- Ahh.
Ahh.
- Hang on, kid.
- (LIGHTSABER HUMMING)
Dagobah system.
- Whew!
- Dagobah.
This may smell bad, kid...
- Yoda.
- (PANTING CALMLY)
but it'll keep you warm...
till I get the shelter up.
(LUKE GROANING) Ben!
Dagobah!
Ah!
I thought they smelled bad...
on the outside!
Ahh!
- (WIND WHISTLING)
- Ahh.
(HAN PANTING HEAVILY)
(SNOWSPEEDER ROARING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Echo Base.
I've got something.
Not much. But, it
could be a life-form.
(ROARING CONTINUES)
ROGUE 2: Commander
Skywalker, do you copy?
This is Rogue 2.
Captain Solo!
Do you copy?
Commander Skywalker,
do you copy?
This is Rogue 2.
HAN: Good morning.
Nice of you guys to drop by.
Echo Base,
This is Rogue 2.
I've found them.
Repeat, I've found them.
C-3PO: Master Luke, sir,
it's so good to see you
fully functional again.
LUKE: Thanks, 3PO.
R2 expresses his relief also.
- HAN: How you feeling, kid?
- (CHEWIE GROWLS)
You don't look so bad to me.
You look strong enough to
pull the ears off a gundark.
Thanks to you.
- That's two you owe me, junior.
- (CHEWIE GROWLS)
Well, Your Worship,
looks like you managed
to keep me around for a
little while longer.
I had nothing to do with it.
General Rieekan
thinks it's dangerous
for any ships to
leave the system
until we've activated
the energy field.
That's a good story.
I think you just
can't bear...
to let a gorgeous guy like
me out of your sight.
I don't know where you get...
your delusions, laser brain.
(CHEWIE LAUGHS)
Laugh it up, Fussball.
But you didn't see us alone...
in the south passage.
She expressed her...
true feelings for me.
My...
LEIA: Why, you...
stuck-up...
half-witted...
scruffy-looking...
nerf herder!
Who's scruffy-looking?
(R2-D2 WHISTLES, CHIRPS)
I must have hit pretty
close to the mark to
get her all riled up
like that, huh, kid?
Well, I guess you don't know...
everything about women yet.
(CHEWIE GRUMBLES)
Headquarters personnel...
report to command center.
(GROWLING)
Headquarters personnel...
report to command center.
Take it easy.
Excuse us, please.
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
Princess, we have a visitor.
Picked up something
outside the
base's Zone 12 moving east.
It's metal.
Then it couldn't be one
of those creatures.
Could be a speeder,
one of ours.
No.
Wait.
There's something very
weak coming through.
(RADIO STATIC)
C-3PO: Sir, I'm fluent
in six million...
forms of communication.
This signal is not
used by the Alliance.
It could be an imperial code.
It isn't friendly,
whatever it is.
Come on, Chewie,
let's check it out.
Send Rogues 10 and
11 to Station 38.
(DROID BEEPING)
(CHEWIE ROARS)
(ALARM BLARES)
(CHEWIE GRUNTS)
- I'm afraid there's not much left.
- What was it?
Droid of some kind.
I didn't hit it that hard.
Must've had a self-destruct.
An imperial probe droid.
HAN: It's a good bet the
Empire knows we're here.
We'd better start
the evacuation.
(DARTH VADER THEME PLAYING)
(ION ENGINES ROARS)
(DARTH VADER BREATHING)
MAN: Admiral?
Yes, Captain.
I think we've got
something, sir.
The report is only
a fragment...
from a probe droid
in the Hoth system,
but it's the best
lead we've had.
We have thousands of probe
droids searching the galaxy.
I want proof, not leads.
The visuals indicate
life readings.
It could mean anything.
- If we followed up every lead...
- PIETT: But, sir.
The Hoth system is supposed...
to be devoid of humans.
- VADER: You found something?
- Yes, my lord.
(RADIO STATIC)
That's it.
The rebels are there.
My lord...
there are so many...
uncharted settlements.
It could be smugglers...
That is the system.
And I'm sure Skywalker
is with them.
Set your course for
the Hoth system.
General Veers,
prepare your men.
Admiral?
Groups 7 and 10 will stay
behind to fly the speeders.
As soon as each
transport is loaded...
evacuation control will give
clearance for
immediate launch.
Right, sir.
HAN: All right! That's it.
Try it.
(SIZZLING)
Oh! Turn it off!
- Turn it off!
- (CHEWIE EXCLAIMING)
- (ALARM BLARING)
- Turn it off!
Sir, it will take
quite a while...
to evacuate the T-47s.
Well, forget the
heavy equipment.
There's plenty of time to
get the smaller modules
on the transports.
- Take care, sir.
- Thanks.
Chewie.
Take care of yourself, Okay?
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
(GRUNTS) Okay!
- HAN: Hi, kid.
- (BEEPING)
There's got to be
a reason for it.
Check it at the other end.
- Wait a second.
- (BEEPING)
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Be careful.
You too.
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
General, there's a fleet
of Stardestroyers
coming out of
hyperspace in Sector 4.
Reroute all power to
the energy shield.
We gotta hold them till
all transports are away.
Prepare for gun assault.
(ION ENGINES ROARING)
What is it, General?
My lord, the fleet has
moved out of light speed.
ComScan has detected an...
energy field protecting...
an area of the
sixth planet...
of the Hoth system.
The field is strong enough
to deflect any bombardment.
The rebels are alerted
to our presence.
Admiral Ozzel came
out of light speed...
too close to the system.
He felt
surprise was wiser.
He is as clumsy
as he is stupid.
General, prepare your troops...
for a surface attack.
Yes, my lord.
Lord Vader, The fleet
has moved out of...
light speed, and we're
preparing to...
(CHOKING)
You have failed me for
the last time, Admiral.
- Captain Piett.
- PIETT: Yes, my lord?
Make ready to land our troops...
beyond their energy field...
and deploy the fleet so that...
nothing gets off the system.
You are in command now...
Admiral Piett.
Thank you, Lord Vader.
(GROANS SOFTLY)
LEIA: All troop carriers will
assemble at the
north entrance.
The heavy transport
ships will
leave as soon as
they're loaded.
Only two fighter
escorts per ship.
The energy shield
can only be...
opened for a short time,
so you'll have
to stay very...
close to your transports.
Two fighters against
a Stardestroyer?
The ion cannon will
fire several shots
to make sure that
any enemy ships
will be out of
your flight path.
When you've gotten past
the energy shield,
proceed directly to
the rendezvous point.
- Understood?
- ALL: Yeah.
Good luck.
Okay, Everybody
to your stations.
- Let's go!
- Right.
Their primary target will
be the power generators.
Prepare to open shield.
Sir, rebel ships are
coming into our sector.
Good. Our first
catch of the day.
Stand by, ion control.
Fire!
(ION CANNON FIRES)
- MAN: (ON PA) The first transport is away.
- (ALL CHEERING)
The first transport...
is away.
DAK: Feeling all right, sir?
Just like new, Dak.
How about you?
Right now I feel I could take...
on the whole Empire myself.
I know what you mean.
(WEAPONS COCKING)
(AT-AT WALKING)
Echo Station Three-T-Eight.
MAN: We've spotted
imperial walkers.
MAN 2: Imperial walkers
on the north ridge.
(R2-D2 BEEPS SOFTLY)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
LUKE: Echo Station 5-7.
We're on our way.
All right, boys.
Keep tight now.
DAK: Luke, I have
no approach vector.
I'm not set.
Steady, Dak!
Attack pattern delta. Go now!
All right, I'm coming in.
Hobbie, you still with me?
That armor's too
strong for blasters!
Rogue Group, use
your harpoons...
and tow cables.
LUKE: Go for the legs. It might be
our only chance of stopping them.
All right, stand by, Dak.
Oh, Luke, we've
got a malfunction...
in fire control.
I'll have to cut
in the auxiliary.
Just hang on!
Hang on, Dak!
Get ready to fire
that tow cable.
(SCREAMS)
Dak! Dak!
Yes, Lord Vader?
I've reached the main
power generators.
The shield will be
down in moments.
You may start your landing.
Rogue 3!
Copy, Rogue Leader.
LUKE: Wedge, I've
lost my gunner.
You'll have to
make this shot.
I'll cover for you.
Set your harpoon. Follow
me on the next pass.
WEDGE: Coming around,
Rogue Leader.
Steady, Rogue 2.
Activate harpoon!
(HARPOON ACTIVATES)
Good shot, Jansen!
- One more pass.
- JANSEN: Coming around, Wedge!
Cable out. Let her go!
Detach cable!
Cable detached!
Come on!
(CRUMPLING EXPLOSIONS)
Hah! That got him!
I see it, Wedge. Good work.
I don't think we can protect
two transports at a time.
It's risky, but we can't
hold out much longer.
We have no choice.
Launch patrol.
Evacuate remaining
ground staff.
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
HAN: No, no, no!
This one goes there!
That one goes there, right?
R2, you take good care of...
Master Luke now, understand?
(R2-D2 CHIRPING)
And do take good
care of yourself.
(BEEPING)
(R2-D2 CHIRPING NERVOUSLY)
Oh, dear. Oh, dear.
All troops will debark
for ground assault.
Prepare to target
the main generator.
- Rogue 2, are you all right?
- ROGUE 2: Yeah.
I'm with you, Rogue Leader.
Well, set harpoon.
I'll cover for you.
Coming around.
Watch that crossfire, boys.
Set for position 3.
- Steady.
- LUKE: Stay tight and low.
- This is it!
- (SCREAMING)
Hobbie!
I've been hit!
(RUMBLING)
(THUDS)
(CLAMORING)
HAN: You all right?
Why are you still here?
Heard the command
center had been hit.
You've got your
clearance to leave.
Don't worry. I'll leave.
First I'm gonna get
you to your ship.
Your Highness, we must
take this last transport.
It's our only hope.
Send all troops in
Sector 12 to the...
south slope to protect
the fighters.
- (LOUD BOOM) -
(C-3PO SCREAMING)
Imperial troops have
entered the base.
entered...(STATIC)
Come on. That's it.
Give the evacuation
code signal.
And get your transports!
Whoa! Wait for me!
(MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
(LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATES)
(CRUMPLING EXPLOSIONS)
(LOUD BOOM)
Distance to power generators?
17.28.
(EXPLODES)
Target. Maximum firepower.
- (LOUD BOOM)
- (LEIA SCREAMING)
Transport, this is Solo.
Better take off. I
can't get to you.
I'll get her out
on the Falcon.
- Come on.
- (LEIA GRUNTS)
(C-3PO STAMMERS)
Where are you going?
Come back!
(LOUD BOOMING)
(DARTH VADER THEME PLAYING)
C-3PO: Hey, wait for me!
Wait! Stop!
- How typical.
- HAN: Come on!
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
HAN: Hurry up, goldenrod!
You're gonna be a
permanent resident!
C-3PO: Wait! Wait!
(ENGINE STALLING)
- (STEAM HISSES)
- (CHEWIE GROANS)
- How's this?
- (CHEWIE GROWLS)
Would it help if I
got out and pushed?
- Captain Solo! Captain Solo!
- It might!
(GROWLING RAPIDLY)
Sir, might I suggest
that you...
It can wait.
(ENGINE STARTS)
This bucket of bolts is never
gonna get us past
that blockade.
This baby's got
a few surprises
left in her, sweetheart.
- Come on, come on!
- (CHEWIE GROWLS)
Switch over.
Let's hope we don't
have a burnout.
See?
Someday you're
gonna be wrong,
and I just hope I'm
there to see it.
- Punch it!
- (GRUNTS)
R2!
(WHISTLES, BEEPING)
LUKE: Get her ready
for takeoff.
MAN: Good luck, Luke.
See you at the rendezvous.
(R2-D2 CHIRPING NERVOUSLY)
Don't worry, R2.
We're going. We're going.
(R2-D2 BEEPS)
LUKE: There's
nothing wrong, R2.
I'm just setting
a new course.
(WHISTLES, CHIRPS)
We're not gonna regroup
with the others.
We're going to the
Dagobah system.
(WHISTLES, BEEPS)
LUKE: Yes, R2.
(R2-D2 BEEPING CONTINUES)
That's all right.
I'd like to keep it on
manual control for a while.
(WHISTLES)
(CHEWIE GROWLING)
I saw 'em! I saw 'em!
Saw what?
HAN: Stardestroyers, two
of 'em coming right at us.
Sir! Sir! May I...
Shut him up or
shut him down!
(CHEWIE ROARS)
Check the deflector shield.
HAN: Great. Well, we can
still outmaneuver them.
Take evasive action!
(ALARM SOUNDING)
Prepare to make the
jump to light speed.
But, sir!
- LEIA: They're getting closer.
- (CHEWIE GRUNTS)
Oh, yeah. Watch this.
(ENGINE STALLING)
Watch what?
I think we're in trouble.
If I may say so, sir...
I noticed earlier
the hyperdrive
motivator has been damaged.
- It's impossible to go to lightspeed.
- (GROWLS)
We're in trouble!
Horizontal boosters!
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
Alluvial dampers.
- (ROARING)
- HAN: Ow!
That's not it!
Bring me the hydrospanner!
(ROARING CONTINUES)
I don't know how we're
gonna get out of this one.
- (METAL CLANKING)
- HAN: Oww!
Chewie!
- (LOUD THUDS)
- (CHEWIE GROWLING)
That wasn't a laser blast.
Something hit us.
Han, get up here!
- Come on, Chewie!
- (CHEWIE GRUNTS)
LEIA: Asteroids!
Oh, no.
Chewie, set two-seven-one.
What are you doing?
LEIA: You're not
actually going
into an asteroid field?
They'd be crazy to follow
us, wouldn't they?
You don't have to do
this to impress me.
Sir, the possibility
of successfully...
navigating an asteroid field
is approximately 3,720 to 1.
Never tell me the odds!
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
- (CHEWIE GRUNTS)
- (C-3PO YELPS)
Look out!
(SCREAMING)
You said you wanted to be
around when I made a mistake.
- This could be it, sweetheart.
- I take it back.
We're going to get
pulverized if...
we stay out here much longer.
Ain't gonna argue with that.
Pulverized?
I'm going in closer to
one of the big ones.
BOTH: Closer?!
(GROWLS)
(LASER FIRING)
Oh, this is suicide!
There's nowhere to go.
There. That looks
pretty good.
LEIA: What looks pretty good?
HAN: Yeah.
That'll do nicely.
C-3PO: Excuse me,
ma'am, but...
where are we going?
I hope you know
what you're doing.
Yeah, me too.
- (WHISTLES)
- Yep, that's it.
Dagobah.
(R2-D2 BEEPING NERVOUSLY)
No, I'm not gonna change
my mind about this.
LUKE: I'm not picking up any...
cities or technology.
Massive life-form
readings, though.
(SIGHS)
There's something
alive down there.
(BEEPING)
Yes. I'm sure it's...
perfectly safe for droids.
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
I know! I know!
All the scopes are dead.
I can't see a thing.
Just hang on!
I'm gonna start the
landing cycle.
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
(R2-D2 CHIRPING)
(BATS SQUAWKING RAPIDLY)
(CHIRPING CONTINUES)
(WHISTLING)
(BEEPING)
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
(CHIRPS, BEEPS)
No, R2, you stay put.
I'll have a look around.
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
(WATER SPLASHES)
R2?
R2!
Where are you?
(WHISTLES, BEEPING)
(SIGHS)
You be more careful.
R2...
that way.
(WATER SPLASHES)
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYS)
R2!
(SCREAMING)
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(R2-D2 BEEPS)
LUKE: Oh, no.
Are you all right?
Come on. (GRUNTING)
You're lucky to get out of here.
(GRUNTS)
Anything broken?
(BEEPS)
If you're saying coming
here was a bad idea,
I'm beginning to
agree with you.
(BEEPING)
R2, What are we doing here?
It's like...(SIGHS)
something out of
a dream or...
I don't know.
Maybe I'm just going crazy.
(BEEPS, LAUGHING)
(DARTH VADER THEME PLAYING)
- (SOFT THUD)
- (STEAM HISSES)
(VADER BREATHING)
Yes, Admiral?
PIETT: Our ships
have sighted
the Millennium Falcon, lord,
but it has entered
an asteroid field,
and we cannot risk...
Asteroids do not...
concern me, Admiral.
I want that ship,
not excuses.
Yes, lord.
I'm gonna shut
down everything...
but the emergency
power systems.
Sir, I'm almost afraid...
to ask, but does
that include shutting
me down, too?
No. I need you to
talk to the Falcon.
Find out what's wrong
with the hyperdrive.
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
Sir, it's quite possible this
asteroid is not
entirely stable.
Not entirely stable?
I'm glad you're here to
tell us these things.
Chewie, take the
professor in the back
and plug him into
the hyperdrive.
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
C-3PO: Sometimes I
just don't understand...
human behavior.
After all, I'm only
trying to do my job.
(LOUD CRASHING)
- Let go.
- (SHUSHES)
Let go, please.
Don't get excited.
Captain, being
held by you isn't
quite enough to
get me excited.
Sorry, sweetheart.
I haven't got time
for anything else.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(CHITTERING)
(LUKE GRUNTING)
LUKE: Ready for some power?
- (R2-D2 BEEPS)
- Okay.
- Let's see now.
- (BEEPS)
Put that in there.
- There you go.
- (BEEPS)
(SIGHS)
Now all I gotta do
is find this Yoda...
if he even exists.
- (BEEPING)
- (GRUNTS, EXHALES)
(SIGHS)
It's really a strange place...
to find a Jedi master.
(WHISTLES)
- This place gives me the creeps.
- (R2-D2 CHIRPS)
But still...
there's something familiar
about this place.
(WHISTLES, BEEPING)
I don't know.
- I feel like...
- YODA: Feel like what?
- (BEEPING)
- (YODA YELLS)
Like we're being watched!
YODA: Away put your weapon!
I mean you no harm!
I am wondering...
why are you here?
I'm looking for someone.
Looking?
Found someone you have,
I would say, hmmm?
(LAUGHING)
Right.
Help you I can.
Yes, mmmm.
I don't think so.
I'm looking for
great warrior.
Oh! (LAUGHS)
Great warrior.
(LAUGHING)
Wars not make one great.
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
Aah!
LUKE: Put that down!
Now we...
Hey!
That's my dinner!
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
(YODA SPITING)
How you get so big...
eating food of this kind?
LUKE: Listen, friend,
we didn't...
mean to land in that puddle.
And if we could get our
ship out, we would.
But we can't, so why...
Cannot get your ship out.
(GIGGLES)
- Hey! Get out of there!
- Ah!
No! Oh!
Hey, you could
have broken this.
Don't do that.
Aah!
(LAUGHING NERVOUSLY)
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(GROANING SOFTLY)
You're making a mess.
(SIGHS) Mmm.
- (LAUGHS)
- Hey!
Give me that!
Mine, or I will help you not.
I don't want your help.
I want my lamp back.
I'm gonna need it to get
out of this slimy mudhole.
Mudhole?! Slimy?
My home this is...
Whoa. Mmm!
(GRUNTS)
LUKE: R2, let him have it.
Mine! Mine!
- Mine! Mine!
- LUKE: R2!
Now, will you move
along, little fellow?
We've got a lot
of work to do.
No! No, no!
Stay and help you I will...
find your friend. Hmm?
I'm not looking for a friend.
I'm looking for
a Jedi master.
Oh.
Jedi Master?
Yoda.
You seek Yoda!
- You know him? - Hmm.
Take you to him I will.
(LAUGHS)
Yes, yes. But now...
we must eat. Come.
(LAUGHS) Good food. Come.
(LAUGHING NERVOUSLY)
YODA: Come! Come!
- R2? - (BEEPS)
Stay and watch
after the camp.
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
C-3PO: Oh!
Where is R2 when I need him?
Sir, I don't know where your...
ship learned to communicate,
but it has the most
peculiar dialect.
I believe, sir, it says
that the power coupling
on the negative axis
has been polarized.
I'm afraid you'll
have to replace it.
(BEEPS)
Well, of course I'll
have to replace it.
HAN: Here! And Chewie...
(CHEWIE GRUNTS)
I think we'd better replace
the negative power coupling.
(CRACKLING)
Hey, Your Worship,
I'm only trying to help.
Would you please stop
calling me that?
Sure, Leia.
(SIGHS)
You make it so
difficult sometimes.
I do. I really do.
You could be a little
nicer, though.
Come on, admit it.
Sometimes you think
I'm all right.
Occasionally...
maybe...
when you aren't acting
like a scoundrel.
Scoundrel?
I like the sound of that.
Stop that.
Stop what?
My hands are dirty.
My hands are dirty too.
What are you afraid of?
Afraid?
Your trembling.
I'm not trembling.
You like me because
I'm a scoundrel.
There aren't enough
scoundrels in your life.
I happen to like nice men.
I'm a nice man.
No, your not.
C-3PO: Sir, sir!
I've isolated...
the reverse power
flux coupling.
HAN: Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Oh, you're perfectly
welcome, sir.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
And that Lord Vader
was the last time
they appeared in
any of our scopes.
Considering the amount of
damage we've sustained,
they must have
been destroyed.
VADER: No, Captain.
They're alive.
I want every ship
available to sweep the...
asteroid field until
they are found.
PIETT: Lord Vader.
Yes, Admiral? What is it?
The emperor commands you
to make contact with him.
Move the ship out of
the asteroid field...
so that we can send a
clear transmission.
Yes, my lord.
VADER: What is thy
bidding, my master?
EMPEROR: There is a great...
disturbance in the Force.
VADER: I have felt it.
We have a new enemy,
the young rebel who...
destroyed the Death Star.
I have no doubt...
this boy...
is the offspring...
of Anakin Skywalker.
How is that possible?
Search your feelings...
Lord Vader.
You will know it...
to be true.
He could destory us.
He's just a boy.
Obi-Wan can no
longer help him.
The Force is...
strong with him.
The son of Skywalker...
must not become...
a Jedi.
If he could be turned,
he would become a
powerful ally.
Yes!
He would be...
a great asset.
Can it be done?
He will join us...
or die, master.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(R2-D2 WHIMPERS SADLY)
(BEEPS, WHISTLES)
(YODA CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Look, I'm sure is delicious.
I just don't understand...
why we can't see Yoda now.
Patience!
For the Jedi, it is...
time to eat as well.
Eat! (LAUGHS)
Eat!
Hot!
YODA: Good food!
Mmm, good, hmm?
How far away is Yoda?
Will it take us
long to get there?
Not far.
Yoda not far.
Patience.
Soon you will be with him.
Root leaf. (LAUGHS) I cook.
Why wish you become Jedi?
Hmm?
Mostly because of
my father, I guess.
Ah, father.
Powerful Jedi was he.
(LAUGHS) Mmm.
- Powerful Jedi.
- LUKE: Oh, come on.
How could you know my father?
You don't even know who I am.
I don't even know
what I'm doing here!
We're wasting our time!
(BOTH SIGH)
I cannot teach him.
The boy has no patience.
OBI-WAN: He will
learn patience.
Hmm.
Much anger in him...
like his father.
OBI-WAN: Was I any different...
when you taught me?
No.
- He is not ready.
- Yoda.
I am ready!
Ben, I can be a Jedi!
Ben, tell him! I'm ready.
Ready, are you?
What know you ready?
For eight hundred years...
have I trained Jedi.
My own counsel will I keep...
on who is to be trained.
YODA: A Jedi must have the...
deepest commitment, hmm?
The most serious mind.
This one a long time...
have I watched.
All his life has...
he looked away...
to the future,
to the horizon.
Never his mind on
where he was, hmm?
What he was doing.
Hmm.
Adventure.
Ha. Excitement.
Ha.
A Jedi craves not
these things.
You are reckless!
OBI-WAN: So was I,
if you remember.
He is too old.
Yes, too old to
begin the training.
But I've learned so much.
(SIGHS)
Will he finish
what he begins?
I won't fail you.
I'm not afraid.
Ahh...
You will be.
(RUMBLING FAINTLY)
(SQUEALS)
(SCREAMING)
Sir, if I may venture
an opinion...
I'm not really interested
in your opinion, 3...
Something out there.
- Where? - Outside the cave.
(THUDDING)
There it is. Listen, listen.
- I'm going out there.
- Are you crazy?
I just got this
bucket back together.
I'm not going to let
something tear it apart.
Oh, then I'm going with you.
(CHEWIE ROARING)
I think it might
be better if I...
stay behind and
guard the ship.
Oh, no.
LEIA: This ground
sure feels strange.
Doesn't feel like rock.
Huh.
HAN: There's an awful lot
of moisture in here.
I don't know.
I have a bad feeling
about this.
Yeah.
Watch out!
It's all right!
Yeah, that's what
I thought...
mynock.
Chewie, check the
rest of the ship and
make sure there are
no more attached,
chewing on the power cables.
Mynocks.
Go on inside.
We'll clean them off
if there are any more.
(LEIA SCREAMING)
Han!
(CHEWIE EXCLAIMING)
(SCREAMING) Go away!
Beastly thing! Shoo! Shoo!
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
Wait a minute.
- (BLASTER FIRES)
- (LOUD RUMBLING)
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
Let's get out of here!
The Empire is still out there!
I don't think...
No time to discuss
this in committee!
(GROANS)
I am not a committee!
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
You can't make the
jump to light speed
in this asteroid field.
Sit down, sweetheart!
We're taking off!
- Look! - I see it! I see it!
- C-3PO: We're doomed!
- LEIA: The cave is collapsing.
- This is no cave! - What?
(GROWLING)
(SQUAWKING RAPIDLY)
(SQUAWKING CONTINUES)
YODA: Yes, run!
Yes!
A Jedi's strength...
flows from the Force.
But beware of the dark side.
YODA: Anger, fear,
aggression...
The dark side of the
Force are they,
easily they flow,
quick to join you in a fight.
If once you start
down the dark path,
forever will it
dominate your destiny.
Consume you it will,
as it did Obi-Wan's
apprentice.
Vader.
- Is the dark side stronger?
- No.
No. No.
Quicker, easier,
more seductive.
How do I know the good
side from the bad?
You will know...
when you are calm,
at peace,
passive.
Hmm,
A Jedi uses the Force...
for knowledge and defense,
never for attack.
But tell me why I...
No, no. There is no why.
(SIGHS)
Nothing more will I
teach you today.
Clear your mind of questions.
(R2-D2 BEEPING SOFTLY)
There's something not right.
I feel cold...
- LUKE: death.
- That place...
is strong...
with the dark side
of the Force.
A domain of evil it is.
In you must go.
What's in there?
Only what you take with you.
Your weapons...
you will not need them.
(SQUISHES)
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
(CHIRPING, BEEPING)
(SQUAWKING)
(SCREECHES)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(VADER BREATHING)
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLES)
(R2-D2 BEEPS SOFTLY)
Hmm.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
PIETT: Bounty hunters.
- We don't need their scum.
- Yes, sir.
Those rebels won't escape us.
(SPEAKING ALIEN DIALECT)
Sir, we have a
priority signal
from the Stardestroyer
A venger.
Right.
VADER: There will
be a substantial...
reward for the...
one who finds...
the Millennium Falcon.
You are free to use...
any methods necessary,
but I want them alive.
No disintegrations.
- BOBA: As you wish.
- PIETT: Lord Vader.
My lord, we have them.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
C-3PO: Oh, thank
goodness we're
coming out of the
asteroid field.
HAN: Let's get out of here.
Ready for lightspeed?
One, two...
- three!
- (ENGINE STALLS)
(CHEWIE GROWLS SOFTLY)
- It's not fair.
- (CHEWIE ROARING SADLY)
HAN: Transfer circuits
aren't working.
It's not my fault!
- No lightspeed?
- It's not my fault.
C-3PO: Sir, we've just lost the
main rear deflector shield.
One more direct
hit on the back
quarter and we're done for.
Turn her around!
I said turn her around!
I'm going to put all power
in the front shield.
You're going to attack them?
Sir, the odds of surviving a
direct assault on
an imperial...
- Shut up!
- (CHEWIE GROWLS)
NEEDA: We're moving
to attack position.
Shields up.
Track them.
They may come around
for another pass.
MAN: Captain Needa,
the ship no longer
appears on our scopes.
They can't have disappeared.
No ship that small has
a cloaking device.
Well, there's no
trace of them, sir.
Captain, Lord Vader demands
an update on the pursuit.
Get a shuttle ready.
I shall assume full
responsibility for losing them...
and apologize to Lord Vader.
Meanwhile, continue
to scan the area.
Yes, Captain Needa.
YODA: Use the force.
Yes.
(WHISTLES, BEEPING)
Now, the stone...
Feel it.
(CHIRPING, BEEPING)
Concentrate!
(GRUNTS)
(R2-D2 BEEPING DEJECTEDLY)
(YODA GROANS SOFTLY)
(R2-D2 WHISTLING)
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
LUKE: Oh, no.
We'll never get it out now.
So certain are you.
(SIGHS)
Always with you...
it cannot be done.
Hear you nothing that I say?
Master, moving stones
around is one thing.
This is totally different.
No! No different.
Only different in your mind.
You must unlearn...
what you have learned.
All right, I give it a try.
No! Try not.
Do.
Or do not.
There is no try.
(SIGHS)
(WATER SLOSHING)
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
(R2-D2 WHIMPERS)
(R2-D2 MOANS SOFTLY)
(SIGHS)
I can't.
It's too big.
Size matters not.
Look at me.
Judge me by my size, do you?
Hmm? Hmm.
And well you should not,
for my ally is the Force.
And a powerful ally it is.
Life create it...
makes it grow.
It's energy...
surrounds us...
and binds us.
Luminous beings are we,
not this crude matter.
You must feel the
Force around you...
Here, between you...
me,
the tree,
the rock,
everywhere!
Yes!
Even between the land...
and the ship.
LUKE: You want
the impossible.
(R2-D2 BEEPING EXCITEDLY)
(WHISTLES)
(WATER RUNNING)
(BEEPING)
Hmm.
(R2-D2 BEEPS)
(WHISTLES)
I don't...
I don't believe it.
That...
is why you fail.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHOKING)
(VADER BREATHING)
VADER: Apology accepted...
Captain Needa.
Lord Vader, our ships
have completed their
scan of the area
and found nothing.
If the Millennium Falcon
went into lightspeed
it'll be on the other side
of the galaxy by now.
Alert all commands.
Calculate every
possible destination...
along their last
known trajectory.
Yes, my lord.
We'll find them.
Don't fail me again...
Admiral.
Alert all commands.
Deploy the fleet.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
C-3PO: Captain
Solo, this time
you've gone too far.
(CHEWIE ROARS)
No! I will not be
quiet, Chewbacca.
Why doesn't anyone
listen to me?
- The fleet's beginning to break up.
- (CHEWIE GROWLS)
Go back and stand
by the manual
release for the landing claw.
(CHEWIE MURMURS)
I really don't see how
that's going to help.
Surrender is a
perfectly acceptable
alternative in extreme
circumstances.
The Empire may be
gracious enough.
HAN: Thank you.
Which every mind for
your next move?
If they follow standard
imperial procedure,
they'll dump their garbage
before they go to light speed,
and then we just float away.
With the rest of the garbage.
Then what?
Then we got to find a safe
port somewhere around here.
- Any ideas?
- And where are we?
The Anoat system.
There's not much there.
No. Whoa, wait.
This is intresting.
Lando.
Lando system.
Lando's not a
system, he's a man.
Lando Calrissian.
He's a cardplayer,
gambler, scoundrel.
You'd like him?
- Thanks.
- Bespin is pretty far.
But I think we can make it.
A mining colony?
Yeah, a tibanna gas mine.
Lando conned
somebody out of it.
We go back a long way,
Lando and me.
- Do you trust him?
- No!
But he's got no love for the
Empire, I can tell you that.
(DULL HUMMING)
Here we go, Chewie. Stand by.
Detach!
You do have your moments.
Not many of them.
But you do have them.
(THRUSTERS FIRING)
(R2-D2 BEEPING EXCITEDLY)
YODA: Concentrate.
Feel the force flow.
Yes.
(BEEPS, WHISTLES)
YODA: Good.
Calm.
Yes.
Through the Force,
things you will see.
Other places.
The future.
The past.
Old friends long gone.
Han?
Leia!
- (R2-D2 SCREAMING)
- (LUKE GROANS)
Hmm.
Control, control.
You must learn control!
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
I saw...
I saw a city in the clouds.
Hmm,
Friends you have there.
They were in pain.
It is the future you see.
Future?
Will they die?
Difficult to see.
Always in motion
is the future.
I've got to go to them.
Decide you must...
how to serve them best.
If you leave now,
help them you could. But...
you would destroy
all for which
they have fought
and suffered.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
No, I don't have...
a landing permit.
I'm trying to reach
Lando Calrissian.
Whoa, whoa! Wait a minute!
Let me explain!
MAN: You will not deviate
from your present course.
C-3PO: Rather touchy,
aren't they?
- I thought you knew this person.
- (CHEWIE EXCLAIMING)
That was a long time ago.
I'm sure he's
forgotten about that.
Permission granted to land...
on Platform 3-2-7.
Thank you!
Nothing to worry about.
We go way back, Lando and me.
Who's worried?
C-3PO: Oh. No on to meet us.
I don't like this.
Well, what would you like?
Well, they did let us land.
Look, don't worry.
Everything gonna be fine.
Trust me.
(DOOR HISSES)
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
See? My friend.
Keep your eyes open, huh?
(GROWLS)
HAN: Hey!
LANDO: Why, you slimy...
double-crossing,
no-good swindler.
You gotta a lot
guts coming here...
after what you pulled.
(GROWLS)
(LANDO LAUGHING EXCITEDLY)
How you doing,
you old pirate?
So good to see you!
(GROWLS)
Well, he seems very friendly.
- (LAUGHING CONTINUES)
- Yes. Very friendly.
LANDO: What are you
doing in here?
Ah, repairs.
I thought you could
help me out.
What have you
done to my ship?
Your ship?
Hey, remember,
you lost her to me
fair and square.
And how you doin', Chewbacca?
You still hanging
around with this loser?
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
Hello, what have we here?
Welcome. I'm Lando
Calrissian.
I'm the administrator
of this facility.
And who might you be?
Leia.
LANDO: Welcome, Leia.
(CHUCKLES)
All right, all right.
You old smoothie.
Hello, sir.
I am C-3PO,
human-cyborg relations.
My facilities are at your...
- (GROWLS) - Well, really!
What's wrong with the falcon?
Hyperdrive.
- I'll get my people to work on her.
- Good.
That ship saved my life
quite a few times.
She's the fastest hunk
of junk in the galaxy.
HAN: How's the gas mine?
Still paying off for you?
LANDO: Oh, not as
well as I'd like.
We're a small outpost and
not very self-sufficient.
And I've had...
supply problems
of every kind.
- I've had labor difficulties.
- (LAUGHING)
LANDO: What's so funny?
You. Listen to you.
You sound like a businessman,
a responsible leader.
Who'd have thought that, huh?
You know, seeing
you brings back
a few things.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm responsible
these days.
LANDO: It's the price you
pay for being successful.
Ooh. Nice to see
a familiar face.
- (SPEAKS ALIEN DIALECT)
- How rude!
(BEEPING)
That sounds like an
R2 unit in there.
I wonder it. Hello.
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
How interesting.
MAN: Who are you?
Oh, my!
(STAMMERS)
I'm terribly sorry. I
didn't mean to intrude.
No, please don't get up. No!
(CHEWIE MURMURS SOFTLY)
Luke...
you must complete
the training.
Ah, I can't keepthe
vision out of my head.
They're my friends.
I got to help them.
You must not go.
But Han and Leia
will die if I don't.
OBI-WAN: You don't know that.
Even Yoda cannot
see their fate.
But I can help them.
LUKE: I feel the force.
But you cannot control it.
OBI-WAN: This is a
dangerous time for you,
when you will be tempted by
the dark side of the Force.
Yes! Yes!
To Obi-Wan you listen.
The cave.
Remember your failure
at the cave.
But I've learned so
much since then.
Master Yoda, I
promise to return...
and to finish
what I've begun.
You have my word.
It is you and your abilities...
the emperor wants.
That is why your friends...
are made to suffer.
That's why I have to go.
OBI-WAN: Luke, I don't
want to lose you
to the emperor the
way I lost Vader.
You won't.
Stopped they must be.
On this all depends.
Only a fully trained
Jedi knight,
with the Force as his ally,
will conquire Vader...
And his emperor.
If you end your training now,
if you choose the
quick and easy path,
as Vader did...
you will become
an agent of evil.
Patience!
And sacrifice Han and Leia?
If you honor what
they fight for...
yes.
If you choose to face Vader,
you will do it alone.
I cannot interfere.
I understand.
- LUKE: R2?
- (R2-D2 BEEPS)
Fire up the converters.
Luke!
OBI-WAN: Don't
give in to hate.
That leads...
to the dark side.
Strong as Vader.
Mind what you have learned.
Save you it can.
I will.
And I'll return.
I promise.
(SIGHS)
Told you I did.
Reckless is he.
Now...
matters are worse.
OBI-WAN: That boy's
our last hope.
YODA: No.
There is another.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
The ship's almost finished.
Two or three more things
and we're in great shape.
The sooner the better.
Something's wrong here.
No one has seen or knows
anything about 3PO.
He's been gone too long
to have gotten lost.
HAN: Relax.
I'll talk to Lando...
and see what I can find out.
LEIA: I don't trust Lando.
Well, I don't
trust him either.
He is my friend.
Besides...
we'll soon be gone.
Then you're as good
as gone, aren't you?
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
(GROWLS)
(HOWLING ANGRILLY)
(ROARING)
(GROWLS)
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
LEIA: What happened?
Where?
- Found him in the junk pile?
- (GROWLS)
Oh, what a mess.
Chewie, you think
you can repair him?
Lando's got people
that can fix him.
- No thanks.
- (TERMINAL BEEPS)
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
I'm sorry, am I
interrupting anything?
Hmm, not really.
(SIGHS)
You look absolutely
beautiful.
LANDO: You truly belong here
with us among the clouds.
Thank you.
Would you join me for
a little refreshment?
Everyone's invited,
of course.
Having trouble
with your droid?
No.
No problem. Why?
LANDO: So, you see, since
we're a small operation,
we don't fall into the...
jurisdiction of the Empire.
So you're part of the
Mining Guild, then?
No, not actually.
Our operation is small
enough not to be noticed.
Which is advantageous
for everybody,
since our customers
are anxious to avoid
attracting attention
to themselves.
HAN: Aren't you afraid the
Empire's going to find out
about this little
operation, shut you down?
It's always been a
danger that looms like
a shadow over
everything we've built.
But things have developed
that'll ensure security.
LANDO: I've just made a deal
that will keep the Empire
out of here forever.
(DOOR OPENS)
(VADER BREATHING)
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
VADER: We would be honored...
If you would join us.
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
I had no choice.
They arrived right
before you did.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, too.
(CHEWIE GROWLING)
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
No, 3PO's with them.
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
Just hang on. We're
almost there.
(WHISTLE SCREECHING)
(CHEWIE EXCLAIMING)
(EXCLAIMING CONTINUES)
(GROWLS SOFTLY)
Oh ah ooh ah.
I m trbly srry.
I dndt mn to intrddd.
No! Secret?
Stormtroopers? Here?
We're in danger!
I must tell the others.
Oh, no! I been shot!
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
Lord Vader.
You may take Captain Solo
to Jabba the Hutt...
after I have Skywalker.
BOBA FETT: He's no
good to me dead.
He will not be...
permanently damaged.
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
Lord Vader...
what about Leia
and the Wookiee?
They must never again...
leave this city.
That was never a condition
of our agreement,
nor was giving Han to
this bounty hunter!
Perhaps you think you're...
being treated unfairly?
- No.
- Good.
It would be unfortunate if I...
had to leave a garrison here.
This deal is getting...
worse all the time.
C-3PO: Oh, yes, that's very good.
I like that.
Oh!
Something's not right
because now I can't see.
Oh, oh, oh, that's
much better.
Wait! Wait!
Oh, my!
What have you done?
I'm backwards,
you flea-bitten furball!
Only an overgrown
mophead like...
you would be stupid enough...
(CHEWIE GROWLS SADLY)
- I feel terrible. - (GROWLS)
(GROWLS)
Why are they doing this?
They never even asked
me any questions.
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
Lando.
HAN: Get out of here, Lando.
Shut up and listen!
Vader's agreed to turn Leia
and Chewie over to me.
Over you?
They'll have to stay here, but
at least they'll be safe.
What about Han?
Vader's given him to
the bounty hunter.
Vader wants us all...
He doesn't want you at all.
He's after somebody
called Skywalker.
- Luke?
- LANDO: Lord Vader set a trap for him.
And we're the bait!
Yeah. Well, he's on his way.
Perfect.
You fixed us all real
good, didn't you?
- My friend.
- (GROANS)
- (HAN GROANS)
- Stop!
(GROWLS)
I done all I can.
I'm sorry I couldn't do better,
but I've got my own problems.
Yeah.
You're a real hero.
You certainly have
a way with people.
(HAN GROANING)
VADER: This
facility is crude,
but it should be
adequate to...
freeze Skywalker...
for his journey
to the emperor.
Lord Vader,
ship approaching,
X-wing class.
Good. Monitor
Skywalker...
and allow him to land.
Lord Vader?
We only use this facility
for carbon freezing.
You put him in there,
it might kill him.
I do not want the
emperor's...
prize damaged.
It will tested...
on Captain Solo.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(DARTH VADER THEME PLAYING)
C-3PO: If only you'd
attached my legs,
I wouldn't be in this
ridiculous position.
Now remember, Chewbacca,
you have a
responsibility for me,
so don't do anything foolish.
(VADER BREATHING)
What's going on, buddy?
You're being put
into carbon-freeze.
BOBA: What if he
doesn't survive?
He's worth a lot to me.
The Empire will compensate...
you if he dies. Put him in!
(CHEWIE HOWLS)
C-3PO: No! No, no! Stop!
HAN: Stop, Chewie! Stop!
Get it all killed to me!
C-3PO: Yes, stop, please!
I'm not ready to die!
Hey! Hey!
Listen to me! Chewie!
Chewie, this won't help me!
- Hey, save your strength.
- (CHEWIE YELPS)
HAN: There will
be another time.
The princess.
You have to take care of her.
You hear me? Huh?
(CHEWIE GROANS)
I love you.
I know.
(CHEWIE HOWLING LOUDLY)
(GROWLING)
(HOWLING CONTINUES)
What's going on? Turn around!
Chewbacca, I can't see.
(DARTH VADER THEME PLAYING)
(CHEWIE GROWLING)
(THUDS)
Oh, they've encased
him in carbonite.
C-3PO: He should be
quite well-protected,
if he survived the
freezing process, that is.
VADER: Well, Calrissian.
Did he survive?
Yes, He's alive.
And in perfect hibernation.
He's all yours...
Bounty Hunter.
Reset the chamber
for Skywalker.
Skywalker has just
landed, lord.
VADER: Good.
See to it that he finds
his way in here.
VADER: Calrissian.
Take the princess
and the Wookie
to my ship.
You said they'd
be left in the
city under my supervision.
I am altering the deal.
Pray I don't alter
it any further.
(GROWLS SADLY)
(R2-D2 BEEPING EXCITEDLY)
(BLASTER FIRES)
(R2-D2 BEEPS)
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
(BEEPING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHEWIE GROWLS ANGRILLY)
Luke! Luke!
Don't! It's a trap!
(SCREAMING)
It's a trap!
(SIZZLING)
(WHISTLES, BEEPING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSING)
(VADER BREATHING)
VADER: The Force is with you,
Young Skywalker.
But your not a Jedi yet.
(BREATHING CONTINUES)
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
(CRACKLING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTS, GROANS)
(LIGHTSABER HUMMING)
- (YELLING) -
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
(CRACKLING CONTINUES)
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
LANDO: Well done.
Hold them in the
secruity tower...
and keep it quiet. Move.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
LEIA: What do you
think you're doing?
I'm getting out of here.
I knew all along. It
had to be a mistake.
Do you think that
after what you did
to Han, we're going
to trust you?
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
(CHOKING) I have no choice!
What are you doing? Trust him!
Trust him!
We understand,
don't we, Chewie?
He had no choice.
I'm just trying to help!
We don't need any
of your help.
(CHOKING) Han!
(GROWLS)
(CHOKING CONTINUES)
- LEIA: What? - Han!
It sounds like Han.
(CHOKING) There's still...
a chance to save Han...
(GROWLS)
at the east...
- platform! - (ROARS)
- Chewie. - (GROWLS SOFTLY)
C-3PO: I'm terribly
sorry about all this.
After all, he's
only a Wookiee.
BOBA: Put Captain Solo
in the cargo hold.
(R2-D2 BEEPING EXCITEDLY)
C-3PO: R2, R2! Where
have you been?
- Wait! Turn around you woodly.
- (CHEWIE GROWLS)
Hurry, hurry. We're
trying to save...
Han from the Bounty Hunter.
(BEEPING)
Well, at least your...
still in one peace.
Look what happen to me?
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
C-3PO: Oh, no!
Chewie, they're behind you!
(CHEWIE GRUNTING)
(R2-D2 BEEPING EXCITEDLY)
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLES)
You have learned
much, young one.
LUKE: You'll find, I'm
full of surprises.
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
Whoa! (GRUNTS)
Your destiny...
lies with me, Skywalker.
Obi-Wan knew is to be true.
No.
(LUKE YELLING)
All too easy.
Perhaps your not as strong
as the emperor thought.
VADER: Impressive.
Most impressive.
(ALARM BLARING)
(SCREAMING)
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
Obi-Wan has taught you well.
You have controlled
your fear.
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
Now, release your anger.
Only your hatred
can destroy me.
(CRACKLING CONTINUES)
(VADER YELPS)
(LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATING)
(VADER BREATHING)
(LIGHTSABERS ACTIVATING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTS)
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
- (LUKE SCREAMS) - (WIND
WHISTLING LOUDLY)
(WIND WHISTLING CONTINUES)
(CHEWIE ROARS)
LANDO: Secruity code
has been changed.
R2, you can tell the computer
to override the
security systems.
C-3PO: R2, hurry.
(BEEPS)
Attention, this is
Lando Calrissian.
LANDO: (ON PA) Attention.
The Empire has taken
control of the city.
I advise everyone to leave...
before more imperial
troops arrive.
(R2-D2 BEEPING RAPIDLY)
- (CHEWIE GROWLS)
- (R2-D2 BEEPING)
This way.
C-3PO: Well, don't blame me.
I'm an interpreter.
I'm not supposed to
know a power socket
from a computer terminal.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING
INDISTINCTLY)
(WHISTLES, BEEPING)
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
(EXCLAIMS) We're
not interested...
in the hyperdrive on the
Millennium Falcon, it's fixed!
(BEEPS)
Just open the door
you stupid lump!
(R2-D2 BEEPING EXCITEDLY)
C-3PO: I never doubt
you for a second.
Wonderful!
(R2-D2 BEEPS RAPIDLY)
(EXCLAIMING)
That hurts! Bend down,
you thoughtless...
Ow!
(CHEWIE GROWLS SOFTLY)
Leia!
Go!
(GRUNTS)
I thought that hairy beast
would be the end of me.
Of course I've looked better.
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
VADER: You are beaten.
It is useless to resist.
Don't let yourself
to destroy...
as Obi-Wan did.
(CRACKLING CONTINUES)
- (GRUNTS) - (GROANS)
(YELLING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
There is no escape.
Don't make me destroy you.
Luke.
You do not yet realize...
your importance.
You've only become to...
discover your power.
Join me...
and I will complete
your training.
With our combined strength...
we can end this...
destructive conflict...
and bring order...
to the galaxy.
I'll never join you!
If you only...
new the power...
of the dark side.
Obi-Wan never...
told you...
what happened to your father.
He told me enough!
He told me you kill him!
No.
I am your father.
That's not true!
That's impossible!
Search your feelings.
You know it to be true.
No!
Luke, you can...
destroy the emperor.
He has forseen this.
VADER: It is your...
destiny.
Join me...
and together...
we can rule the galaxy...
as father and son.
Come with me.
It is the only way.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(YELLS)
(SCREAMS)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(GRUNTS)
Ben?
Ben, please.
(GROANS)
Ben.
Leia.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
Hear me.
Leia.
(SOFTLY) Luke.
We've got to go back.
- What?
- I know where Luke is.
What about those fighters?
Chewie, just do it.
What about Vader?
All right, all
right, all right!
(THRUSTERS FIRING)
Alert my stardestroyer...
to prepare for my arrival.
- Look, someone's up there.
- (GROWLS SOFTLY)
LEIA: It's Luke.
Chewie, slow down.
Slow down. We'll
get under him.
Lando, open the top hatch.
(TERMINAL BEEPING)
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
LEIA: Okay. Easy, Chewie.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR OPENING)
(ION ENGINES ROARING)
- Lando?
- LANDO: Okay, let's go.
(SIGHS) Leia.
LANDO: All right, Chewie.
Let's go.
I'll be back.
LEIA: Stardestroyer.
LANDO: All right, Chewie.
Ready for lightspeed.
If your people fixed
the hyperdrive.
All the coordinates are set.
It's now or never.
- Punch it!
- (GROWLS)
(ENGINE STALLING)
(CHEWIE EXCLAIMS)
They told me they fixed it.
I trusted them!
Let me fix it!
It's not my fault!
(GRUNTS)
PIETT: They'll be in range
of our tractor beam
in moments, lord.
Did your men deactivate...
the hyperdrive...
on the Millennium Falcon?
- Yes, my lord. - Good.
Prepare the boarding party...
and set your weapons
for "stun."
- Yes, my lord. Lieutenant.
- Yes, sir.
Noisy brute.
Why don't we just go
into light speed?
- (R2-D2 BEEPING)
- We can't.
How would you know the...
hyperdrive is deactivated?
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
The city's central
computer told you?
R2-D2, you know
better than...
to trust a strange computer.
Ouch!
Pay attention to
what your doing!
Luke.
Father.
Son...
come with me.
Ben.
Why didn't you tell me?
- Chewie!
- (CHEWIE GROWLS RAPIDLY)
It's Vader.
Luke.
It is your...
destiny.
(SIGHS)
Ben.
Why didn't you tell me?
Alert all commands.
Ready for the tractor beam.
- (R2-D2 BEEPING)
- (CHEWIE GROWLS RAPIDLY)
C-3PO: R2, come back at once!
You haven't finished
with me yet.
You don't know how to
fix the hyperdrive.
Chewbacca can do it.
I'm standing here in pieces,
and you're having
delusions...
of grandeur!
(BEEPING)
(R2-D2 SCREAMING)
C-3PO: You did it!
(THRUSTERS FIRING)
(VADER BREATHING)
(ENGINES ROARING)
Luke, we're ready
for takeoff.
- (GROWLS)
- LUKE: Good luck, Lando.
LANDO: When we find
Jabba the Hutt
and that bounty hunter,
We'll contact you.
I'll meet you at
the rendezvous
point on Tatooine.
Princess, we'll find Han.
I promise.
LUKE: Chewie...
I'll be waiting
for your signal.
Take care you two.
May the Force be with you.
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
(CHEWIE GROWLS FAINTLY)
Ow.
(R2-D2 BEEPING HAPPILY)
(CHEWIE GROWLS RAPIDLY)
(THRUSTERS FIRING)
(WHISTLES, BEEPS)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)