(FOX FANFARE)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALARM SOUNDING)
(CRUMPLING EXPLOSIONS)
- Did you hear that?
- (R2-D2 BEEPS)
C-3PO: They shut down the main reactor.
We'll be destroyed for sure.
- This is madness.
- (R2-D2 BEEPING)
(R2-D2 WHISTLING)
We're doomed.
(WHISTLES, BEEPING)
There'll be no escape for
the princess this time.
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
- (CLANKING)
- What's that?
(CLANKING CONTINUES)
(WEAPONS FIRING)
(WEAPON FIRES)
(R2-D2 BEEPS)
(DARTH VADER BREATHING)
(BREATHING CONTINUES)
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
R2-D2, Where are you?
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
C-3PO: At last, where
have you been?
They're heading in this direction.
- (BEEPS)
- What are we going to do?
We'll be sent to the spice mines of
Kessel, smashed into who knows what!
Wait a minute. Where
are you going?
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
- (DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS)
- (DROIDS BEEPING)
STORMTROOPER: The Death Star plans
are not in the main computer.
Where are those transmissions
you intercepted?
What have you done
with those plans?
(CHOKING) We intercepted
no transmissions.
(GROANING) This is a consular ship.
We're on a diplomatic mission.
If this is a consular ship,
where is the ambassador?
(GROANS)
Commander, tear this ship apart
until you've found those plans,
and bring me the passengers!
I want them alive!
STORMTROOPER: There's one.
Set for stun.
(ZAPPING)
She'll be all right. Inform
Lord Vader we have a prisoner.
(R2-D2 WHISTLES)
Hey! You're not permitted in there.
It's restricted.
You'll be deactivated for sure.
- (BUZZING)
- (BEEPING)
Don't you call me a mindless philosopher,
you overweight glob of grease!
Now come out before
somebody sees you.
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
Secret missions? What plans?
What are you talking about?
I'm not getting in there.
(R2-D2 RASBERRIES)
I'm going to regret this.
(HATCH CLOSING)
(THRUSTERS FIRING)
- There goes another one.
- Hold your fire.
There's no life-forms.
It must have short-circuited.
C-3PO: That's funny. The damage
doesn't look as bad from out here.
(R2-D2 RASBERRIES)
Are you sure this thing is safe?
- (BEEPS)
- Oh.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYS)
LEIA: Darth Vader. Only
you could be so bold.
The Imperial Senate
will not sit still for this.
When they hear you've
attacked a diplomatic-
Don't act so surprised,
Your highness.
You weren't on any mercy
mission this time.
Several transmissions were beamed
to this ship by rebel spies.
I want to know what happened
to the plans they sent you.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I'm a member of the
Imperial Senate...
on a diplomatic
mission to Alderaan.
You are part of the Rebel
Alliance and a traitor.
Take her away!
Holding her is dangerous.
If word of this gets out...
it could generate sympathy for
the rebellion in the senate.
VADER: I've traced the
rebel spies to her.
Now, she is my only link
to finding their secret base.
She'll die before she'll
tell you anything.
Leave that to me.
Send a distress signal...
and then inform the senate
that all aboard were killed.
Lord Vader, the battle station
plans are not aboard this ship.
And no transmissions were made.
An escape pod was jettisoned during the
fighting, but no life-forms were aboard.
VADER: She must have hidden
the plans in the escape pod.
Send a detachment down to retrieve them,
See to it personally, Commander.
There'll be no one to
stop us this time.
Yes, sir.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYS)
(R2-D2 BEEPS FAINTLY)
(CHIRPING)
C-3PO: How did we get into this mess?
I really don't know how.
We seem to be made to suffer.
It's our lot in life.
(BEEPING, CHIRPING)
I've got to rest before I fall apart.
My joints are almost frozen.
(BEEPS, CHIRPS)
C-3PO: What a desolate
place this is.
(BEEPING, WHISTLES)
Where do you think you're going?
Well, I'm not going that way.
It's much too rocky.
- This way is much easier.
- (BEEPS)
What makes you think there
are settlements over there?
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
- Don't get technical with me.
- (BEEPS, CHIRPS)
- What mission? What are you talking about?
- (BEEPING CONTINUES)
I've just about had
enough of you.
Go that way.
You'll be malfunctioning within a
day you nearsighted scrap pile.
And don't let me catch you following me
begging for help because you won't get it.
(BEEPING, CHIRPING)
(CHIRPING)
(R2-D2 BEEPING EXCITEDLY)
No more adventures.
I'm not going that way.
(BEEPING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
C-3PO: That malfunctioning little
twerp. This is all his fault.
He tricked me into going this
way, but he'll do no better.
Wait, what's that? A transport.
I'm saved!
(YELLING) Over here!
C-3PO: Hey! Hey! Help!
Please, help!
(R2-D2 WHISTLING)
(BEEPING)
(ROCK SHATTERS)
(R2-D2 WHIMPERING)
(CHIRPS SADLY)
(SPEAKING IN ALIEN DIALECT)
- Hyah!
- (R2-D2 SHRIEKING)
(WHISTLING)
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
- (R2-D2 GROANS)
- (THUDS)
(SPEAKING ALIEN DIALECT)
JAWA: Utini!
(JAWA YELLING)
(SCREAMING IN ALIEN DIALECT)
(SPEAKING ALIEN DIALECT)
(R2-D2 WHISTLES)
- (CHIRPS)
- (BEEPING)
(CHIRPING)
Gone. Gone.
- C-3PO: R2?
- (R2-D2 BEEPS)
R2-D2, it is you! It is you!
(CHIRPING, BEEPING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
STORMTROOPER: Someone was in the pod.
The tracks go off in this direction.
Look, sir. Droids.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
C-3PO: We stopped.
Wake up. Wake up!
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
(SPEAKING ALIEN DIALECT)
We're doomed.
- Do you think they'll melt us down?
- (BEEPS)
(SPEAKING ALIEN DIALECT)
JAWA: Utini!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
- Will this never end?
- (R2-D2 BEEPS)
(JAWAS CLAMORING)
All right, fine. Let's go.
BERU: Luke! Luke!
Luke!
Tell your uncle if he gets a
translator be sure it speaks Bocce.
LUKE: Doesn't look like we have much
of a choice, but I'll remind him.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS)
(EXCLAIMS IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
OWEN: Yeah, we'll
take that red one.
No, not that one.
You. I suppose you're programmed
for etiquette and protocol.
Protocol? Why, it's my
primary function, sir.
I am well-versed in
all the customs...
I have no need for
a protocol droid.
Of course you haven't, sir. Not
in an environment such as this.
That is why I have
been programmed...
What I really need is a
droid who understands...
the binary language of
moisture vaporators.
Vaporators? Sir, my first job was
programming binary load lifters,
very similar to your
vaporators in most respects.
- Can you speak Bocce?
- Of course I can, sir.
- It's like a second language to me.
- Yeah, all right.
- Shut up! I'll take this one. Luke!
- C-3PO: Shut up, sir.
(EXCLAIMS IN ALIEN DIALECT)
Take these two over to the garage, will
you? I want them cleaned up before dinner.
But I was going into Tosche Station
to pick up some power converters.
You can waste time with your
friends when your chores are done.
OWEN: Now come on. Get to it.
(SIGHS)
All right. Come on.
(R2-D2 WHIMPERS)
- And the red one. Come on.
- (DROID BEEPING)
LUKE: Well, come on, red.
Let's go.
(WHISTLING, BEEPING)
(SPEAKS ALIEN DIALECT)
- Uncle Owen!
- Yeah?
This R2 unit has a
bad motivator! Look!
Hey, what are you
trying to push on us?
(WHISTLING, BEEPING)
C-3PO: Excuse me, sir.
But that R2 unit is in prime
condition, a real bargain.
- Uncle Owen!
- OWEN: Yeah?
What about that one?
What about that blue one?
We'll take that one.
I'm quite sure you'll be very
pleased with that one, sir.
He really is in first-class condition.
I've worked with him before.
- Here he comes.
- (BEEPING, WHISTLING)
Okay, let's go.
Now, don't you forget this.
Why I should stick my neck out for
you is quite beyond my capacity.
(WHISTLES, BEEPS)
C-3PO: Thank the maker! This oil
bath is going to feel so good.
I've got such a bad case of dust
contamination, I can barely move.
LUKE: It just isn't fair. Oh, Biggs is
right. I'm never gonna get out of here.
Is there anything I
might do to help?
No. Not unless you can alter time,
speed up the harvest, or
teleport me off this rock.
I don't think so, sir.
I'm only a droid and
not very knowledgeable...
about such things, not
on this planet, anyway.
As a matter of fact, I'm not
even sure which planet I'm on.
Well, if there's a bright
center to the universe
you're on the planet
that it's farthest from.
I see, sir.
Well. You can call me Luke.
I see, Sir Luke.
(LAUGHS) Just Luke.
Oh.
And I am C-3PO,
human-cyborg relations.
This is my counterpart... R2-D2.
- Hello.
- (R2-D2 BEEPS)
You got a lot of carbon scoring here. Looks
like you boys have seen a lot of action.
With all we've been through...
sometimes I'm amazed we're in
as good condition as we are...
what with the rebellion and all.
You know of the rebellion
against the Empire?
That's how we came to be in your
service, if you take my meaning, sir.
(WHISTLES)
- LUKE: Have you been in many battles?
- Several, I think.
Actually, there's
not much to tell.
I'm not much more than an interpreter
and not very good at telling stories.
Well, not at making them
interesting, anyway.
(GRUNTS) Well, my little friend,
you got something jammed
in here real good.
Were you on a Starcruiser or...
LEIA: Help me, Obi-Wan Kenobi.
You're my only hope.
- LUKE: What's this?
- (R2-D2 CHIRPS)
"What is what"? He asked you a question.
What is that?
Help me, Obi-Wan Kenobi.
You're my only hope.
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
C-3PO: Oh, he says it's nothing,
sir, merely a malfunction.
Old data. Pay it no mind.
Who is she? She's beautiful.
- I'm afraid I'm not quite sure, sir.
- Help me, Obi Wan Kenobi.
I think she was a passenger
on our last voyage.
A person of some
importance, I believe.
- Our captain was attached.
- Is there any more to this recording?
(BEEPS EXCITEDLY)
Behave yourself, R2. You're
going to get us into trouble.
C-3PO': It's all right. You can trust him.
He's our new master.
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
He says that he's the
property of Obi-Wan Kenobi...
a resident of these parts, and
it's a private message for him.
C-3PO: Quite frankly, sir, I don't
know what he's talking about.
Our last master was
Captain Antilles.
But with all we've been through,
this little R2 unit has
become a bit eccentric.
(R2-D2 BEEPS)
Obi-Wan Kenobi. I wonder if
he means old Ben Kenobi.
I beg your pardon, sir, but do you
know what he's talking about?
I don't know any Obi-Wan, but...
Old Ben lives out
beyond the Dune Sea.
- He's kind of a strange old hermit.
- Help me, Obi-Wan.
I wonder who she is.
Sounds like she's in trouble. I
better play back the whole thing.
(R2-D2 BEEPING EXCITEDLY)
He says the restraining bolt has
short-circuited his recording system.
He suggests that if
you remove the bolt,
he might be able to play
back the entire recording.
Hmm? Oh, yeah. Well...
I guess you're too small
to run away on me...
if I take this off. Okay.
(LUKE GRUNTS)
There you go.
Wait a minute. Where'd she go? Bring her
back. Play back the entire message.
- (BEEPS)
- What message?
The one you've
just been playing!
The one you're carrying
inside your rusty innards.
BERU: Luke! Luke!
All right, I'll be right
there, Aunt Beru.
I'm sorry, sir. But he appears to
have picked up a slight flutter.
Here. See what you can do with him.
I'll be right back.
(R2-D2 BEEPS)
Just you reconsider playing
that message for him.
- (BEEPS)
- No, I don't think he likes you at all.
No, I don't like you, either.
(BEEPS SADLY)
You know, I think that R2 unit we
bought might have been stolen.
What makes you think that?
Well, I stumbled across a recording
while I was cleaning him.
He says he belongs to someone
called Obi-Wan Kenobi.
(CLATTERS)
LUKE: I thought he might
have meant old Ben.
- Do you know what he's talking about?
- Mmm-mm.
Well, I wonder if
he's related to Ben.
That wizard's just
a crazy old man.
Tomorrow, I want you to take that R2 unit
to Anchorhead and have its memory erased.
That'll be the end of it.
It belongs to us now.
But what if this Obi-Wan
comes looking for him?
OWEN: He won't.
I don't think he exists anymore.
He died about the same
time as your father.
- He knew my father?
- I told you to forget it.
OWEN: Your only concern is to prepare
those new droids for tomorrow.
In the morning, I want them up there on the
south ridge working on those condensers.
Yes, sir.
I think those new droids
are gonna work out fine.
In fact, I, uh...
was also thinking about our agreement
about me staying on another season?
And if these new droids do work out,
I want to transmit my application...
to the academy this year.
You mean the next semester
before the harvest?
- Sure. There's more than enough droids.
- Harvest is when I need you the most!
It's only one season more.
This year we'll make enough on the harvest
that I'll be able to hire more hands...
and then you can go to
the academy next year.
OWEN: You must understand
I need you here, Luke.
But it's a whole 'nother year!
Look, it's only one more season.
Yeah, that's what you said
when Biggs and Tank left.
- BERU: Where are you going?
- Looks like I'm going nowhere.
I have to go finish
cleaning those droids.
Owen, he can't stay here forever.
Most of his friends have gone.
BERU: It means so much to him.
I'll make it up
to him next year.
- I promise.
- No.
Luke's just not a farmer, Owen. He
has too much of his father in him.
That's what I'm afraid of.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
- (BUZZING)
- C-3PO: Oh!
What are you doing
hiding back there?
It wasn't my fault, sir.
Please don't deactivate me.
I told him not to go, but
he's faulty, malfunctioning.
Kept babbling on
about his mission.
Oh, no!
C-3PO: That R2 unit has
always been a problem.
These astro droids are
getting quite out of hand.
Even I can't understand
their logic at times.
LUKE: How could I be so stupid?
He's nowhere in sight.
Blast it.
Pardon me, sir, but
couldn't we go after him?
It's too dangerous with all
the Sandpeople around.
We'll have to wait
until morning.
OWEN: Luke! I'm shutting
the power down!
All right! I'll be there
in a few minutes!
Boy, am I gonna get it.
You know, that little droid's going
to cause me a lotta trouble.
Oh, he excels at that, sir.
(SIGHS) Come on.
Luke!
Have you seen Luke this morning?
He said he had some things to
do before he started today,
so he left early.
-Did he take those two new droids with him?
-I think so.
Well, he better have those
units in the south range...
repaired by midday, or
there'll be hell to pay.
Look it, there's a droid on the scanner.
Dead ahead.
It might be our little R2 unit.
Hit the accelerator!
(SPEEDER REVVING)
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYS)
(SPEAKING ALIEN DIALECT)
(CREATURE ROARS)
Hey, whoa! Where do
you think you're going?
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
C-3PO: Master Luke is
your rightful owner now.
We'll have no more of this
Obi-Wan Kenobi gibberish.
(BEEPS)
And don't talk to me of
your mission, either.
You're fortunate he doesn't blast you
into a million pieces right here!
No. It's all right, but
I think we'd better go.
(R2-D2 WHISTLES)
What's wrong with him now?
C-3PO: There are several creatures
approaching from the southeast.
LUKE: Sandpeople, or worse.
Come on. Let's go have a look.
Come on!
(WHISTLES)
LUKE: Well...
there are two banthas down
there but I don't see any...
Wait a second.
They're Sandpeople, all right.
I can see one of them now.
(TUSKEN RAIDER YELLS)
(C-3PO SCREAMING)
(LUKE GROANS)
(YELLING)
(MUFFLED YELLING)
(WHIMPERS)
(WHISTLING)
(WHISTLING CONTINUES)
(TUSKEN RAIDER GRUNTS)
(R2-D2 CHIRPING)
(BEEPING)
(OBI-WAN HOWLING)
(TUSKEN RAIDER EXCLAIMS)
(R2-D2 WHIMPERS)
OBI-WAN: Hello there.
(WHISTLES)
Come here, my little friend.
Don't be afraid.
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
Oh, don't worry.
He'll be all right.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIGHS)
Rest easy, son. You've
had a busy day.
You're fortunate to
be all in one piece.
Ben? Ben Kenobi?
LUKE: Boy, am I glad to see you.
The Jundland Wastes are not
to be traveled lightly.
(WHISTLES, BEEPS)
- (SIGHS)
- Tell me, young Luke...
what brings you out this far?
Ah, this little droid.
(CHIRPS)
LUKE: I think he's searching
for his former master...
but I've never seen such
devotion in a droid before.
(R2-D2 WHIMPERS)
Ah, he claims to be the
property of an Obi-Wan Kenobi.
Is he a relative of yours? Do you
know who he's talking about?
Obi-Wan Kenobi?
Obi-Wan.
Now, that's a name I've
not heard in a long time.
(CLICKS TONGUE) A long time.
I think my uncle knows him.
He said he was dead.
No, he's not dead. Not yet.
- You know him?
- Well, of course I know him.
He's me.
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
I haven't gone by the
name of Obi-Wan since...
oh, before you were born.
Well, then the droid
does belong to you.
I don't seem to remember
ever owning a droid.
- Very interesting.
- (TUSKEN RAIDER GROWLING)
OBI-WAN: I think we
better get indoors.
The Sandpeople are
easily startled...
but they'll soon be back,
and in greater numbers.
(R2-D2 WHISTLING)
- (CHIRPING)
- LUKE: 3PO!
Where am I? I must
have taken a bad step.
Can you stand? We've got to get out
of here before the Sandpeople return.
I don't think I can make it.
You go on, Master Luke.
There's no sense in you risking
yourself on my account.
- I'm done for.
- (R2-D2 WHIMPERS)
LUKE: No, you're not.
What kind of talk is that?
Quickly. They're on the move.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
No, my father didn't fight in the wars.
He was a navigator on a spice freighter.
That's what your uncle told you.
He didn't hold with
your father's ideals.
Thought he should have stayed
here and not gotten involved.
- You fought in the Clone Wars?
- OBI-WAN: Yes.
I was once a Jedi knight
the same as your father.
I wish I'd known him.
OBI-WAN: He was the best
starpilot in the galaxy...
and a cunning warrior.
I understand you've become
quite a good pilot yourself.
(SIGHS)
And he was a good friend.
Which reminds me, I have
something here for you.
(CHIRPING)
Your father wanted you to have this
when you were old enough...
but your uncle
wouldn't allow it.
He feared you might follow
old Obi-Wan on some...
damn-fool idealistic crusade
like your father did.
Sir, if you'll not be needing me
I'll close down for a while.
Sure. Go ahead.
- What is it?
- (R2-D2 BEEPING)
It's your father's lightsaber.
This is the weapon
of a Jedi knight.
Not as clumsy or random...
- as a blaster.
- (LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
An elegant weapon.
For a more civilized age.
(LIGHTSABER HUMMING)
For over a thousand generations the
Jedi knights were the guardians...
of peace and justice
in the old Republic.
Before the dark times...
- before the empire.
- (LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATING)
How did my father die?
A young Jedi named Darth Vader.
Who was a pupil of mine
until he turned to evil...
helped the Empire hunt down
and destroy the Jedi knights.
He betrayed and
murdered your father.
OBI-WAN: Now the Jedi
are all but extinct.
Vader was seduced by the
dark side of the Force.
The Force?
The Force is what gives
a Jedi his power.
It's an energy field created
by all living things.
It surrounds us, penetrates us,
it binds the galaxy together.
(BEEPING, WHISTLES)
(CHIRPING)
Now let's see if we can't figure
out what you are, my little friend.
and where you come from.
- I saw part of a message he was...
- I seem to have found it.
LEIA: General Kenobi.
Years ago you served my
father in the Clone Wars.
Now he begs you to help him in
his struggle against the Empire.
I regret that I am unable to present
my father's request to you in person.
But my ship has fallen
under attack...
and I am afraid my mission to
bring you to Alderaan has failed.
I have placed information
vital to the survival of...
the rebellion into the memory
systems of this R2 unit.
My father will know
how to retrieve it.
You must see this droid safely
delivered to him on Alderaan.
This is our most desperate hour.
LEIA: Help me, Obi-Wan Kenobi.
You're my only hope.
(STATIC)
You must learn the
ways of the Force...
if you're to come
with me to Alderaan.
Alderaan?
I'm not going to Alderaan.
I've got to get home.
It's late. I'm in
for it as it is.
I need your help, Luke.
She needs your help.
I'm getting too old for
this sort of thing.
I can't get involved.
I've got work to do.
It's not that I like the Empire.
I hate it.
but there's nothing I can
do about it right now.
It's all such a
long way from here.
That's your uncle talking.
(SIGHS) My uncle.
- How am I ever gonna explain this?
- Learn about the Force, Luke.
Look, I can take you
as far as Anchorhead.
You can get a transport there to Mos
Eisley or wherever you're going.
You must do what you feel
is right, of course.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
MAN: Until this battle station
is fully operational...
we are vulnerable.
The Rebel Alliance is too well equipped.
They're more dangerous than you realize.
Dangerous to your
starfleet, Commander...
not to this battle station.
The rebellion will continue to gain
support in the Imperial Senate...
TARKIN: The Imperial Senate will
no longer be of any concern to us.
I have just received word that the emperor
has dissolved the council permanently.
The last remnants of the old
Republic have been swept away.
That's impossible.
How will the emperor maintain
control without the bureaucracy?
The regional governors now have
direct control over their territories.
Fear will keep the
local systems in line.
TARKIN: Fear of this
battle station.
MAN: And what of the rebellion?
If the rebels have obtained a complete
technical readout of this station...
it is possible,
however unlikely...
that they might find a
weakness and exploit it.
VADER: The plans you refer to
will soon be back in our hands.
Any attack made by the rebels against this
station would be a useless gesture...
no matter what technical
data they've obtained.
This station is now the
ultimate power in the universe.
CONAN: I suggest we use it.
VADER: Don't be too proud of this
technological terror you've constructed.
The ability to destroy a
planet is insignificant...
next to the power of the Force.
Don't try to frighten us with
your sorcerer's ways, Lord Vader.
CONAN: Your sad devotion to that
ancient religion hasn't helped you...
conjure up the stolen data tapes.
Or given you clairvoyance enough
to find the rebels' hidden fortre--
(CHOKING)
(CHOKING CONTINUES)
I find your lack of
faith disturbing.
(GRUNTING)
Enough of this!
- Vader, release him.
- (CHOKING)
- As you wish.
- (GROANS)
(PANTING)
This bickering is pointless.
TARKIN: Now, Lord Vader will
provide us with the location...
of the rebel fortress by the time
this station is operational.
We will then crush the rebellion
with one swift stroke.
(WHISTLES, CHIRPS)
LUKE: It looks like the
Sandpeople did this, all right.
Look. There's gaffi
sticks, bantha tracks.
It's just, I've never heard of them
hitting anything this big before.
OBI-WAN: They didn't, but we
are meant to think they did.
These tracks are side-by-side.
Sandpeople always ride single
file to hide their numbers.
These are the same Jawas
that sold us R2 and 3PO.
And these blast points,
too accurate for Sandpeople.
Only imperial stormtroopers
are so precise.
But why would imperial troops
want to slaughter Jawas?
If they traced the robots
here, they may have...
learned who they sold them to and
that would lead them back...
- home!
- Uh, wait, Luke!
OBI-WAN: It's too dangerous!
(SPEEDER REVVING)
Uncle Owen!
Aunt Beru!
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(ION ENGINES ROARING)
(DOOR OPENS)
And now, Your Higness. we will discuss
the location of your hidden rebel base.
(DROID WHIRRING)
(WHIRRING CONTINUES)
(DOOR CLOSES, THUDS)
OBI-WAN: There's nothing you could
have done, Luke. had you been there.
You'd have been killed, too,
and the droids would now be
in the hands of the Empire.
I want to come with
you to Alderaan.
There's nothing for me here now.
I want to learn the ways of the Force
and become a Jedi like my father.
(SPEEDER REVVING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
OBI-WAN: Mos Eisley spaceport.
You will never find a more wretched
hive of scum and villainy.
We must be cautious.
(SPEEDER REVVING)
(CHATTERING)
(BRAYING)
(JAWAS EXCLAIMING)
STORMTROOPER: How long
have you had these droids?
LUKE: Three or four seasons.
OBI-WAN: They're up for
sale if you want them.
Let me see your identification.
You don't need to see
his identification.
We don't need to see
These aren't the droids
you're looking for.
we're looking for.
He can go about his business.
You can go about your business.
- Move along.
- Move along. Move along.
C-3PO: I can't
abide those Jawas.
Disgusting creatures.
- Go on, go on.
- (JAWA IN ALIEN DIALECT)
I can't understand how
we got by those troops.
I thought we were dead.
The Force can have a strong
influence on the weak-minded.
(CREATURE ROARS)
LUKE: Do you really think we're gonna find
a pilot here that'll take us to Alderaan?
Most of the best freighter pilots
are to be found here...
only watch your step.
- This place can be a little rough.
- LUKE: I'm ready for anything.
(BELLOWS)
- Come along, R2.
- (BEEPING)
(WHISTLES, BEEPS)
(LOUNGE MUSIC PLAYING)
(LAUGHING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
MAN: Hey! We don't
serve their kind here.
- What?
- Your droids.
They'll have to wait outside.
We don't want them here.
Why don't you wait out by the speeder?
We don't want any trouble.
I heartily agree with you, sir.
(CHATTERING CONTINUES)
Uh, I'll have one of those.
(SPEAKING ALIEN DIALECT)
(CHEWIE GRUNTS)
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
- He doesn't like you.
- I'm sorry.
I don't like you, either.
You just watch yourself.
MAN: We're wanted men.
I have the death sentence
on twelve systems.
I'll be careful.
You'll be dead!
This little one's not
worth the effort.
Come, let me get you something.
(YELLING)
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
(SCREAMING)
(LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATING)
(MUSIC RESUMES)
I'm all right. (SIGHS)
Chewbacca here is first mate
on a ship that might suit us.
I don't like the look of this.
- (BEEPS)
- (GROWLING)
Han Solo. I'm captain
of the Millennium Falcon.
Chewie here tells me you're looking
for passage to the Alderaan system.
Yes, indeed, if
it's a fast ship.
Fast ship?
You've never heard of
the Millennium Falcon?
Should I have?
It's the ship that made the Kessel
run in less than 12 parsecs.
I've outrun imperial starships.
Not the local bulk
cruisers, mind you.
I'm talking about the big
Corellian ships now.
She's fast enough
for you, old man.
- What's the cargo?
- Only passengers.
Myself, the boy, two droids.
and no questions asked.
What is it, some kind
of local trouble?
Let's just say we'd like to avoid
any imperial entanglements.
Well, that's the real
trick, isn't it?
And it's gonna cost
you something extra.
10,000, all in advance.
10,000?
We could almost buy our
own ship for that.
But who's gonna
fly it, kid, you?
You bet I could. I'm not
such a bad pilot myself.
We don't have to sit
here and listen.
We can pay you 2,000 now...
plus 15 when we reach Alderaan.
17, huh?
Okay. You guys got
yourselves a ship.
We'll leave as soon
as you're ready.
- HAN: Docking Bay 94.
- Ninety-four.
Looks like somebody's beginning to
take an interest in your handiwork.
STORMTROOPER:
All right. We'll check it out.
- (CHEWIE GRUNTS)
- HAN: 17,000.
(SCOFFS) Those guys must
really be desperate.
This could really save my neck.
- Get back to the ship, get it ready.
- (GROWLS)
OBI-WAN: You'll have
to sell your speeder.
LUKE: That's okay. I'm never
coming back to this planet again.
(SPEAKING ALIEN DIALECT) Solo?
Yes, Greedo. As a matter of fact, I
was just going to see your boss.
Tell Jabba that
I've got his money.
(GREEDO SPEAKING
ALIEN DIALECT)
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, but this time
I've got the money.
I don't have it with me.
Tell Jabba...
- (GREEDO CHUCKLES)
- (BLASTER COCKS)
(GREEDO SPEAKING
ALIEN DIALECT)
HAN: Even I get
boarded sometimes.
Do you think I had a choice?
Over my dead body.
Yes. I'll bet you have.
(BLASTER FIRES)
(JAWA EXCLAIMS)
(SIZZLING)
Sorry about the mess.
(JAWAS IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
(ION ENGINES ROARING)
VADER: Her resistance to the
mind probe is considerable.
It'll be some time before we can
extract any information from her.
CONAN: The final
checkout is completed.
All systems are operational.
What course shall we set?
TARKIN: Perhaps she would respond
to an alternative form of persuasion.
What do you mean?
I think it is time we demonstrated
the full power of this station.
- Set your course for Alderaan.
- CONAN: With pleasure.
C-3PO: Lock the door, R2.
All right. Check this
side of the street.
The door's locked.
Move on to the next.
(BEEPS)
I would much rather have gone with
Master Luke than stay here with you.
I don't know what all this trouble is
about but I'm sure it must be your fault.
(R2-D2 RASBERRIES)
You watch your language.
(BEEPING)
All right. Give it to me.
I'll take it.
(BEEPS)
Look at this.
Ever since the XP-38 came out,
they just aren't in demand.
- It'll be enough.
- (DROIDS BEEPING)
JABBA: Solo.
(SPEAKING HUTTESE)
- Solo!
- HAN: Right here, Jabba.
I've been waiting
fot you.
(JABBA IN HUTTESE)
(LAUGHS)
You didn't think I was
gonna run, did you?
Greedo?
Look, Jabba, next time you want to
talk to me, come see me yourself.
Don't send one of these twerps.
Han.
(SPEAKING HUTTESE)
(CONTINUES SPEAKING HUTTESE)
Look, Jabba, even I get
boarded sometimes.
(GASPS, GRUNTS)
You think I had a choice?
But I got a nice, easy charter. I'll
pay ya back, plus a little extra.
I just need a little more time.
(HUTTESE)
Fifteen, Jabba. Don't push it.
Jabba...you're a
wonderful human being.
(AGREES IN HUTTESE)
If the ship's as fast as he's
boasting, we ought to do well.
(CHEWIE GRUNTS)
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
What a piece of junk!
She'll make point-five
past lightspeed.
She may not look like much, but
she's got it where it counts, kid.
I've made a lot of special
modifications myself.
But we're a little rushed...
so if you'll just get on
board, we'll get outta here.
- C-3PO: Hello, sir.
- (R2-D2 BEEPING)
Which way?
All right, men.
Load your weapons.
STORMTROOPER: Stop
that ship! Blast them!
Chewie, get us out of here!
(R2-D2 CHIRPS)
C-3PO: Oh, my. I'd forgotten
how much I hate space travel.
(THRUSTERS FIRING)
(CHEWIE GROWLING)
Looks like an imperial cruiser.
Our passengers must be
hotter than I thought.
Try and hold 'em off. Angle
the deflector shields...
while I make the calculations
for the jump to lightspeed.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
Stay sharp. There's
two more comin' in.
They're gonna try
and cut us off.
LUKE: Why don't you outrun 'em? I
thought you said this thing was fast!
Watch your mouth, kid, or you're
gonna find yourself floating home.
We'll be safe enough once we
make the jump to hyperspace.
Besides, I know a few maneuvers.
We'll lose 'em.
Here's where the fun begins.
How long before you can make
the jump to lightspeed?
It'll take a few moments to get the
coordinates from the navicomputer.
Are you kidding? At the
rate they're gaining?
Traveling through hyperspace
ain't like dustin' crops, boy!
Without precise calculations...
we'd fly right through a star or
bounce too close to a supernova...
and that would end your trip
real quick, wouldn't it?
- (BEEPING)
- What's that flashing?
We're losing a deflector shield.
Go strap yourselves in. I'm gonna
make the jump to lightspeed.
(CHEWIE ROARING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
CONAN: We've entered
the Alderaan system.
LEIA: Govenor Tarkin.
I should have expected to find
you holding Vader's leash.
I recognized your foul stench
when I was brought on board.
(LAUGHS)
Charming to the last.
You don't know how hard I found it signing
the order to terminate your life.
I'm surprised you had the courage to
take the responsibility yourself.
Princess Leia, before
your execution...
I would like you to be my
guest at a ceremony...
that will make this battle
station operational.
No star system will dare
oppose the emperor now.
The more you tighten
your grip, Tarkin,
the more star systems will
slip through your fingers.
Not after we demonstrate
the power of this station.
In a way...
you have determined the choice of the
planet that will be destroyed first.
Since you are reluctant...
to provide us with the
location of the rebel base...
I have chosen to test this
station's destructive power...
on your home planet of Alderaan.
No! Alderaan is peaceful. We have
no weapons. You can't--
TARKIN: You would prefer another target?
A military target?
Then name the system!
I grow tired of asking this,
so it will be the last time.
Where is the rebel base?
Dantooine.
- They're on Dantooine.
- TARKIN: There.
You see, Lord Vader?
She can be reasonable.
Continue with the operation.
- You may fire when ready.
- What?!
You're far too trusting.
Dantooine is too remote to make
an effective demonstration.
But don't worry. We will deal with
your rebel friends soon enough.
No!
Commence primary ignition.
(BEEPS)
(LASER FIRING)
(EXPLODING)
(LIGHTSABER HUMMING)
(LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATING)
Are you all right? What's wrong?
I felt a great disturbance
in the Force...
as if millions of voices
suddenly cried out in terror...
and were suddenly silenced.
I fear something
terrible has happened.
You'd better get on
with your exercises.
HAN: Well, you can forget your
troubles with those imperial slugs.
- I told you I'd outrun them.
- (LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
Don't everybody
thank me at once.
Anyway, we should be at
Alderaan about 0200 hours.
(CHITTERS)
- (BEEPS)
- (LIGHTSABER HUMMING)
(CHITTERING)
(CREATURE SHRIEKING)
- Now be careful, R2.
- (CHIRPING)
(ROARS)
(BEEPS, CHIRPS)
(CHEWIE GRUNTS)
He made a fair move. Screaming
about it can't help you.
Let him have it. It's not
wise to upset a Wookiee.
But, sir, nobody worries
about upsetting a droid.
That's 'cause a droid don't pull people's
arms out of their sockets when they lose.
HAN: Wookiees are
known to do that.
(GRUMBLES)
I see your point, sir.
I suggest a new strategy, R2.
Let the Wookiee win.
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
(LIGHTSABER HUMMING)
Remember, a Jedi can feel the
Force flowing through him.
You mean it controls
your actions?
Partially, but it also
obeys your commands.
- (LUKE GROANS)
- (HAN LAUGHING)
Hokey religions and ancient weapons
are no match for a good blaster...
- at your side, kid.
- (LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATING)
You don't believe in
the Force, do you?
Kid, I've flown from one side
of this galaxy to the other.
I've seen a lot of
strange stuff...
but I've never seen anything
to make me believe...
there's one all-powerful force
controlling everything.
HAN: There's no mystical energy
field controls my destiny.
It's all a lot of simple
tricks and nonsense.
I suggest you try
it again, Luke.
This time, let go your
conscious self...
and act on instinct.
(LAUGHS) With the blast shield
down, I can't even see.
- How am I supposed to fight?
- Your eyes can deceive you.
Don't trust them.
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
(GROANS, SIGHS)
Stretch out with your feelings.
(LIGHTSABER HUMS)
- You see? You can do it.
- (LIGHTSABER DEACTIVATING)
HAN: I call it luck.
In my experience, there's
no such thing as luck.
Look, good against
remotes is one thing.
Good against the living,
that's something else.
(TERMINAL BEEPING)
Looks like we're
coming up on Alderaan.
LUKE: You know, I did feel something.
I could almost see the remote.
That's good. You've taken your
first step into a larger world.
TARKIN: Yes?
Our scout ships have
reached Dantooine.
MAN: They found the
remains of a rebel base,
but they estimate that it has
been deserted for some time.
They are now conducting an extensive
search of the surrounding systems.
TARKIN: She lied. She lied to us.
VADER: I told you she would never
consciously betray the rebellion.
Terminate her, immediately!
(FUSE BLOWING)
Stand by, Chewie. Here we go.
Cut in the sublight engines.
- (RUMBLING)
- What the-
(CHEWIE EXCLAIMING)
Uh, we've come out of hyperspace
into a meteor shower.
Some kind of asteroid collision.
It's not on any of the charts.
What's going on?
Our position's correct,
except no Alderaan.
What do you mean?
Where is it?
That's what I'm trying to tell you, kid. It
ain't there. It's been totally blown away.
- LUKE: What? How?
- OBI-WAN: Destroyed by the Empire.
The entire starfleet couldn't
destroy the whole planet.
It would take 1,000 ships
with more firepower than...
(BEEPING)
- There's another ship coming in.
- Maybe they know what happened.
It's an imperial fighter.
- LUKE: It followed us!
- (ION ENGINES ROARS)
OBI-WAN: No. It's a
short-range fighter.
There aren't any bases around here.
Where did it come from?
It sure is leaving in a big hurry. If
they identify us, we're in big trouble.
Not if I can help it. Chewie,
jam its transmissions.
It would be as well to let it go.
It's too far out of range.
Not for long.
(ION ENGINES ROARING)
A fighter that size couldn't get
this deep into space on its own.
He must have gotten lost, been
part of a convoy or something.
Well, he ain't gonna be around long
enough to tell anybody about us.
LUKE: Look at him. He's
heading for that small moon.
HAN: I think I can get him before he
gets there. He's almost in range.
That's no moon.
- It's a space station.
- It's too big to be a space station.
I have a very bad
feeling about this.
Turn the ship around.
Yeah. I think your right.
Full reverse!
- Chewie, lock in the auxiliary power.
- (CHEWIE GRUNTS)
Chewie, lock in the
auxiliary power.
(CHEWIE EXCLAIMING)
LUKE: Why are we still
moving towards it?!
We're caught in a tractor beam!
It's pulling us in!
There's got to be
something you can do!
There's nothing I can do about it, kid. I'm
at full power. I'm gonna have to shut down.
They're not gonna get
me without a fight.
(CHEWIE GROWLING)
You can't win, but there are
alternatives to fighting.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
MAN: Clear Bay 327.
We are opening the
magnetic field.
To your stations! Come with me.
(SQUEAKING)
Close all outboard shields.
TARKIN: Yes?
We've captured a freighter entering
the remains of the Alderaan system.
Its markings match those of a ship that
blasted its way out of Mos Eisley.
VADER: They must be trying to return
the stolen plans to the princess.
She may yet be of
some use to us.
Unlock one, five, seven, and nine.
Release charge.
316, report to control.
MAN: There's no one
on board, sir.
According to the log, the crew
abandoned ship right after takeoff.
It must be a decoy, sir. Several of
the escape pods have been jettisoned.
- VADER: Did you find any droids?
- No, sir.
If there were any on board,
they must also have jettisoned.
Send a scanning crew aboard. I want
every part of this ship checked.
Yes, sir.
I sense something,
a presence I've
not felt since...
Get me a scanning crew
in here on the double.
I want every part of
this ship checked.
STORMTROOPER: There's no one here.
LUKE: Boy, it's lucky you
had these compartments.
HAN: I use them for smuggling. I never
thought I'd be smuggling myself in 'em.
This is ridiculous. Even if I could take
off, I'd never get past the tractor beam.
OBI-WAN: Leave that to me.
Damn fool, I knew
that you were gonna say that.
Who's the more foolish, the fool
or the fool who follows him?
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
(INDISTINCT PA CHATTER)
The ship's all yours.
If the scanners pick up anything,
report it immediately.
All right, let's go.
(THUDDING)
HAN: Hey, down there!
Could you give us
a hand with this?
(BLASTER FIRING)
TK-421, why aren't
you at your post?
TK-421, do you copy?
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
Take over. We've got a bad transmitter.
I'll see what I can do.
(DOOR OPENS)
(CHEWIE ROARS)
(GROANS)
(GROWLS)
(CHEWIE ROARING)
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
You know, between his howling and
your blasting everything in sight,
it's a wonder the whole station
doesn't know we're here.
HAN: Well, bring them on! I'd prefer a
straight fight to all this sneakin' around.
We've found the
computer outlet, sir.
Plug in. He should be able to interpret
the entire imperial network.
(R2-D2 WHISTLES)
(CHIRPS, BEEPING)
(BEEPING, CHIRPING)
He says he's found the main controls to the
power beam that's holding the ship here.
He'll try to make the precise
location appear on the monitor.
C-3PO: The tractor beam is coupled to
the main reactor in seven locations.
A power loss at one of the terminals
will allow the ship to leave.
I don't think you boys can help.
- I must go alone.
- Whatever you say.
I've done more than I bargained
for on this trip already.
But, I want to go with you.
Be patient, Luke. Stay and
watch over the droids.
- But, he could--
- They must be delivered safely
or other star systems will suffer
the same fate as Alderaan.
Your destiny lies along a
different path from mine.
(DOOR OPENS)
The Force will be with you...
always.
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- (CHEWIE GROWLING)
Well, you said it, Chewie.
Where did you dig
up that old fossil?
Ben is a great man.
- Yeah, great at getting us into trouble.
- I didn't hear you give any ideas.
Well, anything's better than just hangin'
around waiting for 'em to pick us up.
- Who do you think-
- (R2-D2 BEEPING)
What is it?
C-3PO: I'm afraid I'm
not quite sure, sir.
He says "I've found her" and
keeps repeating "She's here."
Well, who... who has he found?
Princess Leia.
The princess? She's here?
- Princess?
- LUKE: Where? Where is she?
HAN: Princess? What's going on?
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
(CHIRPING)
Level 5, Detention Block AA-23.
(R2-D2 CHIRPING)
I'm afraid she's scheduled
to be terminated.
Oh, no!
- LUKE: We've got to do something!
- What are you talking about?
The droids belong to her. She's the one
in the message. We got to help her!
Now look, don't get any funny ideas. The
old man wants us to wait right here.
But he didn't know she was here. Just find
a way back into that detention block.
- I'm not going anywhere!
- There gonna execute her.
Look, a few minutes ago...
you said you didn't want to
just wait here to be captured.
Now all you want to do is stay?
Marching into the detention
area is not what I had in mind.
- But they're gonna kill her!
- Better her than me!
She's rich.
(CHEWIE GRUMBLING)
- Rich?
- Mmm-hmm. Rich.
Powerful. Listen, if you were to
rescue her, the reward would be...
What?
Well, more well than
you can imagine.
- I don't know. I can imagine quite a bit.
- You'll get it.
- I better.
- You will?
All right, kid.
You better be right about this.
- All right.
- HAN: What's your plan?
Uh...
3PO, hand me those
binders there, will you?
LUKE: Okay.
Now, I'm gonna put these on you.
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
Okay. Han, you put those on.
Don't worry, Chewie. I think
I know what he has in mind.
Master Luke, sir, pardon
me for asking. But...
what should R2 and I do
if we're discovered here?
- Lock the door.
- And hope they don't have blasters.
- That isn't very reassuring.
- (R2-D2 WHISTLES)
(DROID BEEPING)
- (CHEWIE GROWLS)
- (DROID YELPS)
MAN: 517 to scanner control.
316, report to control.
53 to upper bay door.
LUKE: I can't see a
thing in this helmet.
(DARTH VADER BREATHING)
- HAN: This is not gonna work.
- LUKE: Why didn't you say so before?
I did say so before.
Where are you taking
this...thing?
LUKE: Prisoner transfer
from Cell Block 1138.
I wasn't notified.
I'll have to clear it.
(CHEWIE ROARS)
- HAN: Look out, he's loose!
- LUKE: He'll tear us all apart!
HAN: I'll get him!
(SCREAMS)
HAN: Look out!
(CHEWIE GROWLING)
(BEEPING)
HAN: We gotta find out which cell
this princess of yours is in.
Here it is...2187.
You go and get her.
I'll hold them here.
Uh, everything's under control.
Situation normal.
- MAN: What happened?
- Uh...
Had a slight weapons
malfunction,
but, uh, everything's
perfectly all right now.
We're fine. We're all fine here now.
Thank you.
- How are you?
- We're sending a squad up.
Uh, uh...
Negative, negative! We have a...a
reactor leak here, uh, now.
Give us a few minutes to lock it down.
Uh, large leak, very dangerous.
Who is this? What's
your operating number?
Ahh.
Boring conversation anyway. Luke!
We're gonna have company!
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(STEAM HISSES)
Aren't you a little short
for a stormtrooper?
LUKE: Huh? Oh, the uniform.
I'm Luke Skywalker. I'm
here to rescue you.
- Your who?
- I'm here to rescue you.
I've got your R2 unit. I'm
here with Ben Kenobi.
- Ben Kenobi? Where is he?
- Come on!
- VADER: He is here.
- TARKIN: Obi-Wan Kenobi?
What makes you think so?
A tremor in the Force.
The last time I felt it...
was in the presence
of my old master.
TARKIN: Surely he
must be dead by now.
VADER: Don't underestimate the Force.
The Jedi are extinct. Their fire
has gone out of the universe.
You, my friend, are all that's
left of their religion.
Yes?
MAN: We have an emergency alert
in Detention Block AA-23.
The princess? Put all
sections on alert.
Obi-Wan is here.
The Force is with him.
If you're right, he must
not be allowed to escape.
VADER: Escape is not his plan.
I must face him alone.
(CHEWIE GROWLING)
Get behind me!
STORMTROOPER: Watch your left.
They went down the cell bay.
Can't get out that way.
Looks like you managed to cut
off our only escape route.
Maybe you'd like it back in
your cell, Your Highness.
- C-3PO! C-3PO!
- C-3PO: Yes, sir?
Are there any other ways out of
the cell bay? We've been cut off!
What was that? I didn't copy!
I said all systems have been
alerted to your presence, sir.
The main entrance seems to
be the only way in or out.
All other information on
your level is restricted.
STORMTROOPER: Open up in there!
Open up in there!
Oh, no.
There isn't any other way out!
(CHEWIE GROWLING)
I can't hold them off forever!
- HAN: Now what?
- This is some rescue!
You came in here, and you didn't
have a plan for getting out?
- He's the brains, sweetheart!
- Well, I didn't!
- What the hell are you doing?
- Somebody has to save our skins.
Into the garbage chute, fly boy!
- Get in there!
- (CHEWIE GROWLS)
HAN: Get in there,
you big furry oaf!
I don't care what you smell!
- (CHEWIE ROARING)
- Get in there and don't worry about it!
Wonderful girl!
Either I'm going to kill her,
or I'm beginning to like her!
HAN: Get in there!
HAN: Yahoo!
- (SCREAMS)
- (CHEWIE GROWLS)
HAN: The garbage chute was
a really wonderful idea.
What an incredible
smell you discovered.
(CHEWIE GRUMBLES)
Let's get out of here.
- Get away from there!
- (CHEWIE ROARS)
LUKE: No, wait!
(CHEWIE ROARING)
LUKE: Will you forget it? I already
tried it! It's magnetically sealed!
LEIA: Put that thing away!
You're gonna get us all killed!
Absolutely, your worship.
Look, I had everything
under control...
till you led us down here!
Ya know, it's not gonna take 'em long
to figure out what happened to us!
- LEIA: Could be worse.
- (CREATURE GROWLING)
It's worse.
LUKE: There's something
alive in here.
HAN: That's your imagination.
Something just
moved past my leg.
- Look! Do you see that?
- What?!
(CHEWIE EXCLAIMS)
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
(WATER SLOSHING)
(CREATURE ROARING)
- HAN: Kid! Luke!
- LEIA: Luke!
- Luke!
- (CHEWIE GROWLING)
Luke!
(CHEWIE GROWLING CONTINUES)
- (LEIA SCREAMS)
- (ROARING CONTINUES)
Luke! Luke, grab hold of this!
(SCREAMING) Blast it!
My gun's jammed!
- Where?
- Anywhere!
(GRUNTS)
- (CHEWIE GRUNTS)
- (WATER SPLASHES)
HAN: Luke! Luke!
(CHEWIE WHIMPERING)
(CLANKING)
- LEIA: Help him!
- (LUKE COUGHING)
- What happened?
- I don't know!
It just let go of
me and disappeared.
(COUGHING)
(COUGHING CONTINUES)
- HAN: I got a bad feeling about this.
- (COUGHS)
(RUMBLING)
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
(CLANKING)
- The walls are moving!
- Don't just stand there.
Try and brace
it with something.
(CHEWIE YELPS)
(CHEWIE GRUNTS)
LEIA: Help me!
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
(CREAKING)
Wait a minute!
(CREAKING CONTINUES)
3PO! Come in, 3PO!
LUKE: (SHOUTING) 3PO!
Where could he be?
STORMTROOPER: Take over.
See to him.
Look, there.
C-3PO: They're madmen. They're
heading for the prison level.
If you hurry, you
might catch them.
Follow me!
You stand guard.
Come on.
(R2-D2 WHISTLES)
Oh.
All this excitement has overrun the
circuits in my counterpart here.
If you don't mind, I'd like to
take him down to maintenance.
- STORMTROOPER: All right.
- (R2-D2 BEEPING)
(GROWLS)
3PO!
Come in, 3PO! 3PO!
HAN: Get on top!
- LEIA: I can't!
- Where could he be? 3PO!
LUKE: 3PO, will you come in!
They aren't here. Something
must have happened to them.
See if they've been captured.
Hurry.
(R2-D2 WHISTLING)
One thing's for sure, we're
all gonna be a lot thinner.
- Get on top of it!
- LEIA: I'm trying!
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
(BEEPING)
Thank goodness they
haven't found them.
- Where could they be?
- (BEEPING CONTINUES)
"Use the comlink"?
Oh, my. I forgot.
I turned it off.
- (CREAKING)
- (CHEWIE ROARS)
- Are you there, sir?
- 3PO!
We've had some problems.
LUKE: Will you shut up
and listen to me?
Shut down all the garbage mashers
on the detention level, will ya?
Do you copy?
Shut down all the garbage
mashers on the detention level!
(CHEWIE GRUMBLES)
LUKE: Shut down all the garbage
mashers on the detention level!
No! Shut them all down.
Hurry! Oh, no!
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
- (BEEPS)
- (CLANKING)
- (HAN LAUGHS)
- What?
(LAUGHS)
Hey! Hey, 3PO!
- (ALL SCREAMING)
- Listen to them. They're dying, R2!
Curse my metal body!
I wasn't fast enough.
- It's all my fault!
- (LUKE SCREAMS)
- LUKE: 3PO, we're all right!
- My poor master.
We're all right!
You did great!
(LAUGHING) Hey!
Hey! Open the pressure maintenance
hatch on unit number... Where are we?
LUKE: 3263827!
(SLOW TUNE PLAYS)
(WINDING DOWN)
(LOW BEEPING)
HAN: If we can just avoid
any more female advice...
we ought to be able
to get outta here.
Well, let's get moving.
- (CREATURE ROARING)
- (CHEWIE GROWLS)
Where you going? Ah.
LEIA: No, wait! They're hear!
Come here, you big coward.
Chewie, come here.
LEIA: Listen.
I don't know who you are
or where you came from.
But from now on, you do
as I tell you, Okay?
Look, Your Worshipfulness.
Let's get one thing straight.
I take orders from
just one person. Me!
Hmm, It's a wonder
you're still alive.
Will somebody get this big
walking carpet out of my way?
No reward is worth this.
STORMTROOPER: Give me
regular reports, please.
Right.
Do you know what's going on?
Maybe it's another drill.
You seen that new VT-16?
Yeah. Some of the other guys
were telling me about it.
They say it's... it's
quite a thing to see...
What was that?
Ah, it's nothing. Outgassing.
Don't worry about it.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS)
- HAN: There she is.
- C-3PO, do you copy?
- C-3PO: Yes, sir.
- LUKE: Are you safe?
For the moment.
We're in the main hangar
across from the ship.
LUKE: We're right above you.
Stand by.
You came in that thing?
- You're braver than I thought.
- Nice. Come on.
STORMTROOPER: It's them! Blast them!
- Get back to the ship!
- LUKE: Where you going? Come back!
He certainly has courage.
What good will it do us if he
gets himself killed? Come on.
(HAN SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
Whoa! I think we
took a wrong turn.
There's no lock!
That oughta hold
them for a while.
Quick! We've got to get across. Find
the controls that extend the bridge.
- LUKE: I think I just blast it.
- LEIA: They're coming through!
(BLASTER FIRES)
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(SCREAMING)
Here. Hold this.
LEIA: Here they come!
For luck.
STORMTROOPER: We think
they may be splitting up.
They may be on Level
five and six now, sir.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- Where could they be?
- (R2-D2 BEEPING)
STORMTROOPER: Close
the blast doors!
STORMTROOPER: Open the blast doors.
Open the blast doors.
(VADER BREATHING)
(LIGHTSABER HUMMING)
(LIGHTSABER ACTIVATING)
I've been waiting
for you, Obi-Wan.
We meet again, at last.
VADER: The circle
is now complete.
When I left you, I
was but the learner.
Now, I am the master.
Only a master of evil, Darth.
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
(CRACKLING CONTINUES)
Your powers are weak, old man.
You can't win, Darth.
If you strike me down...
I shall become more powerful...
than you can possibly imagine.
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
You should not have come back.
(CRACKLING CONTINUES)
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
Didn't we just leave this party?
(CHEWIE ROARS)
What kept you?
We, uh, ran into some old friends.
- The ship all right?
- HAN: Seems okay.
If we can get to it.
I just hope the old man got the
tractor beam out of commission.
(LIGHTSABER CRACKLING)
(VADER BREATHING)
LUKE: Look!
Come on, R2, we're going.
(R2-D2 BEEPS)
Now's our chance! Go!
(BEEPS)
Ben?
(CRACKLING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS)
No!
(R2-D2 WHISTLES)
- HAN: Come on!
- LEIA: Luke, come on!
Come on!
Luke, it's too late!
HAN: Blast the door, kid!
(DOOR HISSING)
OBI-WAN: Run, Luke! Run!
I hope that old man got that
tractor beam out of commission,
or this is gonna be
a real short trip.
- Okay, hit it!
- (CHEWIE GROWLS)
(THRUSTERS FIRING)
(GRUMBLING, GROWLS)
(GRUNTS)
(R2-D2 MOANS)
We're coming up on
their sentry ships.
Hold them off. Angle the deflector
shields while I charge up the main guns.
- (CHEWIE GRUNTS)
- (BEEPING)
I can't believe he's gone.
There wasn't anything
you could have done.
Come on, buddy. We're
not out of this yet.
(CONTROLS CLICKS)
You in, kid?
Okay, stay sharp.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
- Here they come!
- (ION ENGINES ROARING)
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYS)
(R2-D2 BEEPS)
(LASERS FIRING)
They're coming in too fast!
(ION ENGINES ROARING)
C-3PO: Oh!
We've lost the lateral controls!
Don't worry.
She'll hold together.
(CRACKLING)
Hear me, baby. Hold together.
(LAUGHS)
- Got him! I got him!
- Great, kid! Don't get cocky!
There's still two more
of them out there!
(LASER FIRING)
(MONITOR BEEPS)
- That's it! We did it!
- We did it!
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
Help! I think I'm melting!
This is all your fault!
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
Are they away?
They've just made the
jump into hyperspace.
You're sure the homing beacon
is secure aboard their ship?
I'm taking an awful risk, Vader.
This had better work.
Not a bad bit of rescuing, huh?
You know, sometimes I
amaze even myself.
That doesn't sound too hard.
They let us go.
It's the only explanation
for the ease of our escape.
- HAN: Easy? You call that easy?
- LEIA: They're tracking us.
Not this ship, sister.
(SIGHS) At least the information
in R2 is still intact.
What's so important?
What's he carrying?
The technical readouts
of that battle station.
I only hope that when the data's
analyzed a weakness can be found.
- It's not over yet.
- It is for me, sister.
Look, I ain't in this for your revolution
and I'm not in it for you, Princess.
I expect to be well paid.
I'm in it for the money.
You needn't worry
about your reward.
If money is all that you love
then that's what you'll receive.
LEIA: Your friend is
quite a mercenary.
I wonder if he really cares
about anything or anybody.
LUKE: I care.
(SIGHS) So...
what do you think of her, Han?
- I'm trying not to, kid.
- (BEEPING)
Good.
Still, she's got a lot of sprit.
I don't know. What do you think? You
think a princess and a guy like me?
No!
(ENGINES ROARING)
(ROARING CONTINUES)
(INDISTINCT PA CHATTER)
(ENGINES ROARING)
You're safe. When we heard about
Alderaan, we feared the worst.
LEIA: We have no time
for sorrows, Commander.
You must use the information in this
R2 unit to help plan the attack.
It's our only hope.
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
(BEEPS)
(R2-D2 BEEPS EXCITEDLY)
- TARKIN: Yes?
- MAN: We're approaching the planet Yavin.
The rebel base is on a
moon on the far side.
We are preparing to
orbit the planet.
(CHITTERING)
(CHITTERING CONTINUES)
JAN: The battle station is heavily
shielded and carries a firepower...
greater than half the starfleet.
Its defenses are designed around
a direct large-scale assault.
A small, one-man fighter should be
able to penetrate the outer defense.
JON: Pardon me for asking, sir.
but what good are snub fighters...
going to be against that?
JAN: Well, the Empire doesn't consider a
small, one-man fighter to be any threat.
Or they'd have a tighter defense.
An analysis of the plans
provided by Princess Leia...
has demonstrated a weakness
in the battle station.
- (BEEPING)
- The approach will not be easy.
You're required to maneuver
straight down this
trench and skim the
surface to this point.
The target area is
only two meters wide.
It's a small thermal exhaust
port right below the main port.
JAN: The shaft leads directly
to the reactor system.
A precise hit will start a chain reaction
which should destroy the station.
Only a precise hit will
set up a chain reaction.
The shaft is ray-shielded, so you'll
have to use proton torpedoes.
That's impossible,
even for a computer.
But, it's not impossible. I used to
bull's-eye womp rats in my T-16 back home.
They're not much
bigger than two meters.
Then man your ships, and
May the Force be with you.
(ALL CLAMORING)
MAN: Orbiting the planet
at maximum velocity.
The moon with the rebel base
will be in range in thirty minutes.
VADER: This will be a
day long remembered.
It has seen the end of Kenobi...
and will soon see the
end of the rebellion.
(DARTH VADER BREATHING)
MAN: (ON PA) All flight
crews, man your stations.
All flight crews,
man your stations.
LUKE: So...you got your reward
and you're just leaving, then?
HAN: That's right. Yeah.
I got some old debts I got
to pay off with this stuff.
And even if I didn't...
you don't think I'd be fool enough
to stick around here, do ya?
Why don't you come with us?
You're pretty good in a fight.
- We could use ya.
- Come on!
Why don't you take
a look around?
You know what's about to happen
what they're up against.
They could use a good pilot like you.
You're turning your back on them.
What good's a reward if you
ain't around to use it?
Besides, attacking that battle
station ain't my idea of courage.
More like, suicide.
All right. Well, take
of yourself, Han.
I guess that's what
you're best at, isn't it?
Hey, Luke!
May the Force be with you.
(CHEWIE ROARING)
What are you looking at?
I know what I'm doing.
MAN: (ON PA) All pilots,
to your stations.
All pilots, to your stations.
- LEIA: What's wrong?
- Oh, it's Han.
I don't know. I really thought
he'd change his mind.
He's got to follow his own path.
No one can choose it for him.
I wish Ben were here.
(KISSES)
MAN: (ON PA) Open
main launch tubes.
Main launch tubes opening, sir.
BIGGS: Hey, Luke!
- LUKE: Biggs!
- I don't believe it! How are you?
- Great!
- Hey, coming up?
I'll be right up there with you, and
have I got stories to tell you.
Are you sure you can
handle this ship?
BIGGS: Sir, Luke is the best bush
pilot in the outer-rim territories.
- You'll do all right.
- Thank you, sir. I'll try.
I gotta get aboard. We'll hear all your
stories when we get back, all right?
Right. Hey, Biggs!
- I told you I'd make it someday.
- It'll be likes old times, Luke.
They'll never stop us.
MAN: (ON PA)
Stands clear.
Hey, this R2 unit of yours seems a
bit beat up. You want a new one?
Not on your life. That little droid and
I have been through a lot together.
- You okay, R2? Good.
- (R2-D2 BEEPING)
MAN: (ON PA) Gold squadron,
begin takeoff procedure.
Hang on tight, R2.
You've got to come back.
(R2-D2 BEEPING CONTINUES)
You wouldn't want my life
to get boring, would you?
(WHISTLES, BEEPS)
(INDISTINCT PA CHATTER)
(INDISTINCT PA
CHATTER CONTINUES)
OBI-WAN: Luke!
The Force will be with you.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
MAN: Stand by alert.
Death Star approaching.
Estimated time to
firing range...
fifteen minutes.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(ENGINES ROARING)
All wings report in.
Red Ten standing by.
Red Seven standing by.
Red Three standing by.
Red Six standing by.
Red Nine standing by.
Red Two standing by.
Red Eleven standing by.
- Red Five standing by.
- (R2-D2 BEEPING)
Lock S-foils in attack position.
(X-WINGS ACTIVATING)
GARVEN: We're passing
through the magnetic field.
Hold tight. Switch your
deflectors on. Double front.
Look at the size of that thing.
GARVEN: Cut the shatter, Red Two.
Accelerate to attack speed.
- This is it, boys.
- Red Leader, this is Gold Leader.
GARVEN: I copy, Gold Leader.
JON: We're starting for
the target shaft now.
We're in position.
I'm going to cut across the axis
and try and draw their fire.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYS)
MAN: Heavy fire,
boss, 23 degrees.
GARVEN: I see it. Stay low.
This is Red Five. I'm going in!
BIGGS: Luke, pull up!
- Are you all right?
- I got a little cooked, but I'm okay.
(ALARM BLARING)
We count thirty rebel
ships, Lord Vader!
But they're so small, they're
evading our turbolasers!
We'll have to destroy
them ship to ship.
Get the crews to their fighters.
Watch yourself.
There's a lot of fire coming from the
right side of that deflection tower.
- LUKE: I'm on it.
- BIGGS: I'm going in.
- Cover me, Porkins.
- I'm right with you, Red Three.
(CRUMPLING EXPLOSIONS)
I got a problem here.
- Eject.
- I can hold it.
- Pull up!
- No, I'm all!
(PORKINS SCREAMING)
MAN: (ON PA) The rebel
base will be firing range
in seven minutes.
OBI-WAN: Luke, trust
your feelings.
Squad Leaders.
We've picked up a new
group of signals.
Enemy fighters coming your way.
My scope's negative.
I don't see anything.
Pick up your visual scanning.
Here they come.
(ION ENGINES ROARING)
Watch it. You've got
one on your tail!
I'm hit!
You've picked one up! Watch it!
I can't see it!
He's on me tight.
I can't shake him!
I'll be right there.
(LASER FIRES)
Several fighters have broken
off from the main group.
Come with me.
Fall in! F-Fall in!
Watch your back, Luke. Watch your back.
Fighters above you, coming in.
I'm hit, but not bad. R2, see
what you can do with it.
- (R2-D2 BEEPING)
- LUKE: Hang on back there.
GARVEN: Red Six, can
you see Red Five?
There's a heavy fire zone.
- Red Five, where are you?
- I can't shake him!
WEDGE: I'm on it, Luke. Hold on!
Blast it, Biggs!
Where are you?
- Thanks, Wedge.
- BIGGS: Good shooting, Wedge.
JON: Red Leader,
This Gold Leader.
We're starting our attack run.
GARVEN: I copy, Gold Leader.
- Move into position.
- (ION ENGINES ROARING)
VADER: Stay in attack formation.
JON: The exhaust port is
marked and locked in.
JON: Switch all power to
front deflector screen.
Switch all power to
(GUNS FIRING)
How many guns do you
think, Gold Five?
DAVISH: Say about twenty guns, some
on the surface, some on the towers.
Death Star will be in
range in five minutes.
Switch to targeting computer.
(COMPUTER BEEPING)
Computer locked. Getting a signal.
DEX: The guns.
They stopped.
Stabilize your rear deflectors.
Watch for enemy fighters.
JON: They're coming in!
Three marks at two-ten.
(ION ENGINES ROARING)
I'll take them myself.
- Cover me!
- Yes, sir.
(VADER BREATHING)
It's no good. I can't maneuver.
Stay on target.
- We're too close!
- Stay on target!
Loosen up!
Gold Five to Red Leader.
Lost Tiree, Lost Hutch.
- I copy, Gold Leader.
- They came from behind!
We've analyzed their attack, sir.
And there is a danger.
Should I have your
ship standing by?
Evacuate?
In our moment of triumph?
I think you overestimate
their chances.
MAN: Rebel base, three
minutes and closing.
Red boys, this is Red Leader.
Rendezvous at mark six point one.
- WEDGE: This is Red Two flying toward you.
- BIGGS: Red Three standing by.
Red Leader, This is Base One.
JAN: Keep half your group out
of range for the next run.
GARVEN: Copy, Base One.
Luke, take Red Two and Three.
Hold up here and wait for my
signal to start your run.
This is it!
We should be able
to see it by now.
Keep your eyes open
for those fighters.
There's too much interference. Red Five,
can you see them from where you are?
No sign of any... Wait.
- LUKE: Coming in point three-five.
- I see them.
I'm in range.
- Target's coming up.
- (BEEPING)
GARVEN: Just hold them
off for a few seconds.
VADER: Close up formation.
Almost there.
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
- (VADER BREATHING)
- (BEEPING)
You'd better let her loose.
- THERON: They're right behind me!
- Almost there.
- (BEEPING)
- I can't hold them!
(SCREAMING)
It's away!
(CRUMPLING EXPLOSIONS)
- It's a hit!
- Negative, negative.
It didn't go in.
It just impacted on the surface.
LUKE: Red Leader, we're right above you.
Turn to 0-five. We'll cover for you.
GARVEN: Stay there. I just
lost my starboard engine.
Get set up for your attack run.
(SCREAMING)
(EXPLODES)
MAN: Rebel base, one
minute and closing.
LUKE: Biggs, Wedge.
Let's close it up.
(STAMMERS) We're
going in full throttle.
That ought to keep those
fighters off our back.
Right with you, boss.
Luke, at that speed, will you
be able to pull out in time?
It'll be just like Beggars
Canyon back home.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
We'll stay back far
enough to cover you.
WEDGE: My scope shows the tower,
but I can't see the exhaust port.
Are you sure the
computer can hit it?
Watch yourself. Increase
speed, full throttle.
What about that tower?
You worry about those fighters!
I'll worry about the tower!
R2, that stabilizer's broken loose again.
See if you can't lock it down.
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
WEDGE: Fighters coming in point three.
(LASER FIRES)
WEDGE: I'm hit! I can't stay with you.
LUKE: Get clear, Wedge. You can't
do any more good back there.
Sorry!
Let him go. Stay on the leader.
Hurry, Luke. They're coming in much
faster this time. We can't hold them.
- R2, try and increase the power.
- (R2-D2 WHISTLING)
BIGGS: Hurry up, Luke!
Quick! Quick!
Rebel base, thirty
seconds and closing.
I'm on the leader.
(R2-D2 WHISTLES)
Hang on, R2.
(BEEPING)
(ION ENGINES ROARING)
OBI-WAN: Use the Force, Luke.
Let go, Luke.
The Force is strong
with this one.
Luke, trust me.
His computer's off.
Luke, you switched off your
targeting computer. What's wrong?
LUKE: Nothing! I'm all right.
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
- (R2-D2 SHRIEKING)
- LUKE: I've lost R2!
The Death Star has cleared the planet.
Rebel base in range.
TARKIN: You may fire when ready.
Commence primary ignition.
(BEEPING)
I have you now!
- What?
- Yahoo!
Look out!
You're all clear, kid! Now let's
blow this thing and go home!
(TORPEDOS FIRING)
(SIGHS)
Stand by.
Great shot, kid! That
was one in a million!
OBI-WAN: Remember, the Force
will be with you always.
(ION ENGINES ROARING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
- LEIA: Luke!
- LUKE: Hey!
(LEIA LAUGHING)
HAN: Hey! Hey!
I knew you'd come back.
I just knew it.
Well, I wasn't going to let you get all
the credit and take all the reward.
Hey, I knew there was more
to you than money. (LAUGHS)
Oh, no.
C-3PO: Oh, my. R2,
can you hear me?
Say something.
You can repair him, can't you?
We'll get to work
on him right away.
You must repair him.
Sir, if any of my circuits or gears
will help, I'll gladly donate them.
He'll be all right.
(LAUGHING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHEWIE ROARS)
(R2-D2 WHISTLING)
(BEEPING)
(BEEPS)
(CHEWIE GROWLS)
(CHEERING)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)