You're from Baker?
Tell Baker that I told him
all that I know already.
Tell him I want to live
in peace understand?
There is no use to
go on tormenting me!
I know nothing at all
about that case of coins.
Now that gold has disappeared,
but if he'd listened
we could have
avoided this altogether.
I went to the army court.
There were no witnesses.
They couldn't uncover any more.
I can't tell Baker
what happened to the money.
Go back and tell him that.
Word's around you had a visitor,
and Baker knows it.
Name of Jackson.
Well, Jackson was here
or Baker's got it all wrong.
He's not wrong.
Maybe Baker would like to know,
just what you and
Jackson had to say,
about the cash box.
That's not what
I'm being paid for.
I'm only interested in what name
Jackson's hiding under now.
Why do you think Jackson may
be assuming another name?
I would have found him already.
When I start off to find
somebody I find him.
That's why they pay me.
What is Baker paying you?
That your family?
Yes.
Nice family.
What does he pay
you for murdering me?
$500
to get the name.
The name.
Carson. Bill Carson.
That's what he calls himself now.
That's a lot of money. $1,000.
$1,000?
And some in gold
That's a tidy sum.
But when I'm paid,
I always see the job through.
It's you.
Any information?
Too much.
He said quite a bit
that should interest you,
and one or two
things that interested me.
Such as?
The name Jackson's
hiding under is Bill Carson.
That's your bit.
Keep talking.
He also mentioned something
about a certain cash box,
which just happened to disappear.
That's my bit.
Anything else?
Not enough for you, eh?
Well, you don't have to worry.
He'll never say
anything to anybody again.
Oh, yeah, yeah. Perfect.
Here you are.
Here. This is for you.
You did a good job for me.
Worth $500.
Yeah. I almost forgot.
He gave me $1,000.
I think his idea
was that I kill you.
But you know the pity is
when I'm paid,
I always follow my job through.
You know that.
No! Angel Eyes.
No. No pistol, amigo.
It won't do you any good.
There are three of us.
Hey, amigo.
You know you've got a face beautiful
enough to be worth $2,000?
Yeah.
But you don't look like the
one who'll collect it.
A couple steps back.
Thank you.
How much are you worth now?
How much?
$2,000.
That's right, $2,000.
Yeah, $2,000.
You'll pay for this! I hope
you end up in a graveyard
with the cholera and the
rabies and the plague!
Cut me loose!
Cut me loose,
you filthy bastard!
Put me down!
I hope your mother ends up
in a two-dollar whorehouse!
Cut me loose! Cut me loose!
You can still save yourself.
Let me go, and I'll pardon you.
Let me go.
I think I feel sick.
The blood is bursting through my...
I'm dry, Blondie.
Water.
You swine. You son of
a bitch Let me go!
You're brave with
a man who's tied up!
Come back!
Come back and fight!
You bastard.
Who the hell is that?
One bastard goes in
another comes out.
Cut it out! Cut it out!
I'm an honest farmer!
I'm innocent of any...
So, you're an honest farmer
You recognize this man?
Me'?
Yeah, it's you.
Me? Who says so?
You can't even read.
Yeah, roll it up Roll it up.
I'll give you a good idea
where you can put it.
To hell with all you sheriffs and
deputies and all who gave birth to you.
Hey, everybody, look, look He's
giving him the filthy money.
Judas. You sold my hide.
But you won't enjoy any of
that money, not a penny.
If there's justice in the world
that money will go
to the undertakers.
Every penny of it.
You know who you are?
You want to know
whose son you are?
You don't, I do. Everybody does.
You're the son of a thousand
fathers, all bastards like you.
And your mother Your mother!
She's... You bastard!
Your mother. It's better
not to talk of her!
I never hurt anybody!
"Wanted in 14
counties of this state"
"the condemned is found guilty
of the crimes of murder,"
"armed robbery of citizens,
state banks and post offices"
"the theft of sacred objects
arson in a state prison,"
"perjury, bigamy, deserting
his wife and children,"
"inciting prostitution,
kidnapping, extortion"
"receiving stolen goods
selling stolen goods,"
"passing counterfeit money and
contrary to the laws of this state,"
"the condemned is guilty of using
marked cards and loaded dice."
Therefore, according to
the powers vested in us
we sentence
the accused here before us.
Tuco Benedicto Pacifico
Juan Maria Ramirez...
Known as "The Rat"
and any other
aliases he might have
to hang by the neck until dead.
May God have mercy on his soul.
Proceed.
Five for you. One, two
three, four, five for me.
Five for you and five for me.
Know how much you're worth now?
No. How much?
$3,000.
There are two kinds of people
in the world, my friend,
those with a rope
around their neck,
and the people who have the
job of doing the cutting.
Listen, the neck at
the end of the rope is mine
I run the risks.
So the next time,
I want more than half.
You may run the risks my
friend, but I do the cutting.
If we cut down my percentage.
Cigar?
It's liable
to interfere with my aim.
But if you miss you had
better miss very well.
Whoever double crosses me
and leaves me alive,
he understands
nothing about Tuco.
Nothing.
"Wanted in 15
counties of this state."
"The condemned
standing before us"
sitting before us.
"Tuco Benedicto Pacifico Juan Maria
Ramirez, has been found guilty"
"by the Third District Circuit
Court of the following crimes,"
"murder, assaulting
a justice of the peace"
"raping a virgin
of the white race"
"statutory rape
of a minor of the black race"
"derailing a train in order
to rob the passengers..."
Hey, Angel Eyes
"bank robbery, highway robbery"
"robbing an unknown number of
post offices, breaking out..."
What'd you find out, Shorty?
If you ask me,
it seems like a book.
An armed unit escorting
a cash box of gold coins,
meets a Yankee ambush,
and only three of them are saved.
Stevens, Baker and Jackson.
The thing that wasn't saved
though, was the coins.
But then the army decides
of course,
it ought to hold a hearing
and Jackson's acquitted.
He disappears and
becomes Bill Carson
I know his name.
But you don't know just who
you're looking for, and I do.
And when he's found I'd be
scared to be put in his shoes.
Where is Carson?
All I know is Carson reenlisted.
The poor guy's minus an eye.
He lives with a girl
called Maria who'll tell you.
She's a fresh young
whore in the territory.
Where's she?
Now, what's the
name of that town?
Someplace fairly near,
Santa Ana.
Adios, half-soldier.
Hey, Luke, hand me
down a whiskey.
"And the sheriff's
office in Sonora."
"The condemned hired himself out
as a guide to a wagon train."
"After receiving his payment in
advance, he deserted the wagon train"
"on the hunting grounds
of the Sioux lndians."
Glad they got him a man
guilty of all those crimes.
People with ropes around their
necks don't always hang.
What do you mean?
"The condemned
is also guilty..."
Even a filthy beggar like that
has got a protecting angel.
"As a Mexican general."
A golden-haired angel
watches over him.
For all these crimes
"the accused has made a full
spontaneous confession."
"Therefore, we condemn him to be
hung by the neck until dead."
May the Lord have
mercy on his soul.
Proceed.
Let's get the hell out of here!
What are you trying to say
anybody can miss a shot?
Nobody misses when
I'm at the end of the rope.
You've never had
a rope around your neck.
Well, I'm going to
tell you something.
When that rope
starts to pull tight
you can feel
the devil bite your ass.
Yeah, you're right.
It's getting tougher.
The way I figure
there's really
not too much future
with a sawed-off runt like you.
What do you mean?
'Cause I don't think you'll
ever be worth more than $3,000.
What do you mean?
I mean,
our partnership is untied.
Oh, no. Not you You remain tied.
I'll keep the money,
and you can have the rope.
You filthy,
double-crossing bastard!
Of all the stinking
dirty tricks...
The way back to
town is only 70 miles.
You know,
if you save your breath
I feel a man like
you could manage it.
You filthy bastard! Come here!
Come here! Cut this rope off!
Get off that horse.
Get off that horse
you filthy coward!
If I ever catch you, Blondie, I'll
rip your heart out and eat it!
I'll scalp you!
I'll skin you alive!
I'll hang you up by your thumbs!
You pig! You vulture!
I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
Such ingratitude, after all the
times I've saved your life.
Where are you going? Wait a minute.
This is only a trick.
You wouldn't leave me here.
Come back! Wait! Blondie!
Listen, Blondie.
I believe madam is home.
Sweet dreams, and many thanks
from the Seventh Cavalry!
You filthy rats!
Maria.
Is that you, Bill?
Who are you? What do
you want with me?
Go on talking about Bill Carson.
I don't know him.
You were calling
to him in the dark.
Where is he'?
What are you going to do to him?
I'll ask the questions.
Where is he'?
Where is he? Where?
Where? Where? Where?
That's enough!
I don't know where he is.
He packed his things
ten days ago
and went away with
his unit. They all left.
Which company? Where'd they go?
Hmm?
Third Cavalry, General Sibley.
They left for Santa Fe.
That's all I know, I swear!
But, but.
I'm very sorry,
but the store's closing.
Mmm-hmm.
Revolvers.
Yeah, revolvers.
Well, here's where
I keep the best ones.
Here. Remington, Colt
a Roat, Smith-Wesson Colt, Navy,
Joslyn, another Remington.
- And this one.
- That's enough.
Cartridges.
You want to try the pistol?
Just step out back.
Let's go.
Move. Move.
Cartridge.
How much?
$100.
$200. It's all I've got.
Here.
Come here.
Eh?
Mmm-hmm.
If you work for a living, why
do you kill yourself working?
Potatoes.
You've got to be
poor to eat potatoes.
Really poor
I'm rich. But I'm lonely.
The world is divided
into two parts,
those who have friends, and those
who are lonely like poor Tuco.
You see, I used
to have a friend, Pedro.
Chico and Ramon, his two
brothers, were my friends, too.
But who knows
where they are now?
It's too bad, friends Tough
luck I haven't found you.
I had a good deal for you.
There's a big son of a
bitch who's got $4,000.
$4,000.
And I know where to find it.
If they would help me catch him.
I'd divide it four ways
like a brother.
$1,000 each.
Hmm.
You're alive, Tuco Is it true?
I'm alive and rich.
But people are saying
you got killed in Albuquerque.
And people talk bullshit
I'm alive, you bastards.
I'm alive.
And I've come to
give you $3,000.
This morning,
I heard the whole thing.
They say Colonel Canby's closing
in with his Northerners,
and no later than tomorrow
that they'll be in the city.
That's why these Southerners
are getting out.
You see, as soon as these cowards
hear a Blue Shirt's around, they run.
These Rebels have
no will to fight.
Poor things.
They'll soon be finished.
We get rid of these bastards, then we
begin making money on those Yankees.
They carry gold,
not paper dollars.
And they're going
to beat the South.
Look. See that one with the white
beard sitting in the wagon?
General Sibley He looks dead.
He's finally
getting out of our hair.
Hurray for Dixie!
Hurray! Hurray for Dixie!
Where's the owner of that horse?
Please, mister, sir,
a bad heart condition.
Where?
The war has
frightened me already
I'm looking for the
owner of that horse.
He's tall, blond,
he smokes a cigar
and he's a pig. Where is he now?
You leave him be. He doesn't
know who rides every horse.
You stay quiet, old hen.
Upstairs. Upstairs
in room four, senor.
Hear that?
You rotten criminals
How dare you?
Your spurs.
There are two kinds
of spurs, my friend,
those that come in by the door,
those that come in by the window.
Take off that pistol belt.
It's empty-
Mine isn't.
Even when Judas hanged himself,
there was a storm, too.
That could be cannon fire
Cannon fire or storm,
it's all the same to you.
You ever see this
before, my friend?
Throw it over the roof beam.
That's it.
Now get on that.
That's right.
Now make sure the rope is tight.
It's got to hold
the weight of a pig.
Now put the rope
around your neck.
That's very good.
It's too big for your neck, huh?
We fix that right away.
I have another system
a little different than yours.
I don't shoot the rope
I shoot the legs off the stool.
Welcome, my friend.
If you're looking for a summer
vacation spot you've found it.
Our hotel is luxurious
and filled with conveniences.
And the attractions
don't stop there.
International cuisine,
healthful and nutritious food.
Corn cobs, Dixie-style.
Our government has
spared no expense.
As you can see,
we are treated very well.
Have you ever heard of anyone
by the name of Bill Carson?
And you? Have you ever heard
of someone named Canby? No?
Well, you see,
he's a Yankee colonel
who decided to tear us to pieces.
The only thing we care about
is saving our own hides.
And you ask me if I know someone.
I just don't know what you
drifters could be thinking.
Carson has a patch over one eye.
He's with the Third.
If he's with the Third
they've already left.
For Glorieta.
Canby's front line is
right on their heels.
Those poor young devils.
And the desert
lies ahead of them.
I really doubt that
any of them are still alive.
And what if they
were still alive?
Worse.
Well, then, you must not have
heard anything about Batterville.
It's one of those
Yankee prison camps
you'd better hope
you never end up in.
Keep it. It's yours.
"We have found the accused Thomas
Larson, alias Shorty Larson,"
"guilty of the following crimes"
"horse theft, theft of supplies
belonging to the Union Army"
"theft of supplies belonging
to the Confederate Army,"
wounding two vigilantes
"assault and battery on
one named Barry O'Keefe"
perjury, blackmail, robbery
escaping from a state prison
"disturbing the peace,
pandering, highway robbery."
And Shorty?
Forgery and murder.
Therefore, with the powers vested
in us by the laws of this state...
No?
We have condemned the
aforementioned Thomas Larson,
alias Shorty Larson, to hang
by the neck until dead.
May God have mercy
on his soul. Proceed.
Sorry, Shorty.
Move. Come on, let's go.
I don't know. As soon as I
hit the desert, I'm thirsty.
Burns, huh? They say people with
fair skin can't take too much.
Like that, you won't
have to carry so much.
Where we going?
Where? Where I'm going, amigo.
Over that way.
Another 100 miles
of beautiful, sunbaked sand.
Even the armies are afraid
to march through there.
Sibley's men are
retreating up there.
Canby's men are coming here.
But no one will set
foot in this hell,
except you and me
100 miles, that's a nice walk.
What was it you
told me the last time?
"İf you save your breath I feel a
man like you could manage it."
And if you won't manage it
you'll die, only slowly,
very slowly, old friend.
After you, please Start walking.
Taking a rest?
Come on, Blondie We don't
have very far to go.
Only 70 miles.
Only eight-and-a-half hours
more before sunset.
That's not too bad.
Come on.
Okay, let's eat.
That is, I'll eat.
Hmm?
Meanwhile, you can
enjoy a sunbath.
You want some water?
Drink. Drink.
Come on. Come on.
Well, Blondie. So long.
And so, Blondie
it's goodbye.
Whoa, whoa, whoa
whoa. Whoa, boy.
Easy, easy. Easy, easy.
Attaboy. That's nice.
Water. Water.
$200,000 in gold.
It's yours. Just get me water.
What's that you say?
Who the hell are you?
Carson.
My name is Bill Carson
now It's Carson.
Surprise attack.
All dead. My name is
Jackson, not Carson
Carson, Carson, yeah, yeah
Glad to meet you, Carson.
I'm Lincoln's grandfather What was
that you said about the dollars?
$200,000, all mine.
Was the Third Cavalry's
Baker has nothing.
The gold, I hid the gold
The gold is safe.
Where? Where, here? Here? Talk.
In the cemetery.
Which cemetery?
The one on Sad Hill.
There's a grave by.
Which grave? Have a name?
Have a number?
Come on, you dummy, talk.
There's no number
There's a name.
It's written.
Yes?
Water.
You talk first, huh?
I'll give you water later.
Sad Hill Cemetery. Okay.
In the grave. Okay.
But it must have a name
or a number on it, huh?
There must be a
thousand, five thousand.
Don't die, huh?
Don't die. I'll get you water.
Stay there. Don't move
I'll get you water.
Don't die until later
you son of a...
Get away from there.
He's dead.
Yeah
I'll kill you.
If you do that,
you'll always be poor,
just like the greasy
rat that you are.
If I were you, I'd keep me alive.
What did he tell you, huh?
A name.
A name on a grave.
What name?
Blondie, don't die.
Blondie, don't die
I'm your friend.
Please don't die. Please
Come on. Come on.
Blondie.
I'll help you I'll help you.
Don't move. I'll be right back.
Here's the water.
Don't die like that pig.
Hey, Blondie, here's water.
Water, Blondie.
Don't drink, don't drink
ls no good for you.
Feel better?
Blondie, what's the matter?
Please, don't die.
Hey. open up! Open up! Hurry!
Settle down. Settle down.
Who's there?
What do you mean, "Who's there?"
You think I'm the enemy?
If I were a Yankee, you wouldn't
have time to ask me that.
Come on.
Sergeant, listen to
this corporal for a moment.
Yes, sir.
Sergeant, I have a
gravely wounded man here,
if he's not dead already.
He's still alive?
Well, he seems to be.
What happened? It was a trap.
Only the two of us got away.
Name and traveling papers.
Here. Corporal Bill Carson Third
Regiment, 2nd Cavalry Squadron,
arriving from San Rafael
Is that enough?
Are you reading
when this man is dying?
Why, Corporal,
we're trying to withdraw,
and you're looking
for an infirmary?
İf you want one, you'll have to
make yourself a Yankee prisoner.
So where are we?
Near Apache Canyon.
Apache Canyon?
Apache Canyon.
Is a Mission San Antonio
around here?
Sure, 18 miles south
Take him there.
The brothers take care
of anyone who's wounded
no matter what
the color of his uniform.
And keep your eyes open,
the area is full of Yankees.
Thank you. Goodbye, Sergeant.
Take care.
I've got a very sick man here.
But we have no more beds here.
Let him have yours.
Where's Pablo Ramirez?
Father Ramirez.
He's away at the moment.
He should be back any day now.
Well, it doesn't matter.
For the moment, we take very
good care of my friend.
And may God be praised.
In case you didn't know it
God is on our side, too,
because he hates
the Yanks, huh, Blondie?
Blondie? Father,
is he still breathing?
Yes, of course.
You're heavy.
There.
All right, put a fresh
bandage on him.
Put him in my cell.
Easy.
Out, soldier Out you go. Come on.
Look out for him, please.
He's like a brother to me.
Hey, Father, I.
Father, did he speak'?
Did he say anything'?
Father, did he ask for me? Did
he speak about anything, Father'?
Oh, no, he hasn't spoken as yet.
But you mustn't worry.
He's both young and strong.
That's what's kept
him going until now.
He should regain his strength
in a very short time.
Thank you, Father Thank you.
You don't know how much
this boy's life means to me.
Thanks be to Jesus
Thanks to all of you.
Blondie.
Hey, Blondie.
The old father tells me you'll
be up and around in a few days.
You're very lucky to have me
so close when it happened.
Think if you'd been on your own.
Look, I mean, when.
When one is ill
it's good to have somebody
close by friends or relations.
Do you have parents
Blondie? A mother?
Not even a mother.
No one?
You're all alone, huh?
Like me, Blondie.
We're all alone in the world.
I have you, you have me.
Only for a little while, I mean.
It had to happen now.
What a dirty,
rotten trick of fate.
We could have all that
money in our hands.
I must tell you
the truth, Blondie.
In my place, you would
do the same thing.
It's all over for you now.
There's nothing
anyone can do anymore.
God help me. It's my fault.
Mine, mine, mine, mine
I'll tell you one thing, Blondie.
If I knew that
my last hour had come, I swear
in my place, in your place
I would do the same thing.
I would tell about the gold.
Yes. Yes, I would
I'd tell the name on the grave.
After all, what good is the
money to you if you're dead'?
I know the name of the cemetery,
but you know how many
graves there are there?
Please, Blondie.
Please, have a little, huh?
Here. Coffee.
Please, tell me the name
on the grave.
If I get my hands
on the $200,000
I'll always honor your memory.
I swear, I'll always
honor your memory.
Come closer.
Tell me.
Why, you dirty...
I'll sleep better,
knowing my good
friend is by my side,
to protect me.
"Tuco, water."
Well, here's water.
But if I get that name from
you I'll give you water.
All right, you dirty skunk
get your ass off the bed.
Come on, come on
the party's over.
The wagon is all ready to go.
From the way the wounded
are pouring into this place,
we better get
the hell out of here
before we get
caught up in the war.
Tuco, Father Ramirez is back.
Yeah.
This is something
I have to look into.
It'll only take
a minute. Get moving.
Where, this way? Yes.
Hey, Pablo.
Don't you recognize me?
It's me, Tuco.
Let me embrace you.
I don't know the right thing.
I was just passing by here
I said to myself,
"I wonder if my brother
remembers his brother."
Did I do wrong?
It doesn't matter
I'm very happy.
You have seen me, Tuco.
Yeah, well, I'm very glad I came.
Oh, my uniform It's a long story.
But let's talk about you
It's more important.
You look very well.
A bit thin, perhaps, but
you were always thin
eh, Pablito?
What about our parents?
Only now do you think of them.
To begin after nine years.
Nine years?
So it's nine years Nine years.
Our mother has been dead
a long time now.
Our father died
only a few days ago.
That's why I was away.
He asked for you to be there
but there was only me.
And you?
Outside of evil, what else
have you managed to do?
It seems to me you once
had a wife someplace.
Not one, lots of them.
One here, one there,
wherever I found them.
Go on, preach me
a sermon, Pablo.
What good would that be?
Just keep on
the way you're going.
Go away.
And the Lord have
mercy on your soul.
Sure, I'll go, I'll go.
While I'm waiting for the
Lord to remember me,
I, Tuco Ramirez,
brother of Brother Ramirez
will tell you something.
You think you're
better than I am.
Where we came from if one
didn't want to die of poverty,
one became a priest or a bandit.
You chose your way I chose mine.
Mine was harder!
You talk about Mother and Father.
You remember, when you left to
become a priest, I stayed behind.
I must have been 10, 12, I don't
remember which, but I stayed.
I tried, but it was no good.
Now I will tell you something.
You became a priest because you were
too much of a coward to do what I do.
Tuco.
Please forgive me, brother.
My belly's full.
Nice guy, my brother.
I didn't tell you my brother
was in charge here?
Everything. Like the pope almost.
He's in charge in Rome Yeah,
yeah, my brother he say to me,
"Stay, brother Don't go home."
We never see each other.
"Here there's plenty to eat and drink.
Bring your friend, too."
Whenever we see each other
he never lets me go.
It's always the same story.
My brother, he is crazy about me.
That's so. Even a tramp like
me, no matter what happens.
I know there's a brother somewhere
who will never refuse me
a bowl of soup.
Sure.
Well, after a meal there's
nothing like a good cigar.
Here's the Sierra Magdalena.
Going this way,
we cross the Rio Grande.
That sure is a long way.
Here to the northwest
through all of Texas.
After that... Then what?
When we get there I'll tell you.
You're not worried, are you?
Those men aren't worried about
anything anymore, are they?
But since I'm alive
and I've noticed
we'll be crossing Yankee and
Confederate lines a few times,
I thought you might
tell me where we're going.
Towards $200,000.
Is that good enough for you?
Hey, wake up, you.
The troops are coming Come on.
Blue or gray?
They're gray like us. Let's say
"hello" to them and then get going.
Hoorah! Hoorah for
the Confederacy!
Hoorah! Down with General Grant!
Hoorah for General
What's his name?
Lee! Lee!
God is with us because
he hates the Yanks, too!
God's not on our side
'cause he hates idiots also.
Hut, two, three, four
Hut, two, three, four.
Prisoners of war, forward.
March!
Halt!
Left face!
Form a single file. Move!
Jonathan Frost!
Present!
Richard McGilley!
Nathaniel Sullivan!
Present
Robert Clark!
Sam Richmond!
Present.
Bill Carson!
I said Bill Carson!
Hey, Blondie,
isn't that Angel Eyes?
All right,
what's he doing, sleeping?
Bill Carson!
Yeah, and you
better be Bill Carson.
Bill Carson!
Yeah, that's me.
Please, Carson
answer "present"
What are you, deaf'?
Now suppose you
say "present," Carson.
I like big fat men like you.
When they fall,
they make more noise
and sometimes they never get up
Wallace.
That's enough.
Sergeant!
The captain wants
to see you right away.
Be sure these two
get good treatment.
Hey, Blondie, did you hear that?
Good treatment.
Yeah.
For the last time, Sergeant
I'm telling you, I want the
prisoners treated as prisoners.
No more brutality.
There's hundreds of
prisoners out there
and only a few men to guard them.
Now what am I supposed to do?
I have to have respect.
I think that you'll manage
to gain their respect
by treating them better.
Are our men treated that well
in Andersonville camp?
I don't give a God damn
what they do in Andersonville.
While I'm in charge here the
prisoners are not to be tortured,
or cheated or murdered.
That an accusation?
Sergeant, gangrene is eating
my leg away, not my eyes.
I know the prisoners here are
being robbed systematically.
I know there's scum around who
are bivouacked near the camp
waiting for someone
to deliver this loot.
But as long as I'm commandant I won't
permit any such trickery. Am I clear?
Yes.
Just as long as
you're the commandant.
Yes, Sergeant.
I know this leg means
I won't last very long,
but I pray I can manage to have
enough time to amass evidence
and bring to a court-martial
all those who discredit and
dishonor the uniform of the Union.
I wish you luck.
You and the others better
lay low for a few days.
No, I'll keep this. You go
Wallace will let you know
Wallace, bring me Carson.
Right.
Listen, Angel Eyes said for
us to lay low for a few days,
but we'll keep close enough
to keep an eye on things.
Come on, saddle your horses.
Get in.
Come on in, Tuco
Don't be bashful.
There's no formalities here.
It's been a long time.
You're hungry Sit down, eat.
I knew it, I knew it.
The minute I saw you
I said to myself,
"Look at that pig Angel Eyes."
"I'll bet he got
himself an easyjob"
"and he never forgets a friend."
I never forget old friends, Tuco.
Right.
It's good to see
old friends again.
Good.
Especially when they've
come from so far away
and have so much to talk about.
And you do have a lot to
talk about haven't you?
You were captured
near Fort Craig.
Well, if you were
with Sibley, that means then
that you were coming
from Santa Fe.
Was it hard crossing the desert?
Mmm-Hmm. Very hard.
Especially if you don't
have anything to drink.
Why are you going under the
name of Bill Carson now?
One name is as good as another.
Not wise to use your own name.
Like you.
I'll bet they don't
call you Angel Eyes.
Sergeant Angel Eyes.
Like a little music
with your meal, Tuco?
Music? Yes, it's very good,
very good for the digestion.
Bill Carson's a fake name, huh?
That fake, too'?
Bill Carson's name's
written in it.
Have some.
It's Bill Carson's tobacco.
Was Carson dead or alive
when you found him?
What'd he tell you
about the money?
I don't,
I don't know what
you're talking about.
More feeling.
You can sure consider yourself
much luckier than your pal.
Wallace will punch your friend
as long as the song goes.
So many of us have
had a session in there.
How's your digestion now?
You'd better talk.
I have nothing to tell you.
Play that fiddle, you.
Enough. Enough. I talk. I talk.
What did he say about the money?
It's buried in a grave.
Where?
Sad Hill.
Sad Hill Cemetery.
Which grave'?
I don't know.
I don't know, I tell you.
Blondie. Ask Blondie.
He knows the name on the grave.
Put those clothes on.
Why?
We're going for a ride.
Where?
To find $200,000.
I know the name of
the cemetery now,
and you know
the name of the grave.
You're not gonna give me
the same treatment?
Would you talk?
No, probably not.
That's what I thought.
Not that you're any
tougher than Tuco,
but you're smart enough to know
that talking won't save you.
And Tuco, is he.
No. Not yet.
But he's in very good hands.
You've changed partners but
you still got the same deal.
I'm not greedy.
I'm only taking half.
There's two of us.
It should make it
easier than just one.
Yeah.
Hold it. That's it, don't move.
Now don't breathe
Still. That's it.
Got it. Thank you.
Hey, Corporal,
afraid he'll get lost?
Where's the rebel going?
To hell, with a rope around his
neck and a price on his head.
$3,000, friend.
That's a lot of money for a head
I'll bet they didn't even pay
you a penny for your arm.
I told you once, friend
if I ever get you down
you're gonna need a lot of
help to get up again. A lot.
You're a lot luckier
than that one there.
You get some trouble, rope
and you're all finished.
And there isn't any partner
this time to shoot you down.
If your friends
stay out in the damp
they're liable to
catch a cold, aren't they?
Or a bullet.
Hear that, boys?
Come on out here.
Since we're all going
in the same direction,
might as well go together.
One, two, three, four
five, six.
Six. Perfect number.
Isn't three the perfect number?
Yeah. But I got six
more bullets in my gun.
Sure would like to
put your paw on it, huh?
I would like to piss It's rough.
I've been shaken up on this
train nearly ten hours now.
You smell like a pig already,
but let's not try
to make things any worse.
Get going-
I can't while you're watching me.
You made a lot of noise
my friend, huh?
You don't want to break our friendship huh?
Well, I'll break it.
Ha.
Take your places.
Ready!
Aim! Fire!
Slim, take care of the horses
I've been looking for
you for eight months.
Whenever I should've
had a gun in my right hand.
I thought of you.
Now I find you in exactly
the position that suits me.
I had lots of time to learn
how to shoot with my left.
When you have to shoot
shoot. Don't talk.
Every gun makes its own tune.
It's perfect timing Large One.
Clem, follow him.
Just a minute.
I'll be right there.
Just give me a little time to
get dressed and I'll open up.
Put your drawers on
and take your gun off.
Hey, Blondie.
How the hell did you get
out of that pigsty?
My own way. I'm here with
your old friend, Angel Eyes.
You talked, you traitor
You talked.
No, I didn't talk.
If I did, I probably
wouldn't be here now.
You, me.
So only you know
your half of the secret?
Mmm-hmm.
Blondie
I'm very happy you're working
with me, and we're together again.
I get dressed I kill
him and be right back.
Oh, listen, I forgot to mention,
he's not alone.
There's five of them.
Five?
Yeah, five of them.
So that's why you came to Tuco?
It doesn't matter.
I'll kill them all.
They shot him at close range.
Well, look who's here.
The other one will be along.
They'll come looking for us.
Watch out.
There's two of them.
I want that blond alive.
You, back there.
Come on, let's go.
Were you gonna die alone?
Halt!
Hey, Blondie.
Angel Eyes is mine, huh?
All right.
See you soon.
Idiots.
It's for you.
How peaceful and quiet, amigo.
Like a cemetery for instance?
There should be
a bridge across that river.
We'd better wait for nightfall.
Trust in me, Blondie.
I got a good sense
of where I'm going.
Tuco has taken you this far.
I will take you all the way...
Gentlemen.
Tell the captain. Yes, sir.
Come along now Follow me.
We found them near
the perimeter, sir.
Where do you hail from?
Illinois.
And you?
I'm with him.
Any reason for
being around here?
We want to enlist, General.
You better learn
to distinguish rank
I'm a captain.
Get the hell out.
It sure as hell might be you
today, so go write your will.
Yes, sir.
So you want to enlist?
You gotta take
a test to prove it.
Well, show me.
You've got a career.
At the least, I'd say
you'll make colonel.
Reaiiy? Sure.
Like it says in the manual,
"You've got every qualification",
"to become an expert
in the use of weapons."
For this, sir, is
the most potent weapon in war.
The fighting spirit's
in this bottle.
Volunteers.
You want to enlist?
Let's go. Come on,
gentlemen. Come on.
The shooting hasn't begun yet.
We still have time.
Whoever has the most liquor
to get the soldiers drunk
and send them to be
slaughtered is the winner.
We and the ones over on the other side of
the river only have one thing in common.
All of us reek of alcohol.
What did you say your name was?
And you?
Names don't matter.
Yes, because soon you can join
the gallant heroes
of Branson Bridge.
We have two attacks a day.
Two attacks a day'?
Sure, the Rebs have
decided that damn bridge
is the key to this whole area.
Stupid, useless bridge.
Flyspeck on headquarters' maps.
And headquarters has declared we
must take that ridiculous flyspeck
even if all of us are killed.
Otherwise,
the key will get rusty
and just be a spot on the wall.
And that's not all.
Both sides want
the bridge intact.
Intact is how the South wants
it, and we want it intact, too.
You'll all turn to dust
but one thing is sure, boys, Branson
Bridge will stand unbroken.
Is it bad to speak the
way I do to volunteers?
I've done a lot worse
I've done it.
I've blown it up. Boom.
In here, I've destroyed it all.
It's a court-martial
offense to imagine
to dream of blowing it up
A serious crime.
Even to think of destroying
that bridge is just...
Why not really
blow it up, Captain?
Yeah, Captain, it's nothing. Let's
scare the hell out of them.
I've been dreaming about it
I've even worked out a plan.
I sure have.
The best time is
after the attack
when there's a truce
to get the wounded.
If I could do it, I could
save many thousands of men.
But what I lack is the guts.
They're beginning their daily
slaughter right on time.
Captain, all companies
are awaiting your orders.
Be right there.
Let's go.
All right, friends, come along
and enjoy the spectacle.
Companies, report!
Company B ready!
Company E ready!
Company D ready!
Companies, forwards!
Hey, Blondie
it looks like the captain is really
asking for a bullet in his guts.
Yeah
I've never seen so many
men wasted so badly.
I have a feeling it's really
gonna be a good, long battle.
Blondie? Huh?
The money's on the other
side of the river.
Where?
Amigo, I said the other side
and that's enough.
But while the Confederates are
there we can't get across.
What would happen if somebody
were to blow up that bridge?
Yeah.
Then these idiots would go
somewhere else to fight.
Maybe.
Doctor, quick
the captain's wounded.
Hurry, a stretcher.
Easy. Easy now.
Get things ready.
A little of this will help.
Take a slug of this, Captain.
Keep your ears open.
- What are you doing?
- No, leave me alone.
Blondie, you realize
we might be risking our lives.
Yeah, and if I get killed
you'll never get your hands
on all that beautiful money.
Yeah, Tuco
it sure would be a pity.
Doc.
Doctor.
Could you help me
live a little more?
I expect good news.
Why don't we tell each other
our half of the secret?
Why don't we?
You go first.
No, I think it's better that,
you start.
All right.
The name of the cemetery is.
Sad Hill. Now it's your turn.
The name on the grave is.
Arch Stanton.
Arch Stanton? Are you sure?
Yeah, sure, I'm sure.
It'll be a lot easier with that.
Two can dig a lot
quicker than one.
You're not digging.
If you shoot me, you won't
see a cent of that money
I'll tell you why.
'Cause there's nothing in there.
Why, you son of a.
You thought I'd trust you?
$200,000 is a lot of money.
We're gonna have to earn it.
How?
I'll write the name
on the bottom of this stone.
The gun.
You pig. You want to get me killed?
When'd you unload it?
Last night.
You see, in this world there's
two kinds of people, my friend,
those with loaded guns
and those who dig.
You dig.
Where?
Here.
There's no name on it!
There's no name here either.
You see, that's what
Bill Carson told me.
It was the grave marked "Unknown"
right beside Arch Stanton.
Go ahead.
Blondie! It's all ours, Blondie.
You're joking, Blondie.
You wouldn't play
a joke on me like that.
It's no joke. It's a rope, Tuco.
Now I want you to stand up there
and put your head in that noose.
Well, now, seems
just like old times.
Four for you
and four.
Four for me.
Hey, Blondie.
Sorry, Tuco.
Blondie.
Blondie!
Hey, Blondie!
You know what you are'?
Just a dirty son of a bitch!