Aah!
Wait a minute. He ain't dead!
Let's go! Let's go!
Frank! Get out!
Come on, Frank.
Jesus! Let's get
the hell out of here!
Frank!
Hey, come back! Come back, God damn it!
Come back! Don't leave!
But on this joyous day,
one sobering question,
one haunting question remains.
Are they all back?
Still listed as
missing in action...
Are 2,500 American men.
Are any of them
still being held prisoner?
For the families of those men,
the vietnamese war
will never be over...
Until that question
is answered.
We're waiting
for the first p.O.W.
To emerge from the plane.
All of America waiting,
and in particular,
his family is waiting.
We'll see these heroes
emerging momentarily.
We're waiting now for,
on this momentous day,
the end of the war
officially for them.
This day, march 7, 1973.
The first one coming off now!
He looks a little thin,
but considering
what he's been through,
he looks very good from here.
He's approaching
his family now.
We're waiting
for others to come off.
There's the official reunion.
The war is over for him.
For other American families,
the agonizing will continue...
Until they find out the
fate of their missing sons.
Daddy!
Daddy.
I'm scared.
Can I sleep with you tonight?
Colonel rhodes,
I sympathize, but...
I don't want your sympathy!
I want you to help me
find my son.
But don't you understand?
There's nothing I can do.
There are 2,500 men
still unaccounted for.
There have been over
400 live sightings...
Of Americans held
against their will.
I've heard the numbers.
There's nothing I can do.
That's all I ever
heard in Washington.
Nobody can do anything.
That's why I came to Bangkok.
Look, you didn't
hear this from me,
but there are a couple
of men here in Bangkok...
Who claim they've seen
American p.O.W.S in Laos.
I'll put you
in contact with them.
I think my son's being
held prisoner in Laos,
but I need proof.
Get my son's signature
on the back of this picture.
on the back of that picture.
Get him to
write his name on it.
If I get your son's name here,
I want a lots of money.
Yeah, o.K.
Hey, you.
Hey!
Oh, boy. There's that
old colonel m.I.A. Again.
Senator. Hello, colonel.
How are you? Fine, thanks.
Sorry we haven't
got time today,
but give me a ring in my office,
I'd be happy to talk to you.
Thank you. Sorry.
Colonel rhodes, I can't
help you with your son.
I'm trying to find food
for these new refugees.
Talk to that guy over there.
He'll help. Good luck.
Thank you very much.
That your boy. He
prisoner in camp in Laos.
I smuggled the picture out.
That's him.
I know my son's being held
someplace in northern Laos,
but I need to know
exactly where.
I need a thorough recon
of the area.
Man, that's tough.
Like I told you, I can go
into Laos and north Vietnam.
I've got the connections.
But it'll take a lot of
money to find your son.
Don, hi!
How are you, Jason? Good. Good.
What do you have for me?
You know... If they
find out about this,
they'll retire me, just
like they retired you.
Yeah, yeah, o.K.
I suppose someone could
call this treason.
No. No, thanks.
It's a prison camp in Laos.
Look at the paddy dikes.
There's your proof, Jason.
There's your proof... 111.
You go get your boy.
All right. Now, where was I?
Hey, blaster, tell us about that time
you almost got wasted by that big wave.
I've told you guys
that story a thousand times.
I don't remember how I lied
the last time.
It doesn't matter. It's
still going to be bitchin'.
All right, all right.
The surf on the north shore comes
up real fast, out of nowhere.
You're out there in the
line-up having a good time,
and then it happens...
a life-threatening experience.
And then? Yeah. What
happens, blaster?
This photograph was taken somewhere
close to where Frank is being held.
I'm not saying
Frank is one of them,
but those two are Americans.
They're much too tall
to be vietnamese.
Average vietnamese man
is about 5'2-1/2".
Those two are Americans.
And that's supposed
to be Frank?
That is Frank.
I bought too many fakes
over the last 10 years.
That definitely is Frank.
Been a p.O.W. 10 years
in that shithole?
Listen, Frank is alive.
You got that? My son is alive.
Take a look at that.
That's a high-altitude
photograph taken from a sr-71.
Look at it closely.
See? Right here
in the paddy dikes.
The three lines there.
"111."
That's your old
lrrp team designation...
1st battalion, 11th infantry.
Recon team Arizona.
Don't you see it?
It's plain as day. There.
Yes. Right here.
That's three lines
in the ground.
It could be anything.
You know it isn't though,
don't you?
That's a message from my son.
You know that.
Hello.
Hi.
Mrs. Wilkes?
Yeah, that's right.
I'm Jason rhodes.
I phoned this morning.
Yeah, I know who you are.
Listen, my husband doesn't
want to talk to you.
I phoned him this morning,
and he said he did.
Yeah, well, not anymore.
Why don't you do me a
favor and go away?
Not until I see your husband.
You've got no right to be here.
It's taken me 10 years...
To get that goddamned war
out of his head.
Looks to me like
it's still in his head.
Ohh...
That's very deep.
Where were you all the days...
He spent staring at the walls?
Hey, wilkes!
Goddamn you!
Why did you send
your wife out here?
Don't you have
the guts to come out?
Leave him alone!
My son needs you! At least
look at our photographs.
Oh, please. Please, don't.
Wilkesy.
I'll handle this now.
I don't like your tactics.
But I'll listen
because of Frank.
Blaster.
Wilkesy.
Why didn't you stay in touch?
Why didn't you?
I don't know.
It's weird, ain't it?
How did they find you?
I don't know. Came
looking and found me.
Then we found you.
Thanks a lot, blast.
It's good to see you, man.
There are compounds
all over northern Laos.
There are choppers
we left behind.
We'll use them to get
into the p.O.W. Camp.
They're used all the time,
so they should be
well maintained.
Excuse me, please.
You going out? Mm-hmm.
Little early, isn't it?
I want to make happy hour.
Yeah.
Want to come along?
No. I think I'll
stay home tonight.
No kidding.
What's that mean?
It means, no kidding.
I don't feel like going out.
Well, you never do. He never
feels like doing anything.
That's not true.
Every night it's the same.
He puts on his headphones
and listens to that crap.
That crap happens
to be George gershwin.
Whatever. It's like
I'm not even here.
He's like a turtle
hiding in his shell.
He hasn't taken off those
sunglasses in six years.
I've given up trying
to figure him out.
Maybe you should take
him back to Vietnam.
He doesn't give a damn
about anything here.
It was nice meeting
you, colonel.
Nice meeting you.
If he did go,
how much would he be paid?
Nothing in dollars.
I haven't flown
a helicopter in a long time.
I'd probably get
somebody killed.
There's unfinished business
over there, major Johnson.
Not mine.
Is this the distinguished
flying cross?
Yeah.
How'd you get that?
Ah... Pulling a thud pilot
out of Laos.
Must have been
more to it than that.
Not really.
Tell me about it.
I'd like to hear it.
I got him out after a lot of
good people went down trying.
It was a hell of a day.
We'd already lost
a good man named Hendricks,
couple of f-4 jocks,
even Sandy low lead.
Lost a lot of good friends.
How many?
Oh, I don't remember.
It just seemed like everybody.
You lost 11 men and 9 aircraft.
You were shot down first, and you
volunteered to go back for that pilot.
Why?
If you know that, you tell me.
Because it was my job,
that's why!
We couldn't let good men
die for nothing!
That's why we're
going back now.
Wait! Back up!
You cannot lay
that guilt on me! No!
I'm sorry, but
the answer is no.
What do you want from me?
I run half this hospital.
I lead a good life here.
I'm off to Bermuda next week...
And not off to
some fantasy war.
I cannot save
the goddamn world!
At ease, major.
Macgregor oil.
Mr. Macgregor, please.
Mr. Macgregor's office.
This is Jason rhodes calling.
Jason, how's it going?
We're on our way.
How many?
Three. One chopper
pilot turned me down.
Is two enough?
I'll do it with one
if I have to.
I can't turn back now.
Is there anything
more I can do?
Just keep the cash coming.
I'll get our boys back.
Jason, what about sailor?
He's in Houston.
I'm going there now.
The replica of the p.O.W.
Camp is ready.
Great. Keep in touch.
All right. Talk to you.
Don't worry. He can't see you.
It's a two-way mirror.
Your friend, sailor,
blowtorched
a local kingpin biker.
We're holding him on our
witness protection program.
He come in here with a
grenade around his neck.
I don't think his
bread's quite done.
Jesus.
I had trouble
tracking you down.
You wandered around
the whole country.
Frank mentioned you
in his letters.
He said you were the
best man in the unit.
Yeah? What the hell
happened to you?
I'm so far beyond
that shit now.
I get energy from the air.
I talk to polar bears.
I converse with paramecium.
Man, I fuck nuclear waste!
Shit.
You guys will be
using real grenades.
They took mine.
Hey, look, asshole.
This is not
a biker's acid trip.
This is a precise
military operation.
Frank was the best man
in anybody's unit.
I've got enough brain
cells to remember that.
You've got to
give me a shot, man.
You've got to.
Hey, wilkesy.
Aw, man. Come on.
Sailor?
Ya-hoo!
My man! Blaster!
You haven't changed a bit!
Master wilkes!
Where's your grenade?
I used that for
an emergency enema.
Maybe I do have a little
unfinished business.
Besides, this guy wouldn't
last 10 minutes without me.
You ain't bullshitting.
Get aboard.
Gentlemen, this is it.
Exact replica
of the p.O.W. Camp.
Who built it?
Macgregor's father.
Get your gear.
Stow it in that large tent.
I'll meet you here
in an hour for supper.
Mr. Ky, supper in one hour.
Thank you.
Mr. Scott, at ease.
So, who the hell is that?
Good evening.
Hi. How are you?
Mr. Ky, you can serve
when you're ready.
Good evening.
As you were.
Since military courtesy isn't practical
here, we'll dispense with it.
This is Kevin Scott.
He's well-trained in weapons
and training techniques.
And this is Mr. ky.
We'll be eating vietnamese
food from now on.
We don't want to smell
like Americans.
Any questions?
Good.
How long were you there?
I wasn't.
Too young.
Is he going with us?
Served in fourth recon marines.
Served?
I was discharged for
striking a radio operator...
Who fell asleep at his post.
You're worried that I have
no combat experience.
You're right.
There's no way of proving...
I won't fail in combat.
But you can't prove
that I will, either.
This is gonna be...
A whole lot of fun
with this one.
Gentlemen.
Thank you for coming.
I knew you would come,
'cause you men
have got what it takes.
Molded over a little,
but you still got it.
There's a bond
between you men...
As strong as the bond
between my son and me.
Of course, men who faced
death in battle...
Share the strongest bond.
You men seem to have
a strong sense of loyalty...
Because you're thought
of as criminals...
Because of Vietnam.
You know why?
Hmm?
Because you lost.
And in this country,
that's like going bankrupt.
You're out of business.
They want to forget about you.
You cost too much
and didn't turn a profit.
That's why they
won't get our buddies.
There's no gain in it.
We know the books
are still in the red.
The politicians know, too.
The same politicians...
That never lost a son
in Vietnam. Not one!
They say they've negotiated
for 10 years,
well...
The other side's not buying.
And while the politicians
sit on their asses,
I'm asking you
to lay yours on the line.
Again.
Because, gentlemen...
We're the only hope
those p.O.W.S have.
So, we're going back there.
And this time...
This time,
nobody can dispute...
The rightness
of what we're doing.
Hit the dirt!
Get down!
You're all dead.
Not quite, sir.
Go, colonel! Go, go, go!
Go, colonel. Go, go, go!
Go! Go! Go!
Move it! Move it! Move it!
Fuckin' pimp!
Go! Go! Go!
Blaster, go! Come on, baby, go!
Come on, man.
Come on, sailor! Take it home!
Come on, Scott.
Go! Go, sailor, go!
Come on, rookie!
All right, come on!
Go! Go, sailor!
Hit it!
What are you doing?
You don't ever quit, boy.
Not when it's for real.
All right. That's enough.
Aw, shit!
Damn!
Little too much civilian life.
Pull it in!
O.K.! Move your butts!
Double time!
Good shooting, colonel.
Blaster, your elbow down.
Yeah, yeah.
Sailor, stop spraying!
Conserve your ammo!
You haven't got
one in the kill zone!
These hands were made to fly.
Tell the enemy when he
blows your head off!
Kill the enemy!
Don't lose it, mister!
You kill the fuckin' enemy,
asshole!
Sailor, I could teach...
An undisciplined brawler
like you a lesson.
Make your move, boy.
Scott! A word, please.
Scott, these men
are seasoned veterans.
They can't be treated
like raw recruits.
You have to earn their respect.
Yes, sir.
Wilkesy's
claustrophobic as shit.
He was the tunnel
rat in our unit.
Goes down this tunnel...
To check for weapon storage.
Turns out there's
somebody down there.
He knifes them both
in the dark.
Then the mortar shells hit.
He's stuck until
we dig him out.
Wilkes lights a match...
To move the bodies off of him.
He'd knifed some
woman and her kid.
Killed them deader than shit.
Jesus.
Wilkes starts freaking.
We can hear him screaming,
but he has to stay
with those corpses...
Until we dig him out.
You come in low under
his line of sight.
You leap, taking him down,
placing your hand over his
nose, pulling his face away.
At the base of his skull,
to the right of the spine,
into what the Chinese
call the "wind gate,"
you insert, scramble the
brains... instant rag doll.
Most human problems
can be solved...
By a charge of high-explosives.
In today's lesson,
we'll learn to set what we
call a series or a break.
Follow me. My personal
best is a break of six.
The idea is to create
a linked series of disasters.
Figure evasive moves
from each blast,
and plant your next tomato.
Just as we're coming up here
with a column,
they'd trip charge number one,
an m-26 trip grenade.
Boom!
Column splits in two.
Half here, half there.
Over here, number two will
set their ass on fire.
They think they're safe.
They get away!
Boom! Number three
blows their balls off.
Number four!
They come over here.
They find
a two-pound charge of c-4.
Boom!
Number five.
Quick-fuse grenade.
Not a big bang,
but it does a good job.
Anybody left will think,
"we've got to make it."
They're coming out,
and they're moving,
and then they run
into charge six.
Claymore mine. End of story.
Congratulations, sailor.
You wasted a prisoner.
He's a collaborator.
You all right?
Can't sleep, huh?
For years I couldn't
sleep after Korea.
My nightmares all had to do
with the chosin reservoir.
The ground there
was so frozen...
We couldn't bury our dead.
Piled them on trucks and
lashed them against the tanks.
For years I'd wake up with those
frozen faces staring at me.
Did it ever go away?
No.
I finally made friends
with them though.
No.
Left.
Left, right, left.
No.
Get together, guys!
Gentlemen!
The object
of the next exercise...
get from here to the bridge...
Without being tagged by wilkes.
God damn it! Shit.
Sneaky little shit.
Aw, shit. I'm dead.
Wilkesy, I'm supposed... shit!
Aah!
Shit!
Fuck, man.
Come on!
Come on. Come on. Come on.
You can make it. Come across.
You people got caught
'cause you got careless!
I told you...
All right, wilkesy!
The object of the exercise
was not to get caught!
That guy's elevator
doesn't go to the top.
Agent orange.
No. Red wine and uppers.
That's why he's called sailor.
He'd take red wine and
uppers, and just sail away.
How come he wears that grenade?
Sailor says if life got shitty,
he'd pull the pin
and see what's next.
Wilkesy, remember that song?
Get down, boogie,
remember? Yeah!
Boogie! Come on.
Come on, remember that?
Come on, wilkesy.
Hey, blaster.
Yeah! Come on!
Come on, Johnson! Get out here.
Come on, Johnson!
Go for it!
Do it, boy!
¶ I'll stay with you,
darling, now ¶
¶ I'll stay with you
till my seeds are dried up ¶
agent orange.
All agent orange.
¶ ...waiting so long ¶
¶ to be where I'm going ¶
¶ in the sunshine
of your love ¶¶
o.K., Curtis.
Follow the leader.
Sounds good to me.
Close it up!
Let's go! Fly this thing!
Get your Sierra
together, my man.
Kiss my Sierra, buddy.
You were the ace of the base.
Getting too old
for this shit, buddy?
Looking good, guys.
Looking good.
Left, right, left.
Left, left, left, right, left.
Son of a bitch! Shit!
What the fuck am I doing here?
Come on! Don't quit!
Fuck you!
We have to work
together... everybody!
I don't believe
this motherfuckin' shit!
I've been workin'
my fuckin' ass off,
and I don't need
no wet-nosed asshole...
Screaming in my face!
Back off!
Curtis! Let the shit ride!
What matters is
we're on the same team!
We have to work together!
We are the team, asshole.
We were there, not you.
Now, asshole.
Right now!
Sailor, colonel rhodes
was wrong.
I can't earn your respect,
'cause you have no
respect for yourself.
Boy...
You just bought the whole
can of whoop-ass.
Come on, sailor!
Kick his ass, sailor!
Boy, using that oriental
martial bullshit on me...
Is going to get real expensive.
Get up! Come on, hero!
That's enough, sailor!
Get up, boy! Come on!
You can't keep me
from this mission!
Why are you getting up, marine?
Stay down, man.
Stay down, little fucker!
No. No!
Why you wanna go die, boy?
Why?
I'll tell you why.
His father's
missing in action...
Shot down in Vietnam,
that's why.
Blaster, when I come
over the treeline...
At 0300,
that's your cue to blow up
the radio tower,
then the bridge to cut off
reinforcements from the village.
Boom.
Mister Scott,
that's your cue...
To neutralize guard tower "a".
All right, charts, Johnson...
You pick up blaster after
we've snatched the prisoners.
Major Johnson,
you pick up Scott.
O.K., blaster,
this is the big ride.
All right, sailor!
Gentlemen, study every
inch of this compound.
It's an exact reproduction
of the p.O.W. Camp in Laos.
It's imperative
that we're in and out...
In less than three minutes.
The lives of everyone
involved may depend on it.
We're rehearsing so we can
do this operation in our sleep.
We gotta be in and out
of there in 3 minutes.
10 days time, we'll have
a live fire exercise.
Look, we have been pursuing
diplomatic negotiations...
For the release of all p.O.W.S,
if there are any.
An armed incursion now...
Would undermine
those negotiations.
Negotiations?
It's been 10 years!
They'll be dead
by the time you negotiate!
Damn it, as my friend,
call rhodes
and drop this project!
Look, I didn't
want it to get this far.
You know, they're prepared
to take serious measures...
Against your company...
I.R.S. Audits,
anti-trust suits...
Fuck you, art.
The men we're going after
will be in rough shape...
Something like these men.
They may not be able to walk.
They may not want to walk.
They will be shattered...
Both physically...
And emotionally.
After all these years, they may
not be able to speak English.
Remember, gentlemen,
everything we do tonight...
Is motivated by them.
It looked like
the fourth of July!
It was beautiful!
It was gorgeous!
Gentlemen!
Mr. Macgregor.
I wanted to
thank you personally.
After watching you,
I know Jason's chosen
the right men for the job.
And as a token of my esteem,
a check and
pocket money for Bangkok.
Nah. That's all right.
Take it.
Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
Do you ever regret
letting Frank go, Jason?
He was in the service. There
wasn't any question of him going.
Couldn't your Washington contacts
get him stationed elsewhere?
When there's a war,
the rhodes fight it.
We lost almost the whole
family at gettysburg one day.
That's all we're good at.
Haven't always been real
good at fighting, either.
A lot of us been killed.
But we're always there.
You know, Jason...
I'd give everything
I have... everything...
For just one hour with him.
See if that's our truck.
There's a c.I.A. Man
if I've ever seen one.
Johnson, rhodes...
You're in a shit pile
of trouble.
We're confiscating
your weapons.
My orders are to put you
in jail... a Bangkok jail.
I don't want to put
an old soldier like you in jail,
but damn it,
this scheme of yours is crazy.
Shit!
You'd best be
on the next plane home.
And don't go back to the hotel.
They're waiting
for your ass there, too.
Since our government's
confiscated our weapons,
I'm not going to ask
you gentlemen to go any further.
It's over!
I'm not giving up
to those bastards.
My son Frank's waiting for me.
I'll go in there
with a pocketknife!
You people do whatever
you want, o.K.?
There's got to be someplace
in Bangkok to get guns.
No. Up north in
the golden triangle.
We need money for that!
What about the c.I.A.?
Who cares? It's
a total wipe-out!
We've got money.
That's right.
The money macgregor gave us.
Everybody give it up.
Come on, all of it.
That's all I got.
What you been doin'?
Seeing the sights.
Wilkes, we're going
to need transportation.
4-wheel drive?
Preferably.
Buy it or borrow it?
Steal the fucker!
Left. Left!
Hey!
Some other fella's moved in
on your man's drug operation.
Even moved into his house.
We can find
him down the street.
Colonel rhodes.
Sit down.
Jiang, how are you?
I understand you've
had some trouble.
The misfortunes of
the narcotics world.
I barely escaped
with my life...
And nothing else.
Do you still have men
to take us into northern Laos?
I'll take you myself.
I'm weary of this
life of uselessness.
Jiang, we need weapons.
We need cheap weapons now.
We lost ours in
Bangkok, understand?
No, we don't have time to eat.
I'll bet you'll approve
of our cuisine.
At this restaurant,
you can eat well or poorly,
depending on how
you order your meal.
What does monsieur recommend?
All our cuisine is exceptional.
But there are
seasonal specials.
$5,000.
$4,000.
$3,000.
These dishes require...
24-hour notice.
Monsieur, these entrees
are too rich for our blood.
Come on.
Uncle mich!
Brother bud!
Sorry. The wrong department.
Bargain basement's this way.
How much for the beer?
Compliments of the house.
Ah, yes.
I'll give you the whole
lot for let's say...
No.
$6,000.
Let's say $4,000.
You're cheap.
Garbage.
Thank you.
High and to the right.
Hit. Hit.
Hit.
Gentlemen,
these are my daughters.
They will accompany
us into Laos.
Unfortunately, I have
no sons to offer you.
They were killed by Laotian
red guards during opium run.
However, colonel rhodes,
I am certain my daughters
will prove themselves worthy.
O.K., let's go, gentlemen.
We're back.
I'm just trying to stay warm.
I swear to God.
Jiang.
What happened here?
Y pres.
What?
What's he talking about?
It's French.
A town in France.
The first place the Germans
ever used mustard gas.
Oh, yeah.
Yellow rain.
Hmong people fight vietnamese.
Vietnamese hate them.
Laotian border patrol.
Get the recoilless
rifle right now.
He thinks we're opium dealers.
They want our cargo.
Offer him a bribe.
Anything. Stall.
They want to inspect our packs.
This'll get terminal
in a hurry.
You ready, Johnson? Ready.
Now!
Scott, God damn it,
man your weapon!
Damn it!
Two of them got away!
Colonel.
Sir, we lost one rpg,
six grenades,
and a radio is damaged.
It'll receive,
but the transmitter's shot.
Mr. Jiang.
We...
Come.
We must continue on.
No further words are
necessary, colonel rhodes.
Since we don't have
night vision gear,
we'll change to 0600
instead of 0300.
We're able to receive
your verification...
About the p.O.W.S,
but you'll have to assume
we've gotten the choppers.
Wait till you hear us coming.
Ground team,
you're up that trail.
Air team,
follow me down this creek.
Well, that's it.
It's game time.
I've forgotten
the speech I prepared.
There are some lines
from Julius Caesar.
"If a man were to know...
"The end of this day's
business ere it come,
"but it suffices
that the day will end,
"and then the end be known.
"If we meet again,
"then we'll smile.
"And if not...
Well, then,
this parting was well made."
It should be
right over that hill.
Come on.
Quietly.
Down.
Drop your packs.
It looks deserted.
You think they moved them?
Quite possible.
Rice down there
has been harvested.
I'll take a look.
I'll look at that bridge.
Couldn't find a way in.
It's walled all around.
Look at this.
What?
O.K., wilkesy, I'll go.
No, no, no.
I'll be waiting for you...
When you come out.
O.K., wilkesy?
Take this. It'll
help protect you.
Help!
Wilkesy, you all right?
What's wrong, man?
It's o.K. It's not poisonous.
Yeah.
That charm took care of you.
I don't believe it!
The chopper compound
isn't here.
They must have moved
the goddamn thing.
Give me the map.
Cover!
All right, let's go.
Let's move.
Laotian regulars.
Prisoners.
They must've been working
across the river.
That's why we didn't see them.
Jesus, wilkes!
He spotted me.
You almost got me spotted.
I saw an American.
I saw three.
Alcatraz, this is sing sing.
Bmx.
We've struck oil.
I repeat, bmx.
Hold it! Hold it!
They're there!
The p.O.W.S. They're there!
Jesus Christ.
They're there!
Let's find those choppers.
It could've been Frank.
I just don't know.
We will know soon enough.
Well, I've got some
nocturnal planting to do.
Scott, good luck... Jiang.
Wilkesy, let's go.
Colonel, we've
got to move faster.
There's a lot of
jungle to cover...
Between that base and us.
Come on.
Where is it?
I know it came
down in this area.
Hurry. It's almost dawn.
All right. They're asleep.
Let's get them
before they wake up.
Charts and sailor,
take the barracks.
I'll take the
officers' quarters.
Mr. Charts must
fly the helicopter.
He cannot risk injury.
I will go in first
with Mr. Sailor.
Charts?
They should be on their way.
Get out of here! Let's go!
Hands up!
Charts... Charts!
Get the gunship!
Johnson, in the huey!
Hold them right here, sailor!
Lai fun, stay with sailor!
Battery!
Up on the Ridge!
I'll cover!
Johnson's chopper
took another hit!
Spot for me.
I got a guy.
200 meters, top of the Ridge,
left of the tree.
Right, two meters!
Got him!
All right!
Baby!
Let's go! Let's go!
Come on, sailor!
Charts! Lai fun!
O.K., fucker!
You're history, pal.
Charts, are you with me?
Right behind you.
Johnson, are you with me?
Right on you, colonel!
Shit. Where are they?
You cannot let them
cross the bridge!
What if they don't show?
They are coming.
Don't let them
reach the bridge!
Fire in front of them.
Fire!
You ain't crossing
that fucking bridge.
It's still there!
Goddamn caps!
Aah!
Hiyah!
Hah!
Come on, bastards!
Come and get it!
One!
Two!
Three! Four! Five!
Six! A new record!
Seven!
Yeah! Eight! Unbelievable!
We can get them out!
Oh, my God!
Yaah!
Whoo! Damn it!
Coming in on the tower.
Son of a bitch!
We've been hit!
Hold on!
Gun's jammed, colonel!
I'll take out the tower.
O.K., boss!
We're going to hit heavy!
Colonel!
Wilkes, give me a hand.
Jesus Christ!
Are you all right?
Yeah.
We saw four Americans,
one in your building!
Go! Go! Go!
Frank!
Come on, buddy.
We're going home.
I can't.
The garden.
We'll take it with us.
It's all right.
Come on. It's o.K.
Let's go. Hurry, boss.
Frank? Frank?
It's o.K., soldier.
It's all right.
It's o.K.
No!
Come on, let's go.
Home? Home for real?
Yeah! Come on!
Any more rounds
for the recoilless?
Jiang?
Holy shit!
Eeeyaahhh!
I'll kill you,
you motherfuckers!
Charts! This way!
Move it! Move it!
Come on, man!
Go, go, go!
There's no sign of number four.
Where's the other American?
What's he saying?
In the pit.
Where's the pit?
Give me a count of 60, then go.
We can't leave anybody
behind this time.
Leave, or everybody
will get left behind!
Frank!
Macgregor?
Wilkes, cover me.
Run, colonel, run!
Run.
Head for the chopper!
We'll be wiped out!
Come on!
God damn it!
Wilkes!
Leave it!
Come on! Come on!
Where's sailor?
He's bought it!
He's dead!
Sailor! Sailor!
Eeeyaaah!
Come on, man.
Come on.
Where's blaster?
God damn it!
Mr. Charts!
Mr. Scott! Come!
Come quickly!
This way!
Charts, come on!
We got to hustle!
Come on!
Mayday! Mayday!
American m.I.A.S on board!
Chartsy, give me
a hand up here.
I got a heavy stick.
Mayday! Mayday!
American m.I.A.S on board!
It's really good...
To see you.
Frank...
He got sick...
So sick.
I tried to help him.
He died.
He saved my life that day.
He saved my life.
¶ We're all startin' to feel ¶
¶ the pain we endure ¶
¶ makes us wonder
what in the hell ¶
¶ we're all fightin' for ¶
¶ a decade of nightmares ¶
¶ long years of tears ¶
¶ who can take the injustice? ¶
¶ who can get past the fears? ¶
¶ and true hearts of courage ¶
¶ even in a world
turned wrong ¶
¶ those precious hearts
are gone ¶
¶ but they're never forgotten ¶
¶ I believe that all good deeds
of men will never fall ¶
¶ they live on forever ¶
¶ forever standin' tall ¶
¶ I believe that all good deeds
of men will never fall ¶
¶ we're all brothers
in the night ¶
¶ reaching out
for something right ¶
¶ there are dark, evil forces ¶
¶ that hide behind masks ¶
¶ and to right all the wrongs ¶
¶ is an impossible task ¶
¶ yet at a certain time ¶
¶ and in a certain place ¶
¶ man can redeem ¶
¶ mankind's disgrace ¶
¶ the courage of our past ¶
¶ will lead to peace at last ¶
¶ even after war so rotten ¶
¶ so many hearts are gone
but not forgotten ¶
¶ I believe that all good deeds
of men will never fall ¶
¶ they live on forever ¶
¶ forever standin' tall ¶
¶ I believe that all good deeds
of men will never fall ¶
¶ we're all brothers
in the night ¶
¶ reaching out
for something right ¶
¶ we're all brothers
in the night ¶
¶ it's our time,
please let's unite ¶
¶ ooh ¶
¶ ah, I believe, I believe,
I believe ¶
¶ the courage of our past ¶
¶ will lead to peace at last ¶
¶ even after war so rotten ¶
¶ so many hearts are gone
but not forgotten ¶
¶ I believe that all good deeds
of men will never fall ¶
¶ they live on forever ¶
¶ forever standin' tall ¶
¶ I believe that all good deeds
of men will never fall ¶
¶ they live on forever ¶
¶ forever standin' tall ¶
¶ I believe that all good deeds
of men will never fall ¶
¶ we'll never forget ya ¶
¶ they live on forever ¶
¶ forever standin' tall ¶
¶ I believe that all good deeds
of men will never fall ¶
¶ they live on forever ¶
¶ forever standin' tall ¶
¶ we're all brothers
in the night ¶
¶ reaching out
for something right ¶
¶ we'll walk always
in the night ¶
¶ it's our time, let's unite ¶¶